<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: From The Jam to last ditch bid for shekels	</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 04:51:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: admin		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-992</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 04:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2008/01/22/from-the-jam-to-last-ditch-bid-for-shekels/#comment-992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This thread is closed.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This thread is closed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Eric Greenwood		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-991</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Greenwood]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 04:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2008/01/22/from-the-jam-to-last-ditch-bid-for-shekels/#comment-991</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[johnny bland,

the list in the top right is for &quot;recent reviews.&quot; below that list you will see &quot;recent blog posts&quot;, under which this jam piece was listed back when it was recent.

however, you do see the point slightly in your assessment of the smashing pumpkins. i agree that they are a sham as well. but this from the jam stuff is equally suspect. i think you&#039;re wrong in saying 2/3 is enough. it&#039;s not. andy summers sang a song for the police. so did stewart copeland. and both wrote several police songs. but if stewart and andy reformed without sting and called it kinda sorta maybe the police would you buy into it? of fucking course not. but they have every right to play the songs, right? give me a break.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>johnny bland,</p>
<p>the list in the top right is for &#8220;recent reviews.&#8221; below that list you will see &#8220;recent blog posts&#8221;, under which this jam piece was listed back when it was recent.</p>
<p>however, you do see the point slightly in your assessment of the smashing pumpkins. i agree that they are a sham as well. but this from the jam stuff is equally suspect. i think you&#8217;re wrong in saying 2/3 is enough. it&#8217;s not. andy summers sang a song for the police. so did stewart copeland. and both wrote several police songs. but if stewart and andy reformed without sting and called it kinda sorta maybe the police would you buy into it? of fucking course not. but they have every right to play the songs, right? give me a break.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: K		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-990</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 03:35:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2008/01/22/from-the-jam-to-last-ditch-bid-for-shekels/#comment-990</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I think this horse is dead, people.  Let&#039;s move along.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think this horse is dead, people.  Let&#8217;s move along.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Pleasantly Surprised		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-989</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pleasantly Surprised]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 03:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2008/01/22/from-the-jam-to-last-ditch-bid-for-shekels/#comment-989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So Foxton and Buckler should either sit home and have wistful memories, or bust out some &quot;updated&quot; new shit?  Is that it?  They have &quot;no right&#039; to play the songs that took them to the top of the charts, the songs which they toured the world with, the songs that basically changed their lives?

The Jam didn&#039;t break up for lack of record sales or fans.  On the contrary, they were at their absolute peak of popularity.  Weller REFUSED to play ANY Jam songs for YEARS.  These days he&#039;ll throw in 2 or 3 per gig if you&#039;re lucky.  (The rest of his solo gigs are completely unmemorable) The fans want to hear these Jam songs.  Foxton and Buckler want to play them.  Everybody is happy. 

Everyone except apparently some interweb pseudo-critic losers who are still in love with Paul Weller&#039;s rockstar soiled undies.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So Foxton and Buckler should either sit home and have wistful memories, or bust out some &#8220;updated&#8221; new shit?  Is that it?  They have &#8220;no right&#8217; to play the songs that took them to the top of the charts, the songs which they toured the world with, the songs that basically changed their lives?</p>
<p>The Jam didn&#8217;t break up for lack of record sales or fans.  On the contrary, they were at their absolute peak of popularity.  Weller REFUSED to play ANY Jam songs for YEARS.  These days he&#8217;ll throw in 2 or 3 per gig if you&#8217;re lucky.  (The rest of his solo gigs are completely unmemorable) The fans want to hear these Jam songs.  Foxton and Buckler want to play them.  Everybody is happy. </p>
<p>Everyone except apparently some interweb pseudo-critic losers who are still in love with Paul Weller&#8217;s rockstar soiled undies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Johnny Bland		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-988</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Johnny Bland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 02:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2008/01/22/from-the-jam-to-last-ditch-bid-for-shekels/#comment-988</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[p.s. weller and noel were recently seen making out in a copy of hello magazine!!!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>p.s. weller and noel were recently seen making out in a copy of hello magazine!!!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Johnny Bland		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-987</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Johnny Bland]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 02:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2008/01/22/from-the-jam-to-last-ditch-bid-for-shekels/#comment-987</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[well well well.. so much contraversy over a coupla guys getting their old band back together.. anyway if this isnt a review article why does the list at the top right come up as &quot;recently reviewed&quot;.  For those principled few out there who would never see a band just because it only has 2/3 of its members... FTJ is a great example of how in our mediacentric world, a great band was defined basically on the good looks and one ball of it&#039;s &quot;frontman&quot;... if you want to really get down to it. From the Jam is arguably better than they were as &quot;The Jam&quot; without the pouty weller who inspired so many pouty brit pop and rock acts to follow.. ANyway.. I digress... Foxton does have credit to the writing of many of the bands songs and sings lead vocals on the same. So the argument that you couldn&#039;t see this band because &quot;the lead singer&quot; isn&#039;t there is a bit of a wash. This perpetuated attitude that a band isn&#039;t a band without all its members is pure formalist bullshit. 2/3 of a band who were both involved in the writing of th music should be enough to cut the mustard. Now billy corgan going out and recruiting a whole band full of look alikes of his former band and calling the band by the same name --- thats another story.. thats some serious shamming in my opinion.. as far as Im concerned.. From the Jam should just do themselves a favour, drop the &quot;From&quot;  and keep kicking it old school. Weller can always fill in for Liam when Oasis gets back together and then that band will finally have a complete pair of balls.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>well well well.. so much contraversy over a coupla guys getting their old band back together.. anyway if this isnt a review article why does the list at the top right come up as &#8220;recently reviewed&#8221;.  For those principled few out there who would never see a band just because it only has 2/3 of its members&#8230; FTJ is a great example of how in our mediacentric world, a great band was defined basically on the good looks and one ball of it&#8217;s &#8220;frontman&#8221;&#8230; if you want to really get down to it. From the Jam is arguably better than they were as &#8220;The Jam&#8221; without the pouty weller who inspired so many pouty brit pop and rock acts to follow.. ANyway.. I digress&#8230; Foxton does have credit to the writing of many of the bands songs and sings lead vocals on the same. So the argument that you couldn&#8217;t see this band because &#8220;the lead singer&#8221; isn&#8217;t there is a bit of a wash. This perpetuated attitude that a band isn&#8217;t a band without all its members is pure formalist bullshit. 2/3 of a band who were both involved in the writing of th music should be enough to cut the mustard. Now billy corgan going out and recruiting a whole band full of look alikes of his former band and calling the band by the same name &#8212; thats another story.. thats some serious shamming in my opinion.. as far as Im concerned.. From the Jam should just do themselves a favour, drop the &#8220;From&#8221;  and keep kicking it old school. Weller can always fill in for Liam when Oasis gets back together and then that band will finally have a complete pair of balls.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Eric Beaumont		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-986</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Beaumont]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 00:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2008/01/22/from-the-jam-to-last-ditch-bid-for-shekels/#comment-986</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Eric,

From a man who loved Foxton and Buckler, and wanted them to do well on their own, you&#039;re right.   Get lives, gentlemen.  Write songs, stop living off your past, break up Spinal Jam.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eric,</p>
<p>From a man who loved Foxton and Buckler, and wanted them to do well on their own, you&#8217;re right.   Get lives, gentlemen.  Write songs, stop living off your past, break up Spinal Jam.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
