<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>link &#8211; Drawer B</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 15:02:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>link &#8211; Drawer B</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>De La Soul Offers Entire Catalog for Free for Valentine&#8217;s Day</title>
		<link>./../../../2014/02/14/de-la-soul-offers-entire-catalog-for-free-for-valentines-day/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pat]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 15:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[link]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[De La Soul&#8217;s seminal debut, the witty and weird and wonderful 3 Feet High and Rising, was released 25 years ago. In honor of that quarter-century mark, De La Soul&#8217;s offering a free download of its entire catalog for 25 hours on the group&#8217;s website. The download bonanza will begin on Friday, Feb. 14 at [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<a href="http://media.drawerb.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/media/2014/02/De-La-Soul.jpg"></a></p>
<p>De La Soul&#8217;s seminal debut, the witty and weird and wonderful <em>3 Feet High and Rising</em>, was released 25 years ago. In honor of that quarter-century mark, De La Soul&#8217;s offering a free download of its entire catalog for 25 hours on the <a href="http://www.wearedelasoul.com/">group&#8217;s website</a>. The download bonanza will begin on Friday, Feb. 14 at 11 a.m. EST, and it&#8217;ll run through until Saturday at noon. (But what if I&#8217;m only halfway through downloading <em>The Grind Date</em> at noon on Saturday? What then, De La Soul? WHAT THEN?!)</p>
<p>De La Soul&#8217;s music hasn&#8217;t been offered on many free streaming sites and services due to licensing issues. Prince Paul likes buddy &#8230; but he likes sampling, too, and many of De La&#8217;s early work is built on samples that weren&#8217;t fully licensed.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s about allowing our fans who have been looking and trying to get a hold of our music to have access to it,&#8221; Posdnuos <a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/music/news/de-la-soul-to-make-entire-catalog-available-for-free-20140213">tells <em>Rolling Stone </em></a>about releasing De La&#8217;s catalog. &#8220;It&#8217;s been too long where our fans haven&#8217;t had access to everything. This is our way of showing them how much we love them.&#8221;</p>
<p>That&#8217;s one hell of a V-Day gift, Plug One. Way better than a toaster. Way to make a girl feel special.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Owls Return After 13-Year Hiatus</title>
		<link>./../../../2014/02/04/owls-return-after-13-year-hiatus/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pat]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 20:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[link]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<a href="http://media.drawerb.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/media/2014/02/00622_OWLS_5782_b-40002.jpg"></a></p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/131006876&amp;color=ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG HOLY CRAP THERE&#8217;S A NEW OWLS SONG</p>
<p>Owls, of course, is a Kinsella brothers-led supergroup that released one record (a great one) 13 years ago. Its members have been busy with other projects — namely Owen, Joan of Arc, Make Believe, and Ghosts &amp; Vodka. Polyvinyl releases <em>Two </em><a href="http://www.polyvinylrecords.com/store/index.php?id=2553">next month<em></em></a>; it&#8217;s already leaked another song, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/polyvinyl-records/owls-im-surprised-1">&#8220;I&#8217;m Suprised,&#8221;</a> from the record.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Merge Reissues Richard Buckner&#8217;s Bloomed; Buckner Extends Living Room Tour</title>
		<link>./../../../2014/02/04/merge-reissues-richard-buckners-bloomed-buckner-extends-living-room-tour/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pat]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 17:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[link]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7458</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bloomed, released in 1994, was Richard Buckner&#8217;s first record, and his first great record. Unfortunately, it was released on an imprint of an unsympathetic major label that gave Buckner very little support in terms of promoting the record, leaving it to languish and die. Twenty years later, Buckner, since bounced from the major-label circuit after [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/8oBJMr_WrM0" height="315" width="420" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><em>Bloomed</em>, released in 1994, was Richard Buckner&#8217;s first record, and his first <em>great</em> record. Unfortunately, it was released on an imprint of an unsympathetic major label that gave Buckner very little support in terms of promoting the record, leaving it to languish and die.</p>
<p>Twenty years later, <em></em>Buckner, since bounced from the major-label circuit after a two-record stint with MCA, calls vaunted North Carolina indie label Merge home. In March, Merge reissues <em>Bloomed</em> as the third record of its Merge 25 series, which celebrates Merge&#8217;s 25th anniversary. (The first two: Lambchop&#8217;s <em>Nixon</em> and Superchunk&#8217;s <em>Indoor Living</em>, two of Merge&#8217;s finest releases.) The album will be remastered and released on CD and 180-gram vinyl. Both formats will include a bonus disc featuring radio sessions, live performances and original recordings of songs that appeared on future releases.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the second time <em>Bloomed </em>has been reissued; Rykodisc re-released it in 1999.</p>
<p>In other Buckner news, the songwriter is soliciting dates for his series of living room shows, which wraps up its first run in Arizona next week.</p>
<p>&#8220;Basically, I’ll pull up to your house with an acoustic guitar, find a spot inside where I won’t knock anything over and play all of the hits that made me the hundredaire that I am today,&#8221; Buckner writes on his website. &#8220;The location of the shows is only known to those who purchase tickets.&#8221;</p>
<p>If you have a living room large enough to house one of America&#8217;s greatest living songwriters, you can see if Buckner&#8217;s looking to play your town by checking <a href="undertowmusic.com.">undertowmusic.com</a>. (If he is, and you live in the Carolinas, and you book him, and you don&#8217;t tell me, I hate you.)</p>
<p>After the jump, some notes from Buckner, via Merge, on <em>Bloomed</em>.</p>
<p><span id="more-7458"></span></p>
<p><em>&#8220;Bloomed</em> was originally (erroneously?) released on an unnamable German label in 1994. I was living in San Francisco at the time, having just moved out of a residential hotel and into the 1906 hilltop prefab that adorns the cover. At the time, I was heading a band called The Doubters. We were playing high profile events such as The Covered Wagon Saloon’s Musical Barstools, but weren’t making much headway. We had been turned down consistently every year by SXSW, but I was somehow finagled in as an unannounced guest onto an already unofficial SXSW showcase created by Butch Hancock at his gallery in downtown Austin. There, I met up again with Lloyd Maines, who agreed to produce my first record.</p>
<p>Maines and I met in Lubbock, TX, a few months later, where we worked with Lubbock musicians in a small recording studio walled in wooden shingles Sharpied with bible passages from various church groups that also enjoyed working there. It was 112°F the morning I arrived under the suspicious (Californians are merely B-grade yankees) gaze of downtown’s Buddy Holly statue. That first night there, it hailed so hard that heaven’s angry pellets were storming in under my motel door. It only let up for a few moments that first night, allowing me to run across the street to get a butter burger and fries to go. We finished four days later and I flew back to San Francisco, dismembered the band, and embarked on a tour that would last about 20 years (or a few days, if you count what I actually remember).</p>
<p>Nothing’s changed. I’m still dodging the sky and busking to strangers.&#8221;		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Slint&#8217;s Spiderland to Be Reissued as Mega-Deluxe Box Set</title>
		<link>./../../../2014/01/30/slints-spiderland-to-be-reissued-as-mega-deluxe-box-set/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pat]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 19:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[link]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Slint&#8217;s landmark Spiderland, now 23 years old, will be reissued as a deluxe box set by Touch and Go in April. No other band was as largely overlooked during its relatively brief lifespan as Slint, which posthumously became one of the most influential and far-reaching bands to emerge from the American underground the 1980s. The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/hVdE469GOwg" height="360" width="480" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Slint&#8217;s landmark <em>Spiderland</em>, now 23 years old, will be reissued as a deluxe box set by Touch and Go in April.</p>
<p>No other band was as largely overlooked during its relatively brief lifespan as Slint, which posthumously became one of the most influential and far-reaching bands to emerge from the American underground the 1980s. The band broke up before the release of its magnum opus <em>Spiderland</em>, and couldn&#8217;t reap the rewards of its legacy: Innovative and iconoclastic, the group&#8217;s deft, extremist manipulations of volume, tempo and structure cast them as clear (though unwitting) progenitors of the post-rock movement that blossomed in the decades to come.</p>
<p>The box set includes the album, remastered from the original analog master tapes by Bob Weston and pressed on 180 gram vinyl, plus 14 previously unreleased demos, outtakes and live cuts. (The box set comes with a CD of all of the above, too.)</p>
<p>The box set also comes with a 104-page book replete with never-before-seen photos documenting Slint&#8217;s entire history, as well as lyrics to the songs on <em>Spiderland</em> and a forward by Will Oldham. (Most of Slint&#8217;s members spent at least a little time in Oldham&#8217;s Palace Music project, and Oldham took the album&#8217;s famous cover photo.) There’s also the brand-new, 90-minute documentary <em>Breadcrumb Trail </em>documentary about Slint and the making of Spiderland; it&#8217;s directed by Lance Bangs.</p>
<p>There are only 3,138 copies available, and a limited number of pre-ordered box sets will be signed by all four members of Slint. Pre-orders also include a T-shirt created from the re-discovered silk screen used to print Slint&#8217;s one and only tour shirt.</p>
<p>You can <a href="http://slintbox.touchandgorecords.com/">pre-order the box set here</a>, and the tracklisting is below.</p>
<p>SIDE A<br />
breadcrumb trail (remastered)<br />
nosferatu man (remastered)<br />
don, aman (remastered)</p>
<p>SIDE B<br />
washer (remastered)<br />
for dinner… (remastered)<br />
good morning, captain (remastered)</p>
<p>SIDE C<br />
Nosferatu Man (basement practice)<br />
Washer (basement practice)<br />
Good Morning, Captain (demo)</p>
<p>SIDE D<br />
Pam (rough mix, Spiderland outtake)<br />
Glenn (Spiderland outtake)<br />
Todd&#8217;s Song (post-Spiderland song in progress)</p>
<p>SIDE E<br />
Brian&#8217;s Song (post-Spiderland demo)<br />
Cortez The Killer (live Chicago 1989)</p>
<p>SIDE F<br />
Washer (4 track vocal demo)<br />
Nosferatu Man (4 track vocal demo)<br />
Pam (4 track vocal demo)<br />
Good Morning, Captain (Evanston riff tape)<br />
Nosferatu Man (Evanston riff tape)<br />
Pam (Evanston riff tape)		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Listen to Beck&#8217;s Beautifully Bummed-Out &#8220;Blue Moon&#8221;</title>
		<link>./../../../2014/01/20/listen-to-becks-beautifully-bummed-out-blue-moon/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pat]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 16:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[link]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7437</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I always thought Mutations was Beck&#8217;s most underappreciated record. My favorite of its many nifty tricks is how it sounds simple upon the first listen, then reveals more psychedelic layers upon each play. I&#8217;ve listened to &#8220;Blue Moon,&#8221; the first single from Beck&#8217;s upcoming Morning Phase, his first studio album since 2008&#8217;s Modern Guilt, probably [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<a href="http://media.drawerb.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/media/2014/01/Beck-Morning-Phase.jpg"></a></p>
<p><iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:album:5TafbNrL62AecbmD4lC1zc" height="95" width="350" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>I always thought <em>Mutations</em> was Beck&#8217;s most underappreciated record. My favorite of its many nifty tricks is how it sounds simple upon the first listen, then reveals more psychedelic layers upon each play.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve listened to &#8220;Blue Moon,&#8221; the first single from Beck&#8217;s upcoming <em>Morning Phase</em>, his first studio album since 2008&#8217;s <em>Modern Guilt</em>, probably six times straight now, and I&#8217;m similarly noticing new depths. The gentle flange of the pointillist electric guitar line in the bridge. The unhurried ease of the muted tom rolls. The cavernous reverb that extends Beck&#8217;s doleful vocal melody spaceward. The slight out-of-phase doubling of the acoustic guitars. The variegated acoustic backing instruments. The smear of the delayed signal on those first few electric guitar notes (which sounds like a <a href="http://www.strymon.net/timeline/">Strymon TimeLine</a> in action, to me).</p>
<p>All this is to say, &#8220;Blue Moon&#8221; is sad and beautiful and you should listen to it. I&#8217;m getting a strong <em>Mutations </em>vibe from &#8220;Blue Moon.&#8221; A <em>Sea Change</em> vibe, at least. Moreover, I&#8217;m actually kind of excited about a Beck record for the first time since, well, <em>Mutations</em>.</p>
<p><em>Morning Phase</em> is out on Capitol on Feb. 25.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Merge Plans Summer Festival Commemorating 25th Anniversary</title>
		<link>./../../../2014/01/15/merge-plans-summer-festival-commemorating-25th-anniversary/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pat]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 16:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[link]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Beloved and seminal North Carolina indie rock label Merge Records — home to such historically important indie rock bands as Archers of Loaf and Polvo and current chart-toppers Arcade Fire — celebrates its 25th anniversary this year, and Merge is throwing one hell of a yearlong party. There&#8217;s the Or Thousands of Prizes subscription series, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/1jWcUshLgB0" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Beloved and seminal North Carolina indie rock label <a href="http://www.mergerecords.com/merge-25"><strong>Merge</strong> <strong>Records</strong></a> — home to such historically important indie rock bands as Archers of Loaf and Polvo and current chart-toppers Arcade Fire — celebrates its 25th anniversary this year, and Merge is throwing one hell of a yearlong party.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s the <a href="http://www.mergerecords.com/or-thousands-of-prizes">Or Thousands of Prizes </a>subscription series, which will include 12 seven-inches (split singles, mostly) on colored vinyl featuring exclusive, newly recorded tracks from 25 Merge artists including Superchunk, Mikal Cronin, Mount Moriah and The Mountain Goats. Then there&#8217;s the <a href="http://www.mergerecords.com/25k">Merge 25k Road Race</a>, a 15.5-mile run from Merge&#8217;s old home in Chapel Hill to its new home in beautiful downtown Durham. Along the way, Merge will release re-packaged back catalog favorites each month — Lambchop&#8217;s <em>Nixon</em> and Superchunk&#8217;s <em>Indoor Living</em> are the first two to have been announced.</p>
<p>But the jewel in Merge&#8217;s birthday crown is the midsummer festival Merge is throwing in Carrboro. (Spin broke the news yesterday.) No details on the festival are available yet, save for July 23-26 dates, but it&#8217;d be a fair wager to bet that the lineup will be packed with bands from Merge&#8217;s exemplary stable. Plus, label co-head Mac McCaughan teases the festival will have a &#8220;Mountain Goats-Mount Moriah Misty Mountain Magic Misting Tent&#8221; and a &#8220;Lambchop Petting Zoo.&#8221;</p>
<p>Man, I&#8217;d pay good money to see a Mountain Goats-Mount Moriah split set. And a Bob Mould-Richard Buckner back-to-back would kill. Or maybe an Arcade Fire-Superchunk double headliner. Maybe I can finally see Archers of Loaf. OK, I&#8217;m salivating now.</p>
<p>Speaking of: Man, Laura Ballance can spit really far.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Patrick Wall&#8217;s Top Albums of 2013</title>
		<link>./../../../2013/12/31/patrick-walls-top-albums-of-2013/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pat]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 23:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contentious list-making]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[link]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yearend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7378</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ABOUT THE AUTHOR: Patrick Wall is the man whose name you’d love to touch. But you mustn’t touch. People pay him to write things. KNEE MEETS JERK In Which a Beleaguered Music Journalist Attempts — and Fails — to Identify Ten Records Released Between December 2012 and December 2013 That Were Better Than All Other [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				ABOUT THE AUTHOR: Patrick Wall is the man whose name you’d love to touch. But you mustn’t touch. People pay him to write things.</p>
<p><strong>KNEE MEETS JERK</strong><br />
<em>In Which a Beleaguered Music Journalist Attempts — and Fails — to Identify Ten Records Released Between December 2012 and December 2013 That Were Better Than All Other Releases in the Same Time Period. Listed in alphabetical order. Results subject to change. In seven acts.<br />
</em></p>
<p><span id="more-7378"></span></p>
<p><strong>I. Perspicacity</strong><br />
<em>Or, Twenty-Three Records for Twelve Months<br />
</em><br />
<iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/119200180&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Action Bronson, <em>Blue Chips 2</em> (Atlantic/Vice)</strong><br />
The knock on Action Bronson is that he’s almost a Kenny Powers-ish caricature of Ghostface Killah, that he amplifies Tony Starks’ swagger, flow and gift for storytelling to cartoonish levels. I fail to see the problem with that: <em>Blue Chips 2</em> is freewheeling and fun, and over the 19 sprawling tracks, Bronsoliño’s got the mind of a fucking scientist.</p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2951209986/size=medium/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/t=5/transparent=true/" height="240" width="320" seamless=""></iframe><br />
<strong>Alpoko Don, <em>The Ol Soul</em> EP (Kidfire)</strong><br />
Randrickas Young is from Greenville, S.C. He started posting YouTube videos under the name Alpoko Don sometime last year, his fluid lyrical facility — buoyed by stories and jokes about the coke trade and paeans to the Almighty and Technicolor metaphors — laid naked with just his gruff voice over barely-there beats he makes by pounding his fists on tables and front-porch railings. It’s equal parts trap rap and field hollers. It’s amazing, and proves rap music’s inherent but oft-doubted musicality.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/110753864&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Daniel Bachman, <em>Jesus I’m a Sinner</em> (Tompkins Square)</strong><br />
What Colin Stetson is to the saxophone, Daniel Bachman is to the guitar. That is to say: He is of his tradition — in Bachman’s case, post-Takoma school American primitive guitar — but supersedes it, recalling Basho’s spiritual heft and Rose’s whirling-dervish dexterity while suprassing them. Bachman encompasses, and he eclipses.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/93549370&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Boards of Canada, <em>Tomorrow’s Harvest</em> (Warp)</strong><br />
The Earth is not a cold, dead place, but Boards of Canada makes it seem like one. <em>Tomorrow’s Harvest</em> implies in its title reap-what-we’ve-sown mortality; its disintegrating loops invoking dust storms and abandoned freeway gas stations and scorched landscapes and the Earth reclaiming itself anew. It is music for Thunderdone.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/59082643&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Brokeback, <em>Brokeback and the Black Rock</em> (Thrill Jockey)</strong><br />
Brokeback’s from Chicago — Tortoise’s Douglas McCombs leads the group, and his band features members of Windy City faves Pinebender and The Zincs — but its growling instrumental rock evokes the lonesome, crowded west. Drums roll like tumbleweeds. Guitars whip like desert winds. The reverb — oh, how there’s reverb! — sounds like echoes bouncing off canyon walls.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/97876126&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Richard Buckner, <em>Surrounded</em> (Merge)</strong><br />
I used to go to church once a year. Then, I started seeing Richard Buckner in concert about once a year. I’m happier now.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/90243751&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Chance the Rapper, <em>Acid Rap</em> (self-released)</strong><br />
Great rap is evocative of time and place: New York City in the early ’80s. Los Angeles in the early ’90s. Atlanta in the mid ’90s. New Orleans in the late ’90s. Memphis in 2003. Like Kendrick Lamar’s sprawling <em>good kid, M.A.A.D. City</em> (Compton, mid-late ’00s), Chance the Rapper’s <em>Acid Rap</em> (Chicago, 2013) stamps the emcee as one of the most astounding street-poet storytellers of this generation.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/93221623&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Deafheaven, <em>Sunbather</em> (Deathwish)</strong><br />
The album My Bloody Valentine should’ve made.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/117790792&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Chris Forsyth, <em>Solar Motel</em> (Paradise of Bachelors)</strong><br />
This is probably what the first few Television jam sessions were like, I’d imagine.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/playlists/5242117&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="450" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Steve Gunn, <em>Time Off</em> (Paradise of Bachelors)</strong><br />
Music for quittin’ time, for gettin’ outdoors and sittin’ on the porch and kickin’ off the shoes and crackin’ open a beer and watchin’ the sunset and shootin’ the shit and droppin’ the velar nasal and lettin’ time just kinda go by. (Side note: Between Gunn’s <em>Time Off</em>, Forsyth’s <em>Solar Motel</em> and Hiss Golden Messenger’s <em>Haw</em>, Paradise of Bachelors kind of killed it this year.)</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/107489426&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Tim Hecker, <em>Virgins</em> (Kranky)</strong><br />
Dark. Spectral. Haunting. Austere. Tense. Primal. Eerie. Forcefully so, like the sounds are alive, and trying to claw out of the speakers. You might be able to listen to this one with the lights off. I won’t.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/84281005&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Glenn Jones, <em>My Garden State</em> (Thrill Jockey)</strong><br />
My dad loves Harry Chapin. My dad loves Harry Chapin, he says, because his songs are stories, rich and vibrant and infinitesimally detailed. I love Glenn Jones for the same reason. Thing is, Jones’ songs tell stories without any words.</p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2549328916/size=medium/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/t=8/transparent=true/" height="240" width="320" seamless=""></iframe><br />
<strong>KEN Mode, <em>Entrench</em> (Season of Mist)</strong><br />
The best songs hit you the hardest.<br />
“Figure your life out,” KEN Mode’s Jesse Matthewson sneers on the song of the same name, from the Winnipeg noise-rock trio’s awesome, impassioned <em>Entrench</em>.<br />
I turned 31 this year. I sold my house. I quit my job. I passed up an opportunity to move to the West Coast. I moved, but stayed in the South — from a city in which I was eminently comfortable to one where I live but, as Travis Morrison once quipped, have never felt less at home.<br />
I watched my friends have more successful, more fulfilling years than I did. Some of my friends got married. Some of my friends had children. I put off learning to play the pedal steel guitar another year. I felt undeniable pangs of jealousy as I watched longtime friends in successful bands play on late-night television shows while I slummed and struggled in dive bars. I drank with friends on last nights in town, before they moved to find fulfillment in their work as I slowly lost gratification in mine. As friends and one-time objects of affection reinvented themselves in mind or body or spirit, I just got older, just felt sorry for myself.<br />
So, yeah, I got depressed in 2013. I stopped drinking, then started again. I stopped exercising. For five days a week for nearly six months, I drove 100 miles to work, then another 100 back. I gained 20 pounds.<br />
So, now, on the cusp of a new year, I’m about to be jobless, perhaps careerless, and without health insurance. And all I have to fall back on is a lousy liberal arts diploma, a few guitars, a couple amplifiers and nagging, gnawing, crippling doubt that maybe it’s too late, maybe I&#8217;m too old to start fresh.<br />
“Figure your life out,” Jesse Matthewson sneers. I’m trying, dude. I’m trying.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/125238333&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>The Necks, <em>Open</em> (Northern Spy)</strong><br />
Without fail, I always miscalculate the denouement of The Neck’s graceful, meditative Open. I always think it’s wrapping up, finally winding down its blissful, captivating calm. I always look at the time remaining, and I always see that there are at least 20 minutes remaining in the most subtle and musically sensitive 68 minutes of music released in 2013. I’m never so happy to make a mistake.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/102749319&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Oneohtrix Point Never, <em>R Plus Seven</em> (Warp)</strong><br />
When I was just out of college, before I started working in earnest, I house-sat for some friends of mine. They had a pool, and their stereo system ran cables to speakers on their back porch, meaning I could, ostensibly, listen to music in the pool. One night, I got really high, put on Nobukazu Takemura’s “Icefall” and floated for ten minutes. I want to do something similar with Oneohtrix Point Never’s R Plus Seven, particularly “Problem Areas,” except with DMT and a top-down shooter. (Aside: I’m pretty sure a lot of the instrument samples come from Mario Paint.)</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/102734786&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>William Onyeabor, <em>Who Is William Onyeabor?</em> (Luaka Bop)</strong><br />
Who is William Onyeabor? An elusive and obscure Nigerian funk musician who made a few records in the 1970s and 1980s. Who is William Onyeabor? A musician rediscovered by Luaka Bop, who reissued his impossible-to-find futuristic synth funk on its exemplary World Psychedelic Classics series. Who is William Onyeabor? A mysterious musician on par with Fela Kuti in terms of how and where they pushed funk and electro music. Who is William Onyeabor? A man finally getting his due.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/104273830&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Polvo, <em>Siberia</em> (Merge)</strong><br />
My favorite Polvo album, 1996’s <em>Exploded Drawing</em>, takes a long time to get started. “Fast Canoe” sputters at its outset, like an old lawnmower that needs a few good tugs to really get going — guitar lines stab and dart tentatively, drums tiptoe but don’t tighten. When it finally roars at about the minute-forty-five mark, its locks into a skull-crushing groove. My second-favorite Polvo record, this year’s <em>Siberia</em>, doesn’t wait — it throttles from the get-go, “Total Immersion” beginning seemingly in the throes of an epic jam session that finally got going. And it doesn’t let up.</p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3226130328/size=medium/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/t=1/transparent=true/" height="240" width="320" seamless=""></iframe><br />
<strong>Puig Destroyer, <em>Puig Destroyer</em> / <em>Wait for Spring</em> EPs (The Ghost is Clear)</strong><br />
Why do I like Puig Destroyer, which writes grindcore songs about baseball, so much? Because I like grindcore and baseball. Because fuck you, that’s why. #STOPFUCKINGBUNTING #ONEMANFIVETOOLS</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/98706380&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Run the Jewels, <em>Run the Jewels</em> (Fool&#8217;s Gold)</strong><br />
El Producto sets the tone right off the bat: “Oh dear, what the fuck have we here? / These motherfuckers all thorn, no rose.” Run the Jewels, ten tracks of speaker-obliterating beats and razor sharp verses laced with searingly honest emotion and pitch-black humor, was supposed to be a one-off fuckaround for El-P and Killer Mike following a banner 2012 for both. But when everyone was sweating Kanye’s blown-out <em>Yeezus</em> and Drake’s tepid <em>Nothing Was the Same</em> this summer, Run the Jewels burst through brick walls like the Kool-Aid Man. While Ye and Drizzy were just unlikeable, Mike and El were downright villainous, downright merciless, went Darth Vader on the rap game, force-choking the shit out of sucker emcees. I find everyone else’s lack of faith disturbing.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/112635701&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Savages, <em>Silence Yourself</em> (Matador/Pop Noire)</strong><br />
Maybe this year really was a banner year for women in rock and rock-derived and rock-esque musics. Maybe it was just a banner year for thinkpieces about women in rock and rock-derived and rock-esque musics this year. Either way, women helmed some really great records (Torres’ <em>Torres</em>; Neko Case’s <em>The Worse Things Get…</em>; Beyonce’s <em>Beyonce</em>) and wrote some really great songs (Case’s “Man”; Janelle Monae’s “Q.U.E.E.N.”; Tegan and Sara’s “I Was a Fool) in 2013. But it all starts and ends with Savages, four nails-tough British women playing the best and darkest post-punk since Joy Division.</p>
<p><strong>Wayne Shorter, <em>Without a Net</em> (Blue Note)</strong><br />
Wayne Shorter is jazz’s greatest living saxophonist and improviser and, at 80 years old plays circles around the rest of the blue-chip crew assembled on the fertile <em>Without a Net</em>. Blue Note, nearly 30 years after its relaunch following a lengthy hiatus, remains one of the most essential jazz labels. You do the math.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/90031039&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Speedy Ortiz, <em>Major Arcana</em> (Carpark)</strong><br />
RIYL: Stephen Malkmus, if he were a woman with an MFA in poetry, and she fronted Nirvana instead of Pavement.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/70385017&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>William Tyler, <em>Impossible Truth</em> (Merge)</strong><br />
It was a great and fashionable year for instrumental guitar music. Hell, I put three other instrumental guitar records on this list. But William Tyler’s <em>Impossible Truth</em> is the best because it’s the most nuanced. It’s a rangy record obsessed with open highways and desert heat, a nimble record that heaves big open sighs of drone and purring fingerpicking patterns, a spacious record that calls to mind Ennio Morricone and Daniel Lanois and Willie Nelson in equal measure. I’ve never seen the Grand Canyon, but I’ve seen William Tyler perform <em>Invisible Truth</em>. That’s good enough for me.</p>
<p><strong>II. Whimsy</strong><br />
<em>Or, Bonus Tracks!: 25 Great Songs From Albums Not on the Above List</em><br />
A$AP Rocky, “1 Train” feat. Kendrick Lamar, Joey Badass, Yelawolf, Danny Brown, Action Bronson and Big K.R.I.T.<br />
Big Sean, “Control” feat. Kendrick Lamar &amp; Jay Electronica<br />
Captain Murphy, “Between Villains” feat. Viktor Vaughn, Earl Sweatshirt, Thundercat<br />
Charles Bradley, “Changes”<br />
CFCF, “Forest at Night”<br />
Dads, “My Crass Patch”<br />
Haim, “The Wire”<br />
Earl Sweatshirt, “Chum”<br />
The Front Bottoms, “Twin Sized Mattress”<br />
Ghostface Killah, “Blood on the Cobblestone”<br />
Jason Isbell, “Live Oak”<br />
Juicy J, “One of Those Nights”<br />
Mystikal, “Hit Me”<br />
Pelican, “Immutable Dusk”<br />
Prince, “Breakfast Can Wait”<br />
Pusha T, “40 Acres”<br />
Robin Thicke, “Blurred Lines”<br />
Rich Homie Quan, “Type of Way”<br />
Schoolboy Q, “Collard Greens”<br />
Superchunk, “Me and You and Jackie Mittoo”<br />
Toro Y Moi, “Campo”<br />
Whores., “Cougars, Not Kittens”<br />
Bo White, “National Love and Other Tyrants”<br />
Yo La Tengo, “Ohm”</p>
<p><strong>III. Lamentation</strong><br />
<em>Or, Honorable Mentions and/or Apologies To</em><br />
A$AP Rocky, <em>LONG.LIVE.A$AP</em>; Califone, <em>Stitches</em>; Bill Callahan, <em>Dream River</em>; The Body, <em>Christs, Redeemers</em>; Charles Bradley, <em>Victim of Love</em>; CFCF, <em>Music for Objects</em> EP; Dads, <em>Pretty Good</em> EP; Earl Sweatshirt, <em>Doris</em>; Four Tet, <em>Beautiful Rewind</em>; Helado Negro, <em>Invisible Life</em>; Lonnie Holley, <em>Keeping a Record of It</em>; Hiss Golden Messenger, <em>Haw</em>; Jason Isbell, <em>Southeastern</em>; Keefe Jackson’s Likely So, <em>A Round Goal</em>; Kylesa, <em>Ultraviolet</em>; The Littlest Viking, <em>The Littlest Viking</em>; Low, <em>The Invisible Way</em>; Magnetic Flowers, <em>Old, Cold. Losing It.</em>; Mount Moriah, <em>Miracle Temple</em>; Mountains, <em>Centralia</em>; The National, <em>Trouble Will Find Me</em>; Owen, <em>L’Ami du Peuple</em>; Pelican, <em>Forever Becoming</em>; Phosphorescent, <em>Muchacho</em>; Pusha T, <em>My Name Is My Name</em>; Russian Circles, <em>Memorial</em>; Sigur Ros, <em>Kveikur</em>; Southern Femisphere, <em>Houses</em>; Colin Stetson, <em>New History Warfare Vol 3</em>; Superchunk, <em>I Hate Music</em>; Torres, <em>Torres</em>; Toro Y Moi, <em>Anything in Return</em>; Touche Amore, <em>Is Survived By</em>; Vattnet Viskar, <em>Sky Swallower</em>; Washed Out, <em>Paracosm</em>; Bo White, <em>Adornment</em>; Whores., <em>Clean</em>; Dustin Wong, <em>Mediation of Ecstatic Energy</em>; The World is a Beautiful Place and I Am No Longer Afraid to Die, <em>Whenever If Ever</em>; Yo La Tengo, <em>Fade</em></p>
<p><strong>IV. Purgation</strong><br />
<em>Or, Critically Acclaimed Records I Did Not Care For But Expected I Would or Thought I Might</em><br />
Action Bronson, <em>Saaab Stories</em>; Arcade Fire, <em>Reflektor</em>; Big Boi, <em>Vicious Lies and Dangerous Rumors</em>; David Bowie, <em>The Next Day</em>; CFCF, <em>Outside</em>; Lorde, <em>Pure Heroine</em>; The Men, <em>New Moon</em>; My Bloody Valentine, <em>mbv</em>; Rhye, <em>Woman</em>; Vampire Weekend, <em>Modern Vampires of the City</em>; Kurt Vile, <em>Walkin’ On a Pretty Daze</em>; Waxahatchee, <em>Cerulean Salt</em>; Kanye West, <em>Yeezus</em></p>
<p><strong>V. Quandary</strong><br />
<em> Or, Critically Acclaimed Records I Did Not Listen To Enough (Or, In Some Cases, At All) And I&#8217;m Still Unsure How Much I Like</em><br />
Burial, <em>Rival Dealer</em>; Chvrches, <em>The Bones of What You Believe</em>; Daft Punk, <em>Random Access Memories</em>; Death Grips, <em>Government Plates</em>; Disclosure, <em>Settle</em>; Arnold Dreyblatt &amp; Megafaun, <em>Appalachian Extinction</em>; Forest Swords, <em>Engravings</em>; Ben Goldberg, <em>Unfold Ordinary Mind</em>; John Grant, <em>Pale Green Ghosts</em>; Haim, <em>Days Are Gone</em>; Ka, <em>The Night’s Gambit</em>; The Knife, <em>Shaking the Habitual</em>; Laura Marling, <em>Once I Was an Eagle</em>; Matmos, <em>The Marriage of Two Minds</em>; Migos, <em>YRN</em>; Kacey Musgraves, <em>Same Trailer Different Park</em>; Pharmakon, <em>Abandon</em>; DJ Rashad, <em>I Don’t Give a Fuck</em></p>
<p><strong>VI. Catharsis</strong><br />
<em>Or, The Thirteen Best Live Sets I Saw in 2013</em><br />
Alpoko Don @ Lincoln Theatre, Raleigh, N.C. (Sept. 6)<br />
Richard Buckner @ The Pinhook, Durham, N.C. (Oct. 10)<br />
Code Orange Kids @ Foxfield Bar &amp; Grille, Columbia, S.C. (July 15)<br />
Steve Gunn @ Raleigh Little Theatre, Raleigh, N.C. (Sept. 7)<br />
Keefe Jackson Trio @ Dialect Design, Charlotte, N.C. (Oct. 29)<br />
<a title="Do You Know How to Waltz?" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zI5-MuV5NSo">Low @ Rock the Garden, Minneapolis, Minn. (June 17)</a><br />
The Littlest Viking @ Headhunters, Austin, Tex. (March 16)<br />
Sigur Rós @ Asheville Civic Center, Asheville, N.C. (Sept. 28)<br />
Taylor Swift @ Colonial Life Arena, Columbia, S.C. (March 20)<br />
William Tyler @ The Parish, Austin, Tex. (March 14)<br />
Ken Vandermark &amp; Tim Daisy @ The Hive at Busy Bee Café, Raleigh, N.C. (Sept. 5)<br />
Whores. @ New Brookland Tavern, Columbia, S.C. (Jan. 27)<br />
Dustin Wong @ Central Presbyterian Church, Austin, Tex. (March 16)</p>
<p><strong>VII. Vilification</strong><br />
<em>Or, The Year’s Biggest Disappointment</em><br />
<strong>Dismemberment Plan, <em>The Uncanney Valley</em></strong> <strong>(Partisan)</strong><br />
The Dismemberment Plan is my favorite band. The Dismemberment Plan that made <em>Uncanney Valley</em> is not The Dismemberment Plan.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
