<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Polvo re-signs to Merge, plans new record	</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2009 22:20:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Jeff Stern		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-1689</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Stern]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2009 22:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=5046#comment-1689</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Having seen them three times since they 
&quot;re-formed&quot; (they apparently prefer this term to reunion, since they have a different drummer and think of this version as slightly different), I have to say that this is one of the good reunions.  Their Chapel Hill show in advance of their ATP performance was remarkably tight, and I was really amazed at how they made all the stops, starts and time changes after all these years (similar to my reaction to the previous Slint reunion - it was incredibly faithful).  The next show I saw was a benefit show, and it was even better because they retained the precision but seemed much looser - personally and musically.  It seemed like math and jam in equal doses.  The third time, at a benefit for NCSU radio station WKNC, they seemed even more comfortable and loose, and the show was very much a rock show.  

If you&#039;re interested, a good portion of the 2nd show I described above is avaialable at http://www.cytunes.org/album/26/, an all-volunteer effort at raising money to fight brain cancer in memory of Cy Rawls (the beneficiary of the original benefit show).  I&#039;m also a volunteer at CyTunes and if you&#039;d like to gain review access to the site, just shoot me an email.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Having seen them three times since they<br />
&#8220;re-formed&#8221; (they apparently prefer this term to reunion, since they have a different drummer and think of this version as slightly different), I have to say that this is one of the good reunions.  Their Chapel Hill show in advance of their ATP performance was remarkably tight, and I was really amazed at how they made all the stops, starts and time changes after all these years (similar to my reaction to the previous Slint reunion &#8211; it was incredibly faithful).  The next show I saw was a benefit show, and it was even better because they retained the precision but seemed much looser &#8211; personally and musically.  It seemed like math and jam in equal doses.  The third time, at a benefit for NCSU radio station WKNC, they seemed even more comfortable and loose, and the show was very much a rock show.  </p>
<p>If you&#8217;re interested, a good portion of the 2nd show I described above is avaialable at <a href="http://www.cytunes.org/album/26/" rel="nofollow ugc">http://www.cytunes.org/album/26/</a>, an all-volunteer effort at raising money to fight brain cancer in memory of Cy Rawls (the beneficiary of the original benefit show).  I&#8217;m also a volunteer at CyTunes and if you&#8217;d like to gain review access to the site, just shoot me an email.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: AJW		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-1688</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AJW]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2009 20:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=5046#comment-1688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yep, memories of them being in heavy rotation at WUSC...]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yep, memories of them being in heavy rotation at WUSC&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Erin Reed		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-1687</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Erin Reed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2009 18:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=5046#comment-1687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Polvo! I am immediately transported back to my freshman year at USC. Thanks for this post Eric.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Polvo! I am immediately transported back to my freshman year at USC. Thanks for this post Eric.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
