<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: FTC investigates Burn Lounge as a Pyramid scheme	</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 14:57:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Floyd Fisher		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-160</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Floyd Fisher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 14:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2007/06/12/ftc-investigates-burn-lounge-as-a-pyramid-scheme/#comment-160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, it&#039;s gone.  Along with a lot of people&#039;s dreams.

What do you have to say now?  Are you sorry you even tried to con people into sinkimg money into a business model that was not viable?]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well, it&#8217;s gone.  Along with a lot of people&#8217;s dreams.</p>
<p>What do you have to say now?  Are you sorry you even tried to con people into sinkimg money into a business model that was not viable?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Trae		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-159</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Trae]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2007 03:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2007/06/12/ftc-investigates-burn-lounge-as-a-pyramid-scheme/#comment-159</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This &quot;business opportunity was prosented to me by a dear friend in late 2006.   I did alot of research and found that this may accually work.

Well,  besides putting countless time and money into advertising my store it still couldn&#039;t touch the free sites out there.   I have been pushing my store and placing ads and promoting it for a yr now.  Ask how many sales I&#039;ve had in that year?  ZERO!   You see, I can&#039;t fathum buying the store, paying the monthly fees, and ontop of that, purchase my own music from it just to stay qualified for the next month.  By the way, if you don&#039;t make your quota your sales and all will be flushed away and you have to start all over again.   Needless to say i&#039;m discontinuing my store and not renewing it for another yr.   I have found an amazing system that does hold up to its word and is a part of the Better Business Bureau and a member of their local chamber of comerce.  I have had much success with that...  So, my advice to you is to let the burnlounge go.  Just to much money is being put out with NO return.....   But,  If you feel as if you need to give it a shot,  do it.  Do live with &quot;what ifs&quot; or &quot;I could have&quot;.  Go for it.    Knowledge without experience is incomplete.

my best,
Tracy]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This &#8220;business opportunity was prosented to me by a dear friend in late 2006.   I did alot of research and found that this may accually work.</p>
<p>Well,  besides putting countless time and money into advertising my store it still couldn&#8217;t touch the free sites out there.   I have been pushing my store and placing ads and promoting it for a yr now.  Ask how many sales I&#8217;ve had in that year?  ZERO!   You see, I can&#8217;t fathum buying the store, paying the monthly fees, and ontop of that, purchase my own music from it just to stay qualified for the next month.  By the way, if you don&#8217;t make your quota your sales and all will be flushed away and you have to start all over again.   Needless to say i&#8217;m discontinuing my store and not renewing it for another yr.   I have found an amazing system that does hold up to its word and is a part of the Better Business Bureau and a member of their local chamber of comerce.  I have had much success with that&#8230;  So, my advice to you is to let the burnlounge go.  Just to much money is being put out with NO return&#8230;..   But,  If you feel as if you need to give it a shot,  do it.  Do live with &#8220;what ifs&#8221; or &#8220;I could have&#8221;.  Go for it.    Knowledge without experience is incomplete.</p>
<p>my best,<br />
Tracy</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
