<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>yearend &#8211; Drawer B</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 18:57:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>yearend &#8211; Drawer B</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Eric Greenwood&#8217;s Top Albums of 2019</title>
		<link>./../../../2020/01/05/eric-greenwoods-top-albums-of-2019/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 18:57:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yearend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brittany Howard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chromatics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deerhunter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DIIV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FKA Twigs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Gordon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lana Del Rey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nick Cave and the Bad Seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Purple Mountains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thom Yorke]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../wp/index.html?p=7857</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1. Purple Mountains, Purple Mountains (Drag City) When David Berman returned suddenly after a self-imposed, decade-long exile, it was cause for celebration. Seeing the world through Berman’s &#8211; by turns &#8211; caustic, witty, scholarly, devastating, absurd, and wry lens was sorely missed and missing from independent music at large. His suicide merely weeks after his [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>1. Purple Mountains, <em>Purple Mountains</em> (Drag City)</p>



<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XvUBbROsXBw" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>When David Berman returned suddenly after a self-imposed, decade-long exile, it was cause for celebration. Seeing the world through Berman’s &#8211; by turns &#8211; caustic, witty, scholarly, devastating, absurd, and wry lens was sorely missed and missing from independent music at large. His suicide merely weeks after his re-emergence only exacerbated the bleakness of the stark poetry in Purple Mountains’ astonishing debut. His songwriting had reached a new level of hook-laden laconicism and resignation, but the heartache and hopelessness that bubbled at the surface turned out to be far too real. Berman tosses off references that may send you to the research room one moment while uncovering a previously unnoticed universal truth the next. He was the poet of a generation of over-educated misanthropes, and he will be missed. This final album will long stand the test of time and fits alongside the best of his Silver Jews canon.</p>


<span id="more-7857"></span>



<p>2. Deerhunter, <em>Why Hasn’t Everything Already Disappeared?</em> (4AD)</p>



<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zG2TgCuMcjM" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Deerhunter’s last two records have eschewed some of the band’s noisier and experimental tangents in favor of more streamlined and cohesive statements that showcase Bradford Cox’s compositional skills. There’s still a healthy dose of weirdness; however, it’s just sheathed in a more digestible coating. In a sense it’s a form of trickery: Cox’s idiosyncratic obsessiveness can morph into a pop format, but, while the darkness that lurks underneath may not be obvious to the casual listener, it certainly haunts subversively. Watching Deerhunter conform to pop conventions has angered some of the band’s core audience, but Cox is willfully nonchalant about fan expectations. He has a vision for his band, and he explores the lure of his muse with an unrivaled intensity, and it’s fascinating to watch. Deerhunter is still one of the most exciting bands making music.    </p>


<p>3. DIIV, <em>Deceiver</em> (Captured Tracks)</p>



<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YWk1v5YSGUY" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>



<p>After two albums of sprawling anachronistic lo-fi dream-pop, DIIV has focused its sites on a more taut and muscular approach. Zachary Cole Smith’s statement of sobriety pulls no punches as it exposes his dark past through mammoth, crunching guitars and ghostly, melodic vocals. There are obvious nods to My Bloody Valentine’s layered dynamics, but they never come across in a gratuitous way. DIIV trades the navel-gazing reverb for a more urgent and aggressive sonic palate. The songs are more complex musically and thus take more time to build and ingest, but the reward is breathtaking and fulfilling. </p>



<p>4. Kim Gordon, <em>No Home Record</em> (Matador)</p>



<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TJl_9a6dp4g" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>



<p>Prior to this debut solo full-length, Kim Gordon’s post-Sonic Youth output has been mired in deliberately unlistenable drone. Her collaborations with guitarist Bill Nace in Body/Head explored the tangential aspects of the feedback-drenched, guitar-drone scene. On No Home Record, Gordon packages her experimental tendencies in a far more palatable format that almost embraces pop convention. In lieu of the multi-guitar attack of Sonic Youth, Gordon uses electronics as the vehicle for her urgent and uncompromising audio assaults. Gordon has never possessed a true singing voice, but she uses her voice in fascinating and affecting ways, grunting and howling her way through a morass of quirky hooks. </p>



<p>5. Nick Cave &amp; the Bad Seeds, <em>Ghosteen</em> (Ghosteen LTD)</p>



<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cfKYImFP_Pw" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>



<p><em>Ghosteen </em>is not a fun record to listen to at first. It takes a bit of effort and commitment to experience properly. Nick Cave has turned the tragedy of losing a child into music that exorcizes those demons through a breadth of emotions. Some of those emotions are hard to listen to but captivating all the same. The compositions are stark and atmospheric, allowing Cave to color in the spaces with his imperfect yet booming voice. His lyrics have rarely been straightforward- as they tend to remain awash in allegory and parable, but he drops the façade occasionally to allow the listener to share in his uncomfortable pain. There’s a weird, overarching sense of hope underneath all of the despair, though, that keeps the album from being a suffocating experience. Cathartic despair. </p>



<p>6. Lana Del Rey, <em>Norman Fucking Rockwell</em> (Interscope)</p>



<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1uFv9Ts7Sdw" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>



<p>Lana Del Rey swears her persona is not a “persona.” Regardless of whether the fatalistic, woman-out-of-her-time character is a pose, Del Rey has tapped into something singular and otherworldly, and she has finally created the perfect soundtrack for her guise. Like a black jelly bean in the middle of an apple pie, Del Rey aims to sully the fantasy of the American Dream. Her methods are equally calculating and alluring, but her lyrical acumen elevates her into a rarified league of songwriters. This album is a gorgeously constructed, beautifully sung, and hard to forget.     </p>



<p>7. Chromatics, <em>Closer To Grey</em> ( Italians Do It Better)</p>



<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PjUblmk4Cyo" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>



<p>After teasing the release of the rumored concept album <em>Dear Tommy</em> for nigh on five years, Chromatics returned in 2019 by surprise releasing a completely different record. <em>Closer to Grey</em> runs through the same hall of icy pop mirrors as 2012’s <em>Kill for Love</em> did, but what it lacks in new sonic ground it more than makes up for in substance. Chromatics are masters of monochromatic mood, and this is late night, windows down, driving-through-L.A.-with-the-stereo-at-full-volume music. A haunting soundtrack for what lurks in the night full of whispered, reverb-drenched vocals, sinister synths, splintering guitars and robotic beats.    </p>



<p>8. Brittany Howard, <em>Jaime</em> (ATO)</p>



<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CfizQsGWOxI" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>



<p>Brittany Howard’s genre-swerving debut is the rare
example of a presumably pigeon-holed artist defiantly rising above expectations
through unabashed talent. Her songs can feel like off the cuff fragments but
betray a deeper craft upon repeated listens. With elements of hip hop, roots rock,
neo-soul, and funk, Howard eclipses stereotype with an urgency and vitality
that seems effortless for her. “Stay High” is an infectious instant classic
that feels like it’s always existed. </p>



<p>9. Thom Yorke, <em>ANIMA</em> (XL)</p>



<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IZfCj7tuZ-E" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>



<p>Amazingly, Thom Yorke’s existential dread has not worn out its welcome after a couple of decades of his flaunting his myriad neuroses. Without his bandmates in Radiohead, Yorke tends to zoom in extremely close on his anxieties that are reflected not only in his mellifluous voice but also in the choppy electronics that always seem to accompany it on his solo outings. Yorke’s nervous energy is contagious. His ability to make such peculiar music palatable to a large audience is uncanny. <em>Anima </em>disregards traditional composition and structure, allowing the songs to unfurl in unexpected waves, where mood dominates form.    </p>



<p>10. FKA Twigs, <em>Magdeline </em>(Young Turks)</p>



<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gnmDMAVdaPc" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>



<p>I do not recommend listening to this album while doing other things because at low volume <em>Magdeline</em> blends into the background. I remained unimpressed several times through only to be floored once I put on a set of headphones. Now that I’ve listened to it as God intended, I am in awe of it. FKA Twigs has an extraordinary voice that she wields like a venomous weapon. The production is caustic and futuristic and surprising. She confronts heartbreak, depression, and public scrutiny with unrestrained vulnerability. Her voice can sound small and fragile one moment only to transform into a searing force the next. <em>Magdeline </em>is an artistic statement by someone whose story is far from finished.    </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tug Baker&#8217;s Top Albums of 2019</title>
		<link>./../../../2020/01/04/tug-bakers-top-albums-of-2019/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 21:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yearend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Thief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faye Webster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FKA Twigs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freddie Gibbs and Madlib]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nick Cave and the Bad Seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Purple Mountains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sharon Van Etten]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sturgill Simpson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vampire Weekend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weyes Blood]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../wp/index.html?p=7855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I feel like I had more albums than ever in my running yearlong playlist this year, but I didn&#8217;t get to spend nearly the time with all of them that I would have liked to. Here&#8217;s my list of the albums that rose above the noise in 2019. (Minus metal records. Those might get their [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed-spotify wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-spotify wp-embed-aspect-9-16 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Spotify Embed: Tug&amp;apos;s Favorite Albums of 2019" style="border-radius: 12px" width="100%" height="352" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" loading="lazy" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/playlist/2e2aczjUS5nY3J11OMIA23?si=fYRMbmhQQSG3P1bx4Pb5oA&#038;utm_source=oembed"></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>I feel like I had more
albums than ever in my running yearlong playlist this year, but I didn&#8217;t get to
spend nearly the time with all of them that I would have liked to. Here&#8217;s my
list of the albums that rose above the noise in 2019. (Minus metal records.
Those might get their own list later.) And a handy playlist too!</p>



<span id="more-7855"></span>



<p>40. Girlpool &#8211; What
Chaos Is Imaginary</p>



<p>39. Holly Herndon &#8211;
PROTO</p>



<p>38. Tyler Childers &#8211;
Country Squire</p>



<p>37. Toro y Moi &#8211; Outer
Peace</p>



<p>36. The Highwomen &#8211;
s/t</p>



<p>35. Chromatics &#8211;
Closer To Grey</p>



<p>34. The Hold Steady &#8211;
Thrashing Thru The Passion</p>



<p>33. Orville Peck &#8211;
Pony</p>



<p>32. Better Oblivion
Community Center &#8211; s/t</p>



<p>31. Nivhek &#8211; After its
own death / Walking in a spiral towards the house</p>



<p>30. Charly Bliss &#8211;
Young Enough</p>



<p>29. Carly Rae Jepsen &#8211;
Dedicated</p>



<p>28. Clairo &#8211; Immunity</p>



<p>27. duendita &#8211; direct
line to My Creator</p>



<p>26. Angel Olsen &#8211; All
Mirrors</p>



<p>25. Budos Band &#8211; V</p>



<p>24. Charli XCX &#8211;
Charli</p>



<p>23. Jenny Lewis &#8211; On
The Line</p>



<p>22. The National &#8211; I
Am Easy to Find</p>



<p>21. Lana Del Ray &#8211;
Norman Fucking Rockwell!</p>



<p>20. Jenny Hval &#8211; The
Practice of Love</p>



<p>19. Billie Eilish &#8211;
WHEN WE ALL FALL ASLEEP, WHERE DO WE GO?</p>



<p>18. Brittany Howard &#8211;
Jaime</p>



<p>17. Nilüfer Yanya &#8211;
Miss Universe</p>



<p>16. Aldous Harding &#8211;
Designer</p>



<p>15. Mannequin Pussy &#8211;
Patience</p>



<p>14. Fontaines D.C. &#8211;
Dogrel</p>



<p>13. Mal Blum &#8211; Pity
Boy</p>



<p>12. black midi &#8211; Schlagenheim</p>



<p>11. Solange &#8211; When I
Get Home</p>



<p>10. Sturgill Simpson &#8211;
SOUND &amp; FURY</p>



<p>9. Freddie Gibbs and
Madlib &#8211; Bandana</p>



<p>8. Weyes Blood &#8211;
Titanic Rising</p>



<p>7. Vampire Weekend &#8211;
Father of the Bride</p>



<p>6. Purple Mountains &#8211;
s/t</p>



<p>5. Sharon Van Etten &#8211;
Remind Me Tomorrow</p>



<p>4. Nick Cave and the
Bad Seeds &#8211; Ghosteen</p>



<p>3. FKA twigs &#8211;
MAGDALENE</p>



<p>2. Faye Webster &#8211;
Atanta Millionaires Club</p>



<p>1. Big Thief &#8211;
U.F.O.F./Two Hands (tie)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Patrick Wall&#8217;s Top Albums of 2019</title>
		<link>./../../../2020/01/01/patrick-walls-top-albums-of-2019/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 20:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yearend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../wp/index.html?p=7851</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ABOUT THE AUTHOR: Is Patrick Wall the only one here who gives a shit about the rules? KNEE MEETS JERK: A Tragicomedy in Three Acts Or, In Which a Mostly Retired Music Critic and Journalist Offers Brief, Non-Critical and Non-Sequitur Thoughts Only Tangentially Related to His Favorite Music of 2019. Because, Hey, Music Is Personal [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">ABOUT THE AUTHOR: Is Patrick Wall the only one here who gives a shit about the rules?

<strong>KNEE MEETS JERK: A Tragicomedy in Three Acts</strong>
<em>Or, In Which a Mostly Retired Music Critic and Journalist Offers Brief, Non-Critical and Non-Sequitur Thoughts Only Tangentially Related to His Favorite Music of 2019. Because, Hey, Music Is Personal and Subjective, Right?&nbsp;</em>

<em>Listed in alphabetical order. Results subject to change.</em>

I’m not sure I know where to begin.

So maybe this is a place as good as any: In mid-December, when year-in-review lists started propagating, my friend Reid asked on Twitter how folks can keep up with the never-ending stream of just so much god damned stuff, let alone listen to it and hopefully connect to some of it.

My short answer is simple and practical: I keep a list. In years past, it’s been in a spiral-bound notebook or a Microsoft Word file; this year, it was in a Google Keep sticky note. If I listen to a record and it strikes me on some fundamental level, I make an entry on my list: the release date, the artist, the record, and the label that released it. Come the end of the year, compiling a favorites list is easy: I go back to my list. Some years, there’s a little chaff to be trimmed. Some years there isn’t. But the list helps keep the year-end panic at bay.&nbsp;

The long answer is complicated.

<span id="more-7851"></span>

I used to write about music for a living. I don’t anymore. I quit about halfway through the decade, ground down by the constant grind of the pitch cycle, by the burden of an inbox groaning under the weight of unread emails with watermarked promos, by the nerve-fraying vexation of having to repeatedly defend my opinions. Part of it was the pay grade, sure, but the fun went out of it, too. There is more music released on a daily basis than it is even possible to listen to. Digging through hundreds of albums a month in search of hidden gems became a chore. Content became currency. Human and algorithms blended inseparably. To put words onto a page was to scream into a garbled cacophony of voices. Good writing, bad writing —&nbsp;didn’t matter. It was all folly. Creating a top ten lists at the end of the year —&nbsp;the dick-measuringest of internet dick-measuring contests — even more so.

So I gave it up.&nbsp;

My standard line is that I’m happier now. I don’t know how true that really is. Sure, regular hours and financial stability and health insurance are nice. But the way I interact with music has changed. My tastes have broadened. As I’ve become less interested in defending my opinions, I’ve become perhaps less attuned to them. I don’t know how fully I can articulate why I preferred a certain piece of music over the manifold other pieces of music floating around in the vast ether of the internet. I’m a moving target: My inclinations change in response to any manner of stimuli: whims, weather, mood, whatever. What I like today I might not like as much —&nbsp;or at all —&nbsp;tomorrow, let alone come the end of a month or a year or a decade. I engage with music on my own terms, but those terms are fluid, capricious, unexamined.

Taste, Susan Sontag wrote, has no systems and no proofs. But isn’t the unexamined life, as Socrates mused, not worth living?

All this is to say that I didn’t really search for any throughline in my listening habits in 2019. A cursory glance leaves a few suggestions: ambiance, isolation, confusion, nostalgia. Endless disappointment. Bone-deep dissatisfaction.&nbsp;

So here’s what I focused on instead. I climbed two mountains. I played on a hockey team that, after winning exactly zero games in the previous two years, took home a tournament trophy. I went to my first professional development conference in a city I’d never been to and spent as much time biking and wandering around as I did networking. I set a number of personal bests: fastest crossword times, fastest miles, heaviest Olympic lifts.

This all means something, I’m sure. I do not know what that is.

It’s the primary circumstance of humanity that we are imperfect, that we are built upon an apotheosis that we can never fully attain. At every point in between our first breath and our last we are, therefore, continually guessing, grasping at straws to cobble a basic sense of self. Perhaps, in that way, we can never really know ourselves.

Sometimes, there aren’t endings. What we perceive as foreshadowing is ultimately a projection, devoid of tangible meaning. Sometimes, questions can’t be answered. Ultimately, this is all just a blip, the briefest of stops on a train that’s been running for four billion years since life bubbled out of the primordial ooze. Deadlines are arbitrary. So-called milemarkers delineate nothing. To say that achievements are meaningless is to state the obvious. Time turns everything to dust. Death destroys all memory.&nbsp;

But the absence of intrinsic meaning allows us to ascribe our own meaning to what we do. It is because nothing has meaning unto itself that we are free to create meaning.&nbsp;

As I age, and as I step farther away from being all-consumed by cultural criticism, it’s only been reinforced that I will never, ever be confident in any assessment that any one record is the quote-unquote best. That answer will change every day until I die. So what follows is just a best guess. Tomorrow, or the next day, or the one after that, I’ll remember some melody that moved me, or I’ll revisit a song or record that I connected with once but no longer do. No man, Heraclitus mused, can step twice in the same stream. Ain’t the same stream, after all. For that matter, ain’t the same man.

The point of liking music is finding some personal resonance in it, even if that resonance is inexplicable, its origins too Delphic to discern. Does knowing that I don’t know why I like a piece of music mean that I don’t know myself? Or does being free from the burden of communicating the pleasure I receive mean that I know myself fully? How do I even answer that question?

I’m not sure I even know where to begin.

<strong>I. Perspicacity</strong>
<em>Or, Records Released in the Past Twelve Months That I Felt Compelled to Listen to More Than Once</em>

75 Dollar Bill, <em>I Was Real</em> [Glitterbeat]
Joshua Abrams &amp; Natural Information Society, <em>Mandatory Reality</em> [Eremite]
Altars Altars, <em>Fragments</em> [Home Normal]
Teodross Avery, <em>After the Rain</em> [Tompkins Square]
Jaimie Branch, <em>Fly or Die II: Birds of Paradise</em> [International Anthem]
Chris Cohen, <em>Chris Cohen</em> [Captured Tracks]
The Comet Is Coming, <em>Trust in the Lifeforce of the Deep Mystery</em> [Impulse!]
Floating Points, <em>Crush</em> [Ninja Tune]
Richard Dawson, <em>2020</em> [Domino]
Dibia$e, <em>Bonus Levels</em> [Fat Beats]
Fennesz, <em>Agora</em> [Touch]
Freddie Gibbs &amp; Madlib, <em>Bandana</em> [Keep Cool]
Robert Glasper, <em>Fuck Yo Feelings</em> [Loma Vista]
Gotobeds, <em>Debt Begins at 30</em> [Sub Pop]
Steve Gunn, <em>The Unseen In Between</em> [Matador]
Dave Harrington Group, <em>Pure Imagination, No Country</em> [Clandestine]
Loraine James, <em>For You and I</em> [Hyperdub]
Matt LaJoie, <em>The Center and the Fringe</em> [Flower Room]
Lake Mary &amp; the Ranch Family Band, <em>Sun Dogs</em> [Whited Sepulchre/Full Spectrum]
Lambchop, <em>This (is what I wanted to tell you)</em> [Merge]
le berger, <em>for an audience of not a single cow</em> [self-released]
Loscil, <em>Equivalents</em> [Kranky]
Galcher Lustwerk, <em>Information</em> [Ghostly International]
Mdou Moctar, <em>Ilana (The Creator)</em> [Sahel Sounds]
Mount Eerie, <em>Lost Wisdom Pt. 2</em> [P.W. Elverum &amp; Sons]
Nérija, <em>Blume</em> [Domino]
Bill Orcutt, <em>Odds Against Tomorrow</em> [Palilalia]
Junius Paul, <em>Ism</em> [International Anthem]
Rapsody, <em>Eve</em> [Roc Nation]
r beny, <em>Echo’s Verse</em> [Dauw]
Resavoir, <em>Resavoir</em> [International Anthem]
Ronin Arkestra, <em>First Meeting</em> [Albert’s Favourites]
Sault, <em>5</em> [Forever Living Originals]
Seabuckthorn, <em>Crossing</em> [Eilean]
Gavin Singleton, <em>Weak Intl.</em> [s/r]
Julia Shapiro, <em>Perfect Vision</em> [Hardly Art]
Sunwatchers, <em>Illegal Moves</em> [Trouble in Mind]
Suss, <em>High Line</em> [Northern Spy]
William Tyler, <em>Goes West</em> [Merge]
Billy Woods &amp; Kenny Segal, <em>Hiding Places</em> [Backwoodz]
Thom Yorke, <em>Anima</em> [XL]
zakè (扎克), <em>Orchestral Tape Studies</em> [Past Inside the Present]

<strong>II. Whimsy</strong>
<em>Or, Bonus Tracks!: A Handful of Songs From Albums Not Listed Above</em>

2 Chainz, “N.C.A.A.”
21 Savage, “a lot”
Big Thief, “Cattails”
Jordan Blackmon, “A New Hymn”
Caleb Burhans, “A Moment for Jason Molina”
Denzel Curry, “Ricky”
D’Angelo, “Unshaken”
Da Baby, “Suge”
Brittany Howard, “Stay High”
Killpete, “No Backseat”
Lizzo, “Juice”
Noname, “Song 31”
Oscillator Sink, “Pattern One”/”Pattern Two”
Jeff Parker &amp; the New Breed, “Max Brown”
Sandro Perri, “Time (You Got Me)”
This Is Lorelai, “We Are Taking You Home”

<strong>III. Paradigm</strong>
<em>Or, Notable Reissues &amp; Archival Records</em>

Richard Buckner, <em>Dents and Shells</em> [Merge]
John Coltrane, <em>Blue World</em> [Impulse!]
Duster, <em>Capsule Losing Contact/Duster</em> [Numero Group]
Brian Eno, <em>Apollo: Atmospheres &amp; Soundtracks</em> [UMC]
Steve Roach, <em>Quiet Music Vol. 1–3</em> [Projekt]
Sonny Sharrock, <em>Ask the Ages</em> [Hivemind]
Various, <em>Kankyō Ongaku: Japanese Ambient, Environmental &amp; New Age Music 1980-1990</em> [Light in the Attic]
Various, <em>Nigeria 70: No Wahala: Highlife, Afro-Funk &amp; Juju 1973-1987</em> [!K7 Music]
Various, <em>No Other Love: Midwest Gospel (1965–1978)</em> [Topmkins Square]

<strong>IV. Catharsis</strong>
<em>Or, A Smattering of Good Live Sets</em>

Rafiq Bhatia, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, Massachusetts, March 1
Richard Buckner, Atwood’s Tavern, Cambridge, Massachusetts, November 2
Charnel Ground, Lilypad, Cambridge, Massachusetts, April 17
Kuzu, Nash Hall, Raleigh, North Carolina, September 7
Mdou Moctar, Kings, Raleigh, North Carolina, September 7
The Messthetics, Great Scott, Allston, Massachusetts, July 14
SUSS, Lizard Lounge, Cambridge, Massachusetts, November 21
William Tyler, Columbus Theatre, Providence, Rhode Island, February 23
Ken Vandermark &amp; Nate Woolley, The Alternative Space, Watertown, Massachusetts, April 25

-30-

 </pre>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tug Baker&#8217;s Top Albums of 2014</title>
		<link>./../../../2015/01/02/tug-bakers-top-albums-of-2014/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 23:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yearend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top albums of 2014]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7704</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tug Baker is an eater of things, and an arbiter of tunes. He has shared his best of list from About Today. 1. Run The Jewels, Run the Jewels 2 (Mass Appeal, Sony Red) 2. Hurray For The Riff Raff, Small Town Heroes (ATO) 3. Sturgill Simpson, Metamodern Sounds in Country Music (Loose Music) 4. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				Tug Baker is an <a href="http://www.free-times.com/site/search_results/25cd14ba04117a6db6670571957aa536/">eater of things</a>, and an arbiter of tunes. He has shared his best of list from <a href="http://about-today.tumblr.com/post/105866255064/about-todays-favorite-albums-of-2014">About Today</a>.</p>
<p>1. Run The Jewels, <em>Run the Jewels 2</em> (Mass Appeal, Sony Red)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/uuWQyfGa1yI" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>2. Hurray For The Riff Raff, <em>Small Town Heroes</em> (ATO)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/_KvXteZkByE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>3. Sturgill Simpson, <em>Metamodern Sounds in Country Music</em> (Loose Music)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/6gBV-Nzq7Pg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>4. Sharon Van Etten, <em>Are We There</em> (Jagjaguwar)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/80-_CpH07QQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>5. FKA twigs, <em>LP1</em> (Young Turks)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/3yDP9MKVhZc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>6. Iceage, <em>Plowing Into the Field of Love</em> (Matador)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/roB4hRdLlas" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>7. Cory Branan, <em>The No-Hit Wonder</em> (Bloodshot)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/RZpuuYMTOWk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>8. Cloud Nothings, <em>Here and Nowhere Else</em> (Carpark)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/74TP8QhupLU" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>9. Alvvays, <em>s/t</em> (Polyvinyl)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/TOS2HcQ0soM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>10. Ryan Adams, <em>1984</em> (Pax AM)<br />
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/vM8mdLw4fBU" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><span id="more-7704"></span></p>
<p>11. Jack White, <em>Lazaretto</em> (Third Man)<br />
12. Wye Oak, <em>Shriek</em> (Merge)<br />
13. Noah Gundersen, <em>Ledges</em> (Dualtone)<br />
14. Death From Above 1979, <em>The Physical World</em> (Last Gang)<br />
15. Beverly, <em>Careers</em> (Kanine)<br />
16. Freddie Gibbs &#038; Madlib, <em>Pinata</em> (Madlib Invazion)<br />
17. St. Vincent, <em>s/t</em> (Loma Vista)<br />
18. Bishop Allen, Lights Out (Dead Oceans)<br />
19. Todd Terje, <em>It’s Album Time</em> (Olsen)<br />
20. Grouper, <em>Ruins</em> (Kranky)<br />
21. First Aid Kit, <em>Stay Gold</em> (Columbia)<br />
22. D’Angelo and the Vanguard, <em>Black Messiah</em> (RCA)<br />
23. Flying Lotus, <em>You’re Dead!</em> (Warp)<br />
24. Ex Hex, <em>Rips</em> (Merge)<br />
25. Mac Demarco, <em>Salad Days</em> (Captured Tracks)<br />
26. Fear of Men, <em>Loom</em> (Kanine)<br />
27. The #1s, <em>The Number Ones</em> (Static Shock)<br />
28. Protomartyr, <em>Under Color Of Official Right</em> (Hardly Art)<br />
29. Chromeo, <em>White Women</em> (Last Gang)<br />
30. The Budos Band, <em>Burnt Offering</em> (Daptone)<br />
31. Mr Twin Sister, <em>s/t</em> (Infinite Best)<br />
32. Owen Pallet, <em>In Conflict</em> (Domino)<br />
33. Marissa Nadler, <em>July</em> (Sacred Bones)<br />
34. Spoon, <em>They Want My Soul</em> (Loma Vista)<br />
35. Joyce Manor, <em>Never Hungover Again</em> (Epitaph)<br />
36. Prince, <em>ART OFFICIAL AGE</em> (Warner Bros.)<br />
37. King Creosote, <em>From Scotland With Love</em> (Domino)<br />
38. Yumi Zouma, <em>EP</em> (Cascine)<br />
39. Sharon Jones &#038; The Dap Kings, <em>Give The People What They Want</em> (Daptone)<br />
40. Pharmakon, <em>Bestial Burden</em> (Sacred Bones)		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Robert J. Howell&#8217;s Top Albums of 2014</title>
		<link>./../../../2015/01/02/robert-j-howells-top-albums-of-2014/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rjh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 23:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yearend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top albums of 2014]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This year I can&#8217;t in good conscience list ten albums in order. It always feels like splitting invisible hairs to decide between one and two or five and six, and when the albums I loved this year are such a diverse bunch it just seems silly. (I would say it is like comparing apples to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				This year I can&#8217;t in good conscience list ten albums in order. It always feels like splitting invisible hairs to decide between one and two or five and six, and when the albums I loved this year are such a diverse bunch it just seems silly. (I would say it is like comparing apples to oranges, but one can compare apples to oranges easily. Oranges are much better. Clearly. Ask anyone.) There is a unifying theme in my list, though it embarrasses me a bit to notice it. Almost all of these albums have a throwback quality to them. They often involve attempts to recapture something pure from earlier incarnations of the genres. The best albums of the year represent pure forms of rap/hip-hop, country/rock and punk. Among the others you can hear echoes of Madonna, Magnetic Fields, Silver Jews, and (um, of course) the Talking Heads. St. Vincent is probably the exception. As an aside, it somehow seems to me that many of the newest sounds these days come from women&#8211;witness Cate LeBon, PJ Harvey, and Bjork. And Radiohead. I guess Radiohead is the exception that proves the rule is not really a rule after all. In any case, here&#8217;s my shot at this year&#8217;s list.</p>
<p><strong>Tier 1</strong></p>
<p>Cloud Nothings, <em>Here and Nowhere Else</em> (Subpop)</p>
<p>These Cleveland darlings just keep getting better with every release.  There are shades of Nirvana, The Descendants, and about a dozen other punky lovelies.  I probably listened to this one more than any album this year.</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KxeNn_O5u5E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Run the Jewels, <em>RTJ2</em> (Mass Appeal)</p>
<p>In this year of racial fucknuttery, with white cops reviving scenes of Selma and dumbasses taking it out perfectly innocent police, it was a perfect year for RTJ2 to bring us intelligent, hard hitting rap.  El-P and Killer Mike have had the year of their lives and the excitement is infectious as hell.  Just hearing Killer Mike start the thing out makes me start punching the air.  Lie, Cheat, Steal might be the track of the year.</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PLFejWCokwV9QasMOfppGDSZoXB5eQijs7" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Angel Olsen, <em>Burn Your Fire for No Witness</em> (Jagjaguwar)</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not really fair to have a voice this strong while still kicking ass as a songwriter.  How can someone like this not make those boneheads in Nashville change the way they think about making and marketing music?  If you liked Sharon von Etten&#8217;s Tramp, and you did if you are even moderately reasonable, this album should be on your shelf.  Like von Etten, Olsen spills her guts with style, but perhaps with a greater diversity of styles.  She morphs from Patsy Cline to Leonard Cohen in a heartbeat.</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oL_3Y4zNnqg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Tier II</strong></p>
<p>Sturgill Simpson, <em>Metamodern Sounds in Country Music</em> (High Top Mountain Records)</p>
<p>My friend Eric turned me onto this saying &#8220;This guy is legit as shit,&#8221; and this album plus that comment is a good reminder of why we love our friends.  I haven&#8217;t been as excited about country since Richard Buckner&#8217;s early albums.  Unapologetically excellent.  (Might be paired well with Luke B. Goebel&#8217;s &#8220;14 Stories and None of them are Yours.&#8221;  Those two guys might be the same damn person.)</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w5cMqD0WqYE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Death from Above 1979, <em>The Physical World</em> (Last Gang/Warner Bros.)</p>
<p>Another album from a duo who packs the energy of an entire decade of rock.  I doubt these two spend afterparties riding alligators around a hotel room bonfire, but they sound like it.  I&#8217;ll eagerly wait another ten years for these guys to record another album if I have to.  This stuff is timeless.</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iBNxadj-25c?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>St. Vincent, <em>St. Vincent</em> (Loma Vista)</p>
<p>We Dallasites like to think of Annie Clark as our own, and those of us who have done time in that monochromatic suburb of Garland want to feel somewhat redeemed by the association.  But the truth is she is probably from outer space and has some Kryptonian story of how she got here.  For my money she belongs with PJ Harvey and Bjork as one of the most interesting and innovative artists out there.  She can hack the guitar into pieces and hit all manner of notes while stoically packaging herself for television consumption.  Every St. Vincent album is worth having, and this might be her best yet , but I wouldn&#8217;t be surprised if she just continues to get better for about sixty years.</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TAdARF4rGcQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Alvvays, <em>Alvvays</em> (Polyvinyl/Transgressive)</p>
<p>If I can&#8217;t include Chad VanGaalen&#8217;s album on my year end list, and honestly I can&#8217;t, I&#8217;m happy at least to include an album he produced.  Toronto based Alvvays&#8217; self-titled album is the sort of fresh lo-fi pop that is easy to try but damned difficult to pull off.  While they remind me a lot of Camera Obscura, they&#8217;re willing to let a little more fray show at the edges, and their sound is a little too rough to be twee.  Just try not to like Archie, Marry Me.  If you do try, you&#8217;re just being a jerk.</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZAn3JdtSrnY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><span id="more-7699"></span></p>
<p><strong>Tier III</strong></p>
<p>TV Girl, <em>French Exit</em> (Self-Released)</p>
<p>I&#8217;m such an unimaginative literalist that when I see a book is by a woman I assume until I&#8217;m told otherwise that the narrator is a woman.  I also assume that TV Girl will be a girl.  Both are bad assumptions.  TV Girl is basically a guy named Brad Petering who cobbles together brilliant pop-songs out of samples, keys, and a vulnerable voice.  If you combined Cinerama era David Gedge with Stephin Merritt you might get something like this.  Whatever&#8211;it&#8217;s damn good and you can download the whole thing (name your price) here: http://tvgirl.bandcamp.com/album/french-exit</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="375" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T39N3KKcS10?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Brian Eno and Karl Hyde, <em>High Life</em> (Warp)</p>
<p>By all rights Brian Eno should be resting on his laurels.  (For a long time I thought a laurel must be an ass-cheek. I looked it up and it&#8217;s not. It is, though, apparently rare only to have one laurel.  There the similarity pretty much ends.)  On his second record with Underworld&#8217;s Karl Hyde, though, Eno makes one of his best records in decades.  Usually a behind the scenes man, Eno brings the vocals this time and makes you wonder why he&#8217;s been keeping them under wraps. The sounds and textures here cast back to Fear of Music era Talking Heads&#8211;dense guitar and rhythm layers underneath chantlike vocals.  Sure, there&#8217;s some flirting with pretension here, but Eno&#8217;s earned our patience with that.</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qwnxypgED6s?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Tennis, <em>Ritual in Repeat</em> (Communion)</p>
<p>It would be an easy mistake to complain that Tennis is ripping off the 80s.  I mean, they are, and sometimes there&#8217;s just a little too much Madonna for my comfort, but when the result is this solid I can&#8217;t dismiss em.  The production is full and lush and the harmonies drape perfectly over the beats.  I kept coming back to this one almost despite myself.</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="400" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=true&#038;url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F152467559&#038;show_artwork=true&#038;maxwidth=500&#038;maxheight=750"></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Drew Harkins&#8217; Top Albums of 2013 (better late than never edition)</title>
		<link>./../../../2014/02/20/drew-harkins-top-albums-of-2013-better-late-than-never-edition/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[drew]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 16:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yearend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You think you&#8217;ve got game, and then you meet Drew Harkins and you throw the game away because you just can&#8217;t win. Deerhunter, Monomania (4AD) Pick your favorite review of this album: a.) Monomania is a willfully inscrutable/abstruse nocturnal garage pastiche of shopworn indie standards, pieced together meticulously from a post-nothing fakebook, delivered with mesmerizing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				You think you&#8217;ve got game, and then you meet Drew Harkins and you throw the game away because you just can&#8217;t win.</p>
<p><strong>Deerhunter</strong>, <em>Monomania </em> (4AD) </p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/k9MsFaFrrps?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Pick your favorite review of this album: </p>
<p>a.) Monomania is a willfully inscrutable/abstruse nocturnal garage pastiche of shopworn indie standards, pieced together meticulously from a post-nothing fakebook, delivered with mesmerizing panache and terrorizing aplomb. </p>
<p>b.) Deerhunter’s Monomania re-imagined as a Phish setlist, the way that guy from Dirty Projectors did Black Flag: </p>
<p>Anti-Scale Mode -> Puke Racket, Pot Arpeggioz, Schlock &#038; Choogle II, Churn/Thrust N’ Fey, Jam Progression -> Lawnmower Ratchet -> Omega Point, Denouement, Coy Spoon Acoustic Reprise </p>
<p>c.) When you get a tattoo on your shin, the majority of the work takes place on the fleshy haft of your lower leg. It’s mostly easy dermis for canvas, all smooth and humming along with the perfect amount of pinch, subtly reminding that you’re permanently defacing your skin. </p>
<p>The only actual pain comes when the needle bears down on the distal ends. A pitted feeling sucks your gut but passes quickly.  Those couple moments when the point clicks over that little groove in the ridgeline is the real treat, because it’s just enough to make your privates tingle. </p>
<p>d.) The Black Lips dudes dubbed Monomania “transcend-fi” and I see no reason to reinvent the wheel. </p>
<p>e.) Yes, Bradford. It was great. And it was punk. </p>
<p><strong>Queens of the Stone Age</strong>, <em>&#8230;Like Clockwork</em> (Matador)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/RjYZToXuJaM?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>“Some men are so macho they&#8217;ll get you pregnant just to kill a rabbit.”  &#8211; Maureen Murphy</p>
<p><span id="more-7454"></span></p>
<p><strong>Songs: Ohia</strong>, <em>The Magnolia Electric Company</em> (reissued) (Trifekta) </p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/gO6abj9yRUc?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>There’s been a surprisingly rich amount of reporting following the March passing of Jason Molina, so I’ll attempt to not stomp a dead horse in the face. </p>
<p>That said, I simply can’t not (intended) call a spade a spade. Molina may have died of natural causes as a result of alcohol abuse-related organ failure, but let’s be clear: Jason Molina shuffled off this mortal coil by way of brown-bottle seppuku. No more, no less. </p>
<p>You can pen fifteen thinkpieces examining the infinite regress or romantically redress his illness, or simply just call me an asshole, but Molina was always singing his own dirges. His life never belied his art. </p>
<p>The point is that when examined closely, his death was a choice. To be sure, a very complex choice with a number of psychological, social and maybe even biological variables that all dovetail intricately. But still a choice. </p>
<p>It’s a fucking shame. And it’s a sad, sad, thing. It’s all cunning and baffling and powerful and it just doesn’t make sense, even when it does.   </p>
<p>And you know, Magnolia, I really wish you could have chosen to hold on. Because I might understand very little about sobriety, but for what it’s worth, I do know that the pursuit is still invariably fraught with that truly ineluctable sorrow you were always searching for. </p>
<p><strong>Kacey Musgraves</strong>, <em>Same Trailer, Different Park</em> (Mercury Nashville)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/GZfj2Ir3GgQ?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>This is highly-nuanced country music for the shrewd yet still conflicted modern woman.  </p>
<p>On Saturday nights, she’ll listen to “Blowin’ Smoke” in the shower before going out to the bar, where she’s dumb enough to wait around for some drunk wannabe cowboy to stop losing at pool and flirting with dark-featured women to pay her some remote shred of attention. </p>
<p>On Sunday mornings, she’s smart enough to go to church and meet nice guys with professional degrees who wear khakis and want to buy her jewelry. </p>
<p>GIRL ARE YOU JEOPARDY BECAUSE GAME RECOGNIZE GAME </p>
<p><strong>Phosphorescent</strong>, <em>Muchacho</em> (Dead Oceans)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/ZPxQYhGpdvg?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Remember when you got to college and finally started smoking “good pot” and you just knew that the weed was potent because the buds were so … festively peppered with little red ‘hairs’?</p>
<p>You might say that Muchacho is a sack of heady little nuggets, that the hairs are Willie Nelson’s pubes and Gram Parsons laced the damn bag with the shit that killed Neil Young’s amigos. </p>
<p>But similes are for hacks, Chico, and you should probably just fashion an eeeeeeensy pillow fort with your words, nestle it all nice and smug right under ‘redolent’, toke on a little garden schwag and take a smooth power siesta.   </p>
<p><strong>Black Angels</strong>, <em>Indigo Meadow</em> (Blue Horizon)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/f-4gAjLt9Yo?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Beware of mixing LSD and other drugs, legal or not. Any time you do, you risk an adverse reaction with your own physiology that cannot be predicted.</p>
<p>Please visit Erowid.org for more information about LSD, including basics, effects, dosage, history, legal status, photos, research, media coverage and links to other resources. </p>
<p><strong>The Love Language</strong>, <em>Ruby Red</em> (Merge)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/tyNSUZh0toE?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Stuart McLamb is a ~pretti~ boy from the ~pretti~ state of North Carolina who makes ~pretti~ pop songs about ~pretti~ things with a bunch of ~pretti~	 collaborators and ~pretti~ stringed instruments. </p>
<p>They are quite often gorgeous, partially driving, sometimes sonically challenging, rarely dense, somewhat plucky, kind of orchestral, definitely a little bit twee, and in general, verklempt like a motherfucker. </p>
<p>This album sounds like a party with all of your friends on a lush spring night in college right before graduation. </p>
<p><strong>Arctic Monkeys</strong>, <em>AM</em> (Domino) </p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/qN7gSMPQFss?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>The slinky perversion of opener “Do I Wanna Know,” with its louche bassline, hither come-to and whimpering pout is enough to shoulder the load of this album on pulsing tumescence alone. </p>
<p>Because it’s that feeling when you want something so badly that plausible deniability goes out the window and you’re texting each other pitted barbs at 3 a.m., and even though she makes you so completely #scorpiomad that you throw your phone across the room, it only makes you want it worse. </p>
<p>The rest of the album is a charming bloke, gobsmackingly incisive about its own immaturity; basically all novel riffs and road beers, lyrical subterfuge, failed relationships and pained bravado, which I guess sums up my twenties in a nutshell. </p>
<p><strong>CHVRCHES</strong>, <em>The Bones Of What You Believe</em> (Glassnote)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/_mTRvJ9fugM?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>If you really think about it, fashion is literally the least important thing in the world. People who listen to Chvrches forfeit this irony.  </p>
<p><strong>Kanye West</strong>, <em>Yeezus</em> (Def Jam)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/BBAtAM7vtgc?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>There are three things I can count on in this world &#8212; death, taxes, and black women wanting to play with my hair. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Logan K. Young&#8217;s Top Albums of 2013</title>
		<link>./../../../2014/01/09/logan-k-youngs-top-albums-of-2013/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[logan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 16:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yearend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top albums of 2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year in review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7424</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Logan K. Young is the Editor in Chief at Classicalite.com. ALBUMS: Body/Head, Coming Apart (Matador) Lonnie Holley, Keeping a Record of It (Dust to Digital) Because Oxford American needs to see him. Wolf Eyes, No Answer: Lower Floors (De Stijl) Richard Youngs, Summer Through My Mind (Ba Da Bing!) Because Ba Da Bing! captured him [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				Logan K. Young is the Editor in Chief at <a href="http://www.classicalite.com/">Classicalite.com</a>.</p>
<p>ALBUMS:<br />
<strong>Body/Head</strong>, <em>Coming Apart</em> (Matador)					</p>
<p><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/74316335" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe> </p>
<p><strong>Lonnie Holley</strong>, <em>Keeping a Record of It</em> (Dust to Digital)<br />
Because Oxford American needs to see him.</p>
<p><strong>Wolf Eyes</strong>, <em>No Answer: Lower Floors</em> (De Stijl) 				</p>
<p><iframe width="420" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/grOANaD7cPA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Richard Youngs</strong>, <em>Summer Through My Mind</em> (Ba Da Bing!)<br />
Because Ba Da Bing! captured him at his prolific best.</p>
<p><strong>R. Kelly</strong>, <em>Black Panties</em> (RCA) 						</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/F9OhxEA5NHY?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Jace Clayton</strong>, <em>The Julius Eastman Memory Depot</em> (New Amsterdam)<br />
Because Eastman isn&#8217;t just a school in Rochester.</p>
<p><strong>Tim Berne&#8217;s Snakeoil</strong>, <em>Shadow Man</em> (ECM) 				</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/9TEEekONBsM?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Byron Coley</strong>, <em>Dating Tips for Touring Bands</em> (Hot Cars Warp)<br />
Because you should at least hear the one about Don Rickles and Giuliani.</p>
<p><strong>My Bloody Valentine</strong>, <em>m b v</em> (m b v)						</p>
<p><iframe class="vine-embed" src="https://vine.co/v/b1IXmQK1Z61/embed/simple" width="460" height="315" frameborder="0"></iframe><script async src="//platform.vine.co/static/scripts/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><strong>The Dead C</strong>, <em>Armed Courage</em> (Ba Da Bing!)<br />
Because, really, it’s been a while.</p>
<p>SINGLES:<br />
<strong>Phosphorescent</strong>, “Song for Zula” (Dead Oceans)<br />
<strong>Antwon</strong>, “Dying in the Pussy” (Suicide Squeeze)<br />
<strong>Benjamin Clementine</strong>, “Nemesis” (Later&#8230;with Jools Holland)<br />
<strong>David Bowie</strong>, “Where Are We Now?” (Columbia)<br />
<strong>Jennette McCurdy</strong>, “Wrecking Ball” (YouTube)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/1UrdkrVsEKY?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Jaap Blonk</strong>, “The Prime Minister I” (Plant Migration)<br />
<strong>Hair Police</strong>, “Mercurial Rites” (Type)<br />
<strong>Daft Punk</strong>, “Get Lucky” (Columbia)<br />
<strong>Jennifer Walshe</strong>, “In a Way, It’s All New Age Music” (THMOTES)<br />
<strong>Parquet Courts</strong>, “Stoned and Starving” (What&#8217;s Your Rupture?)</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/OKHAeZLBzME?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
