<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>gossip &#8211; Drawer B</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 14:53:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>gossip &#8211; Drawer B</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Alex Turner&#8217;s Mic-dropping Brit Awards Speech</title>
		<link>./../../../2014/02/23/alex-turners-mic-dropping-brit-award-speech/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 14:53:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gossip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alex Turner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arctic Monkeys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brit Awards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peaches Geldof]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7492</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Arctic Monkeys racked up again at the Brit Awards this year, taking home Best British Group for the fourth time and its well-deserved third Best British Album for AM. Lead singer Alex Turner used the occasion to drop an irony-laced speech that was a winking piss-take on the &#8220;state&#8221; of rock &#8216;n roll. Reactions have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/9ZzJtxrGmtQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Arctic Monkeys racked up again at the Brit Awards this year, taking home Best British Group for the fourth time and its well-deserved third Best British Album for <em>AM</em>. Lead singer Alex Turner used the occasion to drop an irony-laced speech that was a winking piss-take on the &#8220;state&#8221; of rock &#8216;n roll. Reactions have been hilariously all over the map. Peaches Geldof <a href="http://www.entertainmentwise.com/news/141571/Ungrateful-Tt-Peaches-Geldof-Blasts-Alex-Turner-Over-BRIT-Awards-Acceptance-Speech">called him</a> an &#8220;ungrateful twat,&#8221; but I dare say she didn&#8217;t pick up on any of Turner&#8217;s subversive humor. The <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/music/2014/feb/19/arctic-monkeys-win-british-album-of-the-year-2014-brits">comment section on this subject at The Guardian</a> is a goldmine.</p>
<p>Full transcript of Turner&#8217;s mic-dropping speech:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;That rock&#8217;n&#8217;roll, ay? That rock&#8217;n&#8217;roll, it just won&#8217;t go away. It might hibernate from time to time, sink back into the swamp. I think the cyclical nature of the universe in which it exists demands that it acquiesce to some of its rules. But it&#8217;s always waiting there, just around the corner, ready to make its way back through the sludge and smash through the glass ceiling, looking better than ever. Yeah, that rock&#8217;n&#8217;roll, it seems like it&#8217;s faded away sometimes, but it will never die. And there&#8217;s nothing you can do about it. Invoice me for the microphone if you need to.&#8221;   </p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Prince is Crazy, Contradicts Himself, Previews New 3rdEyeGirl Song</title>
		<link>./../../../2014/01/28/prince-is-crazy-contradicts-himself-previews-new-3rdeyegirl-song/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pat]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 01:56:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[controversy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gossip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prince]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To paraphrase Walt Whitman: Does Prince contradict himself? Very well, then. He is large, and he contains multitudes. Earlier today, The New York Times reported that two weeks ago Prince Rogers Nelson filed a lawsuit — well, his lawyers did on his behalf, anyway — against 22 bootleggers who allegedly posted unauthorized recordings of his [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/WkZlzrSzGLc" height="360" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>To paraphrase Walt Whitman: Does Prince contradict himself? Very well, then. He is large, and he contains multitudes.</p>
<p>Earlier today, <a href="http://artsbeat.blogs.nytimes.com/2014/01/28/prince-files-lawsuit-over-links-to-music-file-sharing-sites/?_php=true&amp;_type=blogs&amp;_r=0"><em>The New York Times</em> reported</a> that two weeks ago Prince Rogers Nelson filed a lawsuit — well, his lawyers did on his behalf, anyway — against 22 bootleggers who allegedly posted unauthorized recordings of his concerts to peer-to-peer sharing sites and their Facebook pages. The timestamp on the most recent update to the <em>Times</em> story reads 4:11 p.m. EST. (Oh, and</p>
<p>But not more than three hours later, The Purple One changed his mind, <a href="http://www.tmz.com/2014/01/28/prince-drops-22-million-lawuit-bootleggers-music/">TMZ reported</a>.</p>
<p>Oh, yeah, he also dropped a teaser of &#8220;PRETZELBODYLOGIC,&#8221; a song from his 3rd Eye Girl collaboration with Donna Grantis, Hannah Ford and Ida Neilsen. You can hear the 30-second clip above.</p>
<p>The lesson, as always: Prince moves in mysterious ways.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fiona Apple Tosses Heckler, Plays New Song</title>
		<link>./../../../2013/10/07/fiona-apple-tosses-heckler-plays-new-song/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 12:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[gossip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiona Apple]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Come on, people. You know Fiona Apple is very sensitive. She does not have thick enough skin for heckling, especially when it&#8217;s about her appearance. I have to admit I thought something was amiss when I saw her last September. She looked way too gaunt, but I know better than to yell my thoughts at [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<a href="http://media.drawerb.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/media/2013/10/ku-bigpic.jpg"></a></p>
<p>Come on, people. You know Fiona Apple is very sensitive. She does not have thick enough skin for heckling, especially when it&#8217;s about her appearance. I have to admit I thought something was amiss when I saw her last September. She looked way too gaunt, but I know better than to yell my thoughts at her while she&#8217;s trying to play songs. Anyway, Apple <a href="http://jezebel.com/fiona-apple-breaks-down-on-stage-after-heckler-calls-he-1441395329">had a heckler tossed</a> from her show in Portland last night for screaming, &#8220;Get Healthy. We want to see you in ten years!&#8221; Now, it sounds like said heckler was trying to be supportive, but that&#8217;s just not the way to go about such things. Apple played one more song after the incident and then left the stage in tears, because, OF COURSE SHE DID.</p>
<p>She did manage to play a new song before storming off stage:</p>
<p><iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F113771876"></iframe>		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dave Grohl Publicist &#8220;Won&#8217;t deny&#8221; Nirvana Reunion with Paul McCartney on Vocals</title>
		<link>./../../../2012/12/12/dave-grohl-publicist-wont-deny-nirvana-reunion-with-paul-mccartney-on-vocals/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 18:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[gossip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dave Grohl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Krist Novaselic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nirvana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paul McCartney]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=6974</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Photo swiped from Stereogum because it is awesome. Also, the file name is &#8220;Macvana.&#8221; I&#8217;m not sure what to make of the news that &#8220;Nirvana&#8221; will reunite tonight with Paul McCartney for the Hurricane Sandy Benefit. Are Dave Grohl and Kist Novaselic just taking the piss for hype&#8217;s sake? Or is Sir Paul going to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<a rel="attachment wp-att-6975" href="http://www.drawerb.com/2012/12/12/dave-grohl-publicist-wont-deny-nirvana-reunion-with-paul-mccartney-on-vocals/macvana/"></a></p>
<p>Photo swiped from <a href="http://stereogum.com/1219481/reunited-nirvana-to-perform-with-paul-mccartney-tonight/news/">Stereogum</a> because it is awesome. Also, the file name is &#8220;Macvana.&#8221;</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not sure what to make of the news that &#8220;Nirvana&#8221; will <a href="http://stereogum.com/1219481/reunited-nirvana-to-perform-with-paul-mccartney-tonight/news/">reunite tonight</a> with Paul McCartney for the <a href="http://www.spin.com/articles/watch-12-12-12-sandy-benefit-concert">Hurricane Sandy Benefit</a>. Are Dave Grohl and Kist Novaselic just taking the piss for hype&#8217;s sake? Or is Sir Paul going to slap on some dirty jeans and scream his way through &#8220;Rape Me?&#8221; If he does, he wins. I just don&#8217;t want it to turn into one of those lame all-star jams, where someone is back to back with Bruce Springsteen and the usual cast of relief effort mainstays shouting lyrics no one can hear into a shared mic. But, man, these <a href="http://www.spin.com/articles/paul-mccartney-nirvana-reunion-unconfirmed-sandy-benefit-12-12-12">publicists</a> are doing their jobs. My curiosity is piqued.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rumor Mill: Blur to release new single for Record Store Day</title>
		<link>./../../../2010/04/09/rumor-mill-blur-to-release-new-single-for-record-store-day/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 17:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[gossip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Graham Coxon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Record Store Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=5847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My wallet is certainly happy that I have a conflict with attending Record Store Day on April 17th, but now that a new Blur single might be in the mix I could be in trouble. Granted, the source is The Sun, so take this with the appropriate amount of salt, but Blur has reportedly regrouped [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				</p>
<p>My wallet is certainly happy that I have a conflict with attending <a href="http://www.recordstoreday.com/Home">Record Store Day</a> on April 17th, but now that a new Blur single might be in the mix I could be in trouble. Granted, <a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/showbiz/bizarre/2925423/Blur-to-release-their-first-single-for-seven-years.html">the source is The Sun</a>, so take this with the appropriate amount of salt, but Blur has reportedly regrouped and recorded a new single to be released on 7&#8243; format for Record Store Day. Quoth Blur singer Damon Albarn: &#8220;We want independent record stores to continue &#8211; they&#8217;re an  important part of our musical culture.&#8221; Only 1000 copies will be available and only in record shops in England. With only 1000 copies being pressed, the ones that end up on eBay will not be cheap. So that&#8217;s from whence my wallet pain may stem. But on the bright side, Blur might be releasing its first new single with Graham Coxon in over a decade.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Velvet Underground hang out at NY Public Library</title>
		<link>./../../../2009/12/12/velvet-underground-hang-out-at-ny-public-library/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[k]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2009 18:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[gossip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[link]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andy Warhol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Cale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Velvet Underground]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=5516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The three members of the influential 1960s rock band talked about their association with pop artist Andy Warhol in a program called &#8220;The Art and Soul of the Velvet Underground.&#8221; John Cale, who played bass and viola with the band, was not present at the Tuesday evening reunion. (via @stereogab)]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>The three members of the influential 1960s rock band talked about their association with pop artist Andy Warhol in a program called &#8220;The Art and Soul of the Velvet Underground.&#8221; John Cale, who played bass and viola with the band, was not present at the <a href="http://www.cbc.ca/arts/music/story/2009/12/10/velvet-underground.html">Tuesday evening reunion</a>.</p></blockquote>
<p>  (via @stereogab)		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beck swoops in and finishes the fight</title>
		<link>./../../../2009/11/20/beck-swoops-in-and-finishes-the-fight/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2009/11/20/beck-swoops-in-and-finishes-the-fight/index.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 17:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[controversy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gossip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fueds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matthew Friedberger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radiohead]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Fiery Furnaces]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=5467</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My favorite piece of news in the past week is Beck&#8217;s musical response to that clueless buffoon from The Fiery Furnaces, who tried to insult Radiohead, blog-style, but missed the point completely. And in attempting to cover his ass retroactively, took a swipe at Beck. Well, Radiohead, in their lofty chairs of utter superiority, ignored [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<a href="http://media.drawerb.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/media/2009/11/Beck2.jpg"></a></p>
<p>My favorite piece of news in the past week is Beck&#8217;s musical response to that clueless buffoon from <a href="http://www.thefieryfurnaces.com/site/">The Fiery Furnaces</a>, who tried to insult Radiohead, blog-style, but missed the point completely. And in attempting to cover his ass retroactively, took a swipe at Beck. Well, Radiohead, in their lofty chairs of utter superiority, ignored the noise from the male half of a middling indie rock duo, but Beck took a measured swing  and, of course, won handily.</p>
<p>As you may well be aware, Radiohead <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vztj_TnUQyY">wrote and recorded a song a few months back </a> as a tribute to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_Patch">Harry Patch</a>, the last surviving UK veteran of World War I, who died at the age of 111. Well, dingus extraordinaire, Matthew Friedberger from the unlistenable duo The Fiery Furnaces, decided out of the clear blue to mock Radiohead for their tribute song. Except, he lambastes them for all the wrong reasons. See, Friedberger somehow mistakenly thought that Radiohead had paid tribute to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_Partch">Harry Partch</a>, an American composer famous for his microtonal scales. He proceeded to <a href="http://pitchfork.com/news/37035-fiery-furnaces-matthew-friedberger-continues-radiohead-fight/">trash Radiohead</a> for their pretentiousness and calculated cultivation of cool. Except, whoops, wrong dude. Friedberger then released a confusing, self-mocking <a href="http://pitchfork.com/news/37035-fiery-furnaces-matthew-friedberger-continues-radiohead-fight/">statement</a> wherein he tried to make the whole thing sound like a deliberate joke. Never mind that it was awkward and, well, wrong. The last line of said statement is where it gets good: &#8220;Matt would have much preferred to insult Beck but he is too afraid of Scientologists.&#8221; So, ok, who doesn&#8217;t like a good Scientology joke? But the context of his snark just sounds like a desperate attempt to change the subject.</p>
<p>So, Beck quietly takes this all in and releases a <a href="http://beck.com/">tribute</a> to Harry Partch, both defending Radiohead and dogging Friedberger in one fell swoop. Well played, sir.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2009/11/20/beck-swoops-in-and-finishes-the-fight/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
