<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: VIDEO: The Pretty Reckless &#8220;Make Me Wanna Die&#8221;	</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 17:07:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Anonymous		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-1842</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anonymous]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 17:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=6080#comment-1842</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[OH MY GOD! Please tell me that her parents still allows her to do like this? Her parents are the worst parents in the whole wide world seriously! If only there&#039;s a way to get rid of her parents or change her parents no offense really, but she has gone way too far. If only her parents are religious and God fearing they would not allow their child to become a prostitute even if their child is famous and earns a lot of money. It&#039;s about how people would look at her as a good example and not being so wild/trashy/bad attitude she has, people might lose respect to her. 

I&#039;m not against her music: Actually I love her songs because the tunes are so catchy for emo goth girl like me but the way she brings up herself through the camera and on reality became worst.

She actually adopts her role on Gossip Girl to the real life and Am I the only one who was annoyed by her role in Gossip Girl? I hate hate her attitude and I can&#039;t believe a lot of Teenagers are following the bad example like her, Lindsay Lohan, Britney Spears, Paris Hilton and etc... I mean come on? 

If you know they are showing bad example why would you follow them?

There are a lot of former teen stars like Hilary Duff, Mary Kate and Ashley Olsen, Rayven Simone and etc are setting GOOD EXAMPLES TO EVERYONE. I mean why not them instead of Taylor? 

I know I&#039;m not suppose to butt in to other people&#039;s lives but if you could just think about what&#039;s going in the world today? What you seen in the news, what you&#039;ve heard on the radio and what you have seen on the internet/newspaper a lot of teens are getting unexpected pregnancy its all because of what children follow now a days like you&#039;ve seen on movies/ music videos and one example is this video. It&#039;s crazy!

WAKE UP! teens like Taylor should have discipline and for her to be mature, she should wear proper clothes and not getting almost naked in the video while she&#039;s underage. She needs to be supervised and needs to be controlled by their parents whether the kids like it or not. It&#039;s for their own Good!

Based on my experience, I&#039;m also getting sick from my parents not allowing me to do anything I want to do. But for some reasons I go deeper, and I think about what my parents decision why they do this to me even if I&#039;m already 21. I tried to look for both sides, my side and their side. I realized that they are doing this for me because they love me and they want to raise me in the right way and be protected. 

The lesson here is that having a strict parents should not make you feel bad or what so ever in whatever your thinking that they are ruining your life, NO that should not be it. 

You should learn from your mistakes and try to be a responsible starting with yourself and for others. And life would be different and you may lead yourself to the right path. So that they could trust you.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OH MY GOD! Please tell me that her parents still allows her to do like this? Her parents are the worst parents in the whole wide world seriously! If only there&#8217;s a way to get rid of her parents or change her parents no offense really, but she has gone way too far. If only her parents are religious and God fearing they would not allow their child to become a prostitute even if their child is famous and earns a lot of money. It&#8217;s about how people would look at her as a good example and not being so wild/trashy/bad attitude she has, people might lose respect to her. </p>
<p>I&#8217;m not against her music: Actually I love her songs because the tunes are so catchy for emo goth girl like me but the way she brings up herself through the camera and on reality became worst.</p>
<p>She actually adopts her role on Gossip Girl to the real life and Am I the only one who was annoyed by her role in Gossip Girl? I hate hate her attitude and I can&#8217;t believe a lot of Teenagers are following the bad example like her, Lindsay Lohan, Britney Spears, Paris Hilton and etc&#8230; I mean come on? </p>
<p>If you know they are showing bad example why would you follow them?</p>
<p>There are a lot of former teen stars like Hilary Duff, Mary Kate and Ashley Olsen, Rayven Simone and etc are setting GOOD EXAMPLES TO EVERYONE. I mean why not them instead of Taylor? </p>
<p>I know I&#8217;m not suppose to butt in to other people&#8217;s lives but if you could just think about what&#8217;s going in the world today? What you seen in the news, what you&#8217;ve heard on the radio and what you have seen on the internet/newspaper a lot of teens are getting unexpected pregnancy its all because of what children follow now a days like you&#8217;ve seen on movies/ music videos and one example is this video. It&#8217;s crazy!</p>
<p>WAKE UP! teens like Taylor should have discipline and for her to be mature, she should wear proper clothes and not getting almost naked in the video while she&#8217;s underage. She needs to be supervised and needs to be controlled by their parents whether the kids like it or not. It&#8217;s for their own Good!</p>
<p>Based on my experience, I&#8217;m also getting sick from my parents not allowing me to do anything I want to do. But for some reasons I go deeper, and I think about what my parents decision why they do this to me even if I&#8217;m already 21. I tried to look for both sides, my side and their side. I realized that they are doing this for me because they love me and they want to raise me in the right way and be protected. </p>
<p>The lesson here is that having a strict parents should not make you feel bad or what so ever in whatever your thinking that they are ruining your life, NO that should not be it. </p>
<p>You should learn from your mistakes and try to be a responsible starting with yourself and for others. And life would be different and you may lead yourself to the right path. So that they could trust you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
