<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Elvis Presley: not a racist	</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 03:10:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Eric Greenwood		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-308</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eric Greenwood]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 03:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2007/08/13/elvis-presley-not-a-racist/#comment-308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Elvis was often quick to admit his debt to black music, as the linked article clearly demonstrates, despite his naive mistake of saying no one sounded like him early in his career. He didn&#039;t dictate who came to see him play. Elvis also didn&#039;t claim to be a race unifier; he was just a singer. Being dead, he obviously has little control over how he is portrayed by this media thing you reference.&lt;/p&gt;
]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elvis was often quick to admit his debt to black music, as the linked article clearly demonstrates, despite his naive mistake of saying no one sounded like him early in his career. He didn&#8217;t dictate who came to see him play. Elvis also didn&#8217;t claim to be a race unifier; he was just a singer. Being dead, he obviously has little control over how he is portrayed by this media thing you reference.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: sandra m		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-307</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sandra m]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 02:42:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2007/08/13/elvis-presley-not-a-racist/#comment-307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After Elvis Presley&#039;s death, his legacy has been shaped in a way that distorts history.  First, he was not a co-founder of the music that came to be known as rock &#039;n roll.  Media continually mentions Presley in the same sentence as the likes of Ike Turner, Chuck Berry, Little Richard, and Fats Domino. Yet, those black pioneers were already established by the time Elvis came on the scene. Secondly,  Elvis Presley was not the race unifier he&#039;s portrayed to be.  Notwithstanding his collaboration with a few black musicians, Elvis played in segregated venues. That&#039;s the way it was in the South. But, black musicians saw something else happen at their concerts. As Little Richard recalled, white fans broke through the ropes that separated them and climbed down from their &quot;special&quot; section to be where the action was-with the black kids. Those moments were cited by the NAACP as being just as instrumental as marches and demonstrations in dismantling segregation. But, no such race mixing occurred at Elvis Presley concerts. Indeed, footage from his concerts show no black people in the audience. And, if somebody shows me one, he&#039;ll be there courtesy of Photoshop.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After Elvis Presley&#8217;s death, his legacy has been shaped in a way that distorts history.  First, he was not a co-founder of the music that came to be known as rock &#8216;n roll.  Media continually mentions Presley in the same sentence as the likes of Ike Turner, Chuck Berry, Little Richard, and Fats Domino. Yet, those black pioneers were already established by the time Elvis came on the scene. Secondly,  Elvis Presley was not the race unifier he&#8217;s portrayed to be.  Notwithstanding his collaboration with a few black musicians, Elvis played in segregated venues. That&#8217;s the way it was in the South. But, black musicians saw something else happen at their concerts. As Little Richard recalled, white fans broke through the ropes that separated them and climbed down from their &#8220;special&#8221; section to be where the action was-with the black kids. Those moments were cited by the NAACP as being just as instrumental as marches and demonstrations in dismantling segregation. But, no such race mixing occurred at Elvis Presley concerts. Indeed, footage from his concerts show no black people in the audience. And, if somebody shows me one, he&#8217;ll be there courtesy of Photoshop.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
