<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>review &#8211; Drawer B</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 19:40:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../../wp/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>review &#8211; Drawer B</title>
	<link>./../../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>REVIEW: Prince, Originals (Warner Bros.)</title>
		<link>./../../../../2019/06/28/review-prince-originals-warner-bros/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 18:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[album-review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jay Z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kenny Rogers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Martika]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Morris Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peggy McCreary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prince]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sheila E.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sinead O'Connor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Bangles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tidal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../wp/index.html?p=7786</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Prince’s estate has been a bit of a PR shambles since the star’s sudden death in April of 2016. The lack of any discernible will has led to a never-ending legal battle between Prince’s family and the banks appointed to care for the business dealings of the musician’s vast estate. Despite the financial squabbles, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft"></figure></div>



<p style="text-align:left">Prince’s estate has been a bit of a PR shambles since the star’s sudden death in April of 2016. The lack of any discernible will has led to a never-ending legal battle between Prince’s family and the banks appointed to care for the business dealings of the musician’s vast estate. Despite the financial squabbles, the estate has managed to eke out a few posthumous releases that one would assume even hardcore fans have to admire. Sadly, this is unlikely since Prince’s elite hardcore fans are an admittedly miserable and impossible lot to please, complaining endlessly about any and everything to do with the man. These releases speak more to spreading the legacy to potential fans as well as to those who already identify as “fams”- the term Prince applied to his followers as he found “fan” (short for a fanatic) to be derisive. </p>



<span id="more-7786"></span>



<p>The deluxe edition of Prince’s star-making <em>Purple Rain</em>
soundtrack, released in June of 2017, pried open the door to the man’s storied
vault with a bonus disc of mostly pristine versions of tracks that some had
only read about &#8211; much less heard &#8211; and had long become the stuff of legend
(presumably, elite collectors collectively rolled their eyes and laughed). Exactly
one year later a long-bootlegged session of Prince alone at the piano (pre-<em>Purple
Rain</em>) working out material in an impromptu session received a deluxe
package, <em>Piano &amp; Microphone 1983</em>. With Prince’s birthday as the
release pattern launch date, the estate has returned in 2019 with <em>Originals</em>&#8211;
a collection of songs Prince wrote for other artists. </p>



<p>Fulfilling a contractual obligation with Jay Z’s Tidal streaming service, with whom Prince had entrusted his catalog for streaming purposes toward the end of his life, the estate and Jay Z have compiled a swath of tunes Prince wrote primarily for his female protegees. Despite a few outliers, the bulk of the material stems from the start of Prince’s imperial period (1981-1985), where he was writing and recording in an almost constant state of motion. It was such a frantic period of creative inertia that Prince’s <a href="https://pitchfork.com/thepitch/prince-engineer-peggy-mccreary-interview-originals/">idea of a birthday gift</a> to his beleaguered engineer, Peggy McCreary, was to spend the day in the studio and record a song for her. I’m pretty sure she just wanted to go to sleep, but she now owns a one-of-a-kind, unreleased Prince song. Not everyone can say that.</p>



<p>Hearing Prince’s voice instead of Morris Day’s on “Jungle
Love” is jarring at first. A lot of these songs were intended as guide vocals,
so a full-on radio-ready Prince is not always represented. And a song like
“Jungle Love” by The Time is so inextricably bound to the cultural fabric of
its time that hearing someone else sing it – even Prince &#8211; is hard to wrap your
head around. These issues don’t exist on lesser-known songs like Sheila E.’s
“Noon Rendevous,” which features a stunning, goose-bump-inducing vocal from
Prince. Or on the mind-blowing harmonic explosion of “Love… Thy Will Be Done,”
originally given to one-hit-wonder Martika. The demo version of “Manic Monday,”
which The Bangles turned into a smash hit in early 1986, is stripped to its
core and shows what a quality writer Prince was. It could have easily been
included on his psychedelic <em>Around The World In A Day</em> LP in 1985. Prince’s
recording schedule was so erratic during this period that his staff had to be
on call just to keep up with his muse. The music just flowed out of him.</p>



<p>Anyone well-versed in the deeper ends of Prince’s catalog
shouldn’t be too surprised that he wrote a song for country icon Kenny Rogers.
“You’re My Love” is a simple love song with a straightforward vocal melody as
its centerpiece. The way in which Prince sings it suggests that he was laying
down a blueprint for Rogers to follow exactly, which was typical of Prince’s
method. This is not how Prince would’ve sung it if he were to have meant it for
himself, however. Knowing how to meld your art to fit someone else’s aesthetic
requires a deep level of empathy and understanding. It’s a charming demo albeit
slightly rougher than some of the other songs on this collection.</p>



<p>Creating Sheila E.’s empowering persona was one of Prince’s
most successful side projects. Despite being a huge hit, the version of
“Glamorous Life” here is easier to digest with Prince’s voice because it’s more
in line with his androgynous vision at that time. Sheila E. even looked and
dressed like Prince during this era. With 10 of the 15 tracks written
specifically for women and engineered (mostly) by a woman, the overarching
theme of this compilation is female empowerment- or at least Prince’s version
of it, which leaned more towards sexual empowerment- a daring construct even in
the 1980s. There’s a mix of sexual bravado (“Sex Shooter”), sexual weirdness
(“Makeup”), elevating love over the material (“Glamorous Life”), and love
itself (“Love… Thy Will B Done”). And even though it was written and originally
given to Prince’s girlfriend’s band, The Family, “Nothing Compares 2 U” is pure
gut-wrenching heartbreak made internationally famous by another musically
pioneering woman, Sinead O’Connor.</p>



<p>Few artists have ever possessed the songwriting prowess and
depth that Prince demonstrated during this manic run in the 80s, and this
collection barely scratches the surface of the songs he gave away, much less
wrote for himself. Prince wanted to take over the world, and he wanted to do it
in lockstep with women leading the charge.&nbsp;
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>REVIEW: Fiona Apple, The Idler Wheel Is Wiser Than the Driver of the Screw and Whipping Cords Will Serve You More Than Ropes Will Ever Do (Epic)</title>
		<link>./../../../../2012/12/05/review-fiona-apple-the-idler-wheel-is-wiser-than-the-driver-of-the-screw-and-whipping-cords-will-serve-you-more-than-ropes-will-ever-do-epic/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 20:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[album-review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiona Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maude Maggart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=6910</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fiona Apple’s re-emergence every half decade or so is a triumphant celebration for a niche community of devotees and rather an apathetic shrug for the rest of America, which assumes (wrongly) that she’s just a Lilith Fair throwback, trying to claw her way back into the limelight. I belong to the former group, as my [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<a rel="attachment wp-att-6915" href="http://www.drawerb.com/2012/12/05/review-fiona-apple-the-idler-wheel-is-wiser-than-the-driver-of-the-screw-and-whipping-cords-will-serve-you-more-than-ropes-will-ever-do-epic/fiona-apple/"></a></p>
<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-6915" href="http://www.drawerb.com/2012/12/05/review-fiona-apple-the-idler-wheel-is-wiser-than-the-driver-of-the-screw-and-whipping-cords-will-serve-you-more-than-ropes-will-ever-do-epic/fiona-apple/"></a>Fiona Apple’s re-emergence every half decade or so is a triumphant celebration for a niche community of devotees and rather an apathetic shrug for the rest of America, which assumes (wrongly) that she’s just a Lilith Fair throwback, trying to claw her way back into the limelight. I belong to the former group, as my parenthetical aside betrays. Apple is a brilliant songwriter. I know this to be true. I just feel guilty enjoying her music as much as I do. She’s clearly unwell, both in heart and mind (no matter what she says on the chat shows), and this has never been more apparent than on her latest opus, the steely-eyed and daringly entitled <em>The Idler Wheel Is Wiser Than the Driver of the Screw and Whipping Cords Will Serve You More Than Ropes Will Ever Do</em>.</p>
<p>“Every Single Night” is a most bizarre album opener and even more confounding as a single. With its wild dynamic shifts from heart pounding chants to shaky whispers, Apple sounds not of sound mind. But it works on every level. The lyrics are obsessively reflective, of course, as Apple analyzes the tricks her brain plays on her night after night. She’s fixated on how the brain functions, and its impact on her many neuroses has infiltrated her perceptiveness as a songwriter. You simply can’t help but believe her when she whisper-sings, maniacally, “I just want to feel everything.” On “Daredevil” Apple concedes that she may indeed “need a chaperone” as she’s not to be left alone, but her melodies and vocal idiosyncrasies are so endearing that it’s easy to overlook the obvious pleas for help just to enjoy the song.</p>
<p><span id="more-6910"></span></p>
<p><em>The Idler Wheel</em>… is Apple’s most rhythmically dense album. Several songs spark from odd syncopations that effortlessly weave into minimal layers of piano, stilted percussion and Apple’s oddly nuanced delivery. Her piano refrains embed themselves into your subconscious before she even utters a word. But when the words do come, you can feel the songs slowly ensnare your emotions, too, until you’re trapped in her world, seeing things exactly as she sees them. It’s as frightening as it is moving. Apple’s rawness eschews judgment. The girl doesn’t give a damn what you think of her. She knows what she’s feeling, and she’s able to express it in myriad complicated ways.</p>
<p>Apple’s never been one to hold back- not on stage, not in interviews, and certainly not on record. For “Jonathan” Apple adopts one of her most frequented personae: that of spurned lover. The scorned woman in her has matured, however. Where once she would have raged she now eviscerates in subtle yet cutting ways. Her lyrics have never been better. To make such bitterness palpable yet musical is a talent few possess. On “Left Alone” her theme is simple: She wants to be loved but how can anyone love her and be close to her when all she wants is to be left alone? The Alanis Morrisettes of the world can’t conceive of that level of irony. And she lets loose of soul-mining, gut-wrenching insightfulness: “My ills are reticulate/my woes are granular/the ants weigh more than the elephants” before lurching into an operatic, bemoaning crescendo of the word “alone.” It’s staggeringly good.</p>
<p>The climax of the album &#8211; without question – is “Werewolf,” which very well might be Apple’s finest piece of songwriting to date. What sounds so simple is complicated by factors that aren’t necessarily obvious upon first listen. The lyrics are brutal and honest and hyperbolic. You know, normal Fiona Apple terrain. But her inflection is so universally empathetic and heart-rending that you can’t avoid being hypnotized by the simplicity of the verses, which she sings in a conversational, easy-going tone. The juxtaposition of the absurdity of the content versus the casual delivery is a bit of a mindfuck. The context, of course, is absurdly over the top, but she drifts into the world of meta in the non-sequitur coda/refrain: “There’s nothing wrong when a song ends in a minor key.” It’s more than just an infectious line. You can’t stop singing it to yourself once you’ve heard it. It has such a classic cadence that you can’t believe Elton John – or someone &#8211; hadn’t thought of it before now. It’s simply that good.</p>
<p>“Periphery” mines a familiar theme of love lost and squandered but with a new spirit of optimism engendered with true empathy and understanding. Apple’s lyrical incisiveness is what stands out, though: “Oh, the periphery/I lost another one there/he found a prettier girl than me/with a more even tempered air/and if he wants her, he should get her/cause I think she’s worth it.” Fiona Apple circa 1999 would never have said such things. She’s blowing off love lost? And even encouraging its culmination with another? What? The sadness in her voice is that of passive resignation. Even the vocal histrionics toward the end reveal an “oh well” sort of send-off. It’s a fine line between maturity and just not giving a shit anymore. But then the anger returns on “Regret”: “I ran out of white dove feathers/to soak up the hot piss that flows from your mouth/every time you address me.” Jesus. I would not want to be on the receiving end of that conversation.</p>
<p>“Anything We Want” is a shrewdly understated love song. It qualifies as quite jubilant for this record, though. It’s honest and open and nostalgic and imaginative but not in a sentimental way. There’s an air of dissonance that meanders through it – and the whole album, actually – that keeps you guessing. “Hot Knife” is vocal masterwork in the round, wherein she and her sister, Maude Maggart, play with exuberant harmonies, as though in a room of echoing infinity filled with nothing but voices. It’s a genre-bending tip of the hat to baroque pop’s past that showcases Apple’s respect for the sound of her own voice.  And, if the breathtaking brilliance of <em>The Idler Wheel</em>… proves anything, it’s that Apple knows she’s good, despite the fact that she may not be well.</p>
<p>&nbsp;		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>REVIEW: The Avett Brothers, The Gleam II, Ramseur</title>
		<link>./../../../../2008/09/22/review-the-avett-brothers-the-gleam-ii-ramseur/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[drew]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 20:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2008/09/22/review-the-avett-brothers-the-gleam-ii-ramseur/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What are a few country boys to do? Following their defining release, 2007&#8217;s Introducing: Emotionalism, Concord N.C.&#8217;s The Avett Brothers have enjoyed what most burgeoning bands would consider one hell of a year: National TV appearances, sold out shows in mid-sized venues across the U.S., a mention on Perez Hilton, and a move to the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://media.drawerb.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/media/2008/09/gleam.jpg"></a> What are a few country boys to do? Following their defining release, 2007&#8217;s <i>Introducing: Emotionalism</i>, Concord N.C.&#8217;s The Avett Brothers have enjoyed what most burgeoning bands would consider one hell of a year: National TV appearances, sold out shows in mid-sized venues across the U.S., a mention on Perez Hilton, and a move to the majors to record an album with Rick Rubin. With such widespread acclaim and a staggering tour schedule, the bucolic Avett boys, once considered a regional act at best, have precipitously found themselves perched on the cusp of national recognition.</p>
<p><span id="more-3419"></span> </p>
<p>So, in between all the hype and hullabaloo, how did they choose to position themselves for stardom? Rather than writing a primer with Rubin on &#8220;beards getting it done&#8221; or consulting for Ross Jeffries on seduction tactics for Southern girls (write her a sweet song and call her pretty. Duh.), the notoriously hirsute brothers in their modest &#8220;aw, shucks&#8221; manner released a sequel to 2006&#8217;s EP of low-key acoustic ruminations, <i>The Gleam</i>.</p>
<p>In a recent interview, Scott Avett remarked on how he will likely look back most fondly on these changing times in their career. Whether prescient or precocious, <i>The Second Gleam</i> EP reflects this notion.</p>
<p>Forgoing the assistance of bassist Bob Crawford and touring cellist Joe Kwon, Scott and brother Seth use their last recording for the Ramseur label to introduce six tender melodies (eight on vinyl) to whet the appetite of longtime fans. Beginning with opening track, &#8220;Tear Down the House,&#8221; <i>The Second Gleam</i> is the most serious affair of the Avetts&#8217; catalogue and seems to portend the gravity of the emotions felt about their future. The song cycle of quiet reflections is redolent with hushed picking that intimates the ambivalence and guarded optimism about their changing personas and reconciles their fears with vulnerable affirmations of love and truth.</p>
<p>Scott&#8217;s &#8220;Murdered in the City&#8221;, a concert staple, is underscored with light piano flourishes that enhance the song&#8217;s allegory, the sworn bonds of family and honor. Seth&#8217;s &#8220;Bella Donna,&#8221; intimate and rarely performed live, begs the wistful contemplation of a lover&#8217;s feelings and sets the tone for the responding &#8220;The Greatest Sum,&#8221; a homespun soliloquy of destiny and devotion. &#8220;St. Joseph&#8217;s,&#8221; with its staggered chorus, sings a nostalgic praise of a relationship weathering sickness and health, while &#8220;Souls Like the Wheels&#8221; sews up the earnest theme of love and understanding as the touchstones for growth and humility in an unpredictable world.</p>
<p>Absent the anachronistic instrumentation, flair, and theatrical hallmarks of the Avett brand, <i>The Second Gleam</i> won&#8217;t quite grab new listeners by the hair so much as their live show does, but it proves that at this point the prolific Avett Brothers are on a creative roll, churning out beautifully crafted tunes seemingly effortlessly. And add to that the fact that Rick Rubin has been known to polish a turd or two in the studio over the years, so imagine what he could do with nuggets like these. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Hold Steady, Boys And Girls In America (Vagrant)</title>
		<link>./../../../../2006/11/29/the-hold-steady-boys-and-girls-in-america-vagrant/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2006 15:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2006/11/29/the-hold-steady-boys-and-girls-in-america-vagrant/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Hold Steady Boys And Girls In America Vagrant By: Eric Greenwood Lyrics can often make or break a band. Even an otherwise rocking song can be destroyed by a few clumsy clichés. And since most bands have jumped right into emo&#039;s pandering, self-pitying cesspool of over-used lamentations, it&#039;s refreshing to listen to a band [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="old_review_heads"> <span class="old_review_header_artist">The Hold Steady</span><br /> <span class="old_review_header_album">Boys And Girls In America</span><br /> <span class="old_review_header_label">Vagrant</span><br /> <span class="old_review_header_writer">By: Eric Greenwood</span></div>
<p>Lyrics can often make or break a band. Even an otherwise rocking song can be destroyed by a few clumsy clichés. And since most bands have jumped right into emo&#039;s pandering, self-pitying cesspool of over-used lamentations, it&#039;s refreshing to listen to a band whose lyrics eschew all of that sensitive dreck in favor of the drunken ramblings of a music-obsessed fanboy. It&#039;s Craig Finn&#039;s conversational wordplay and observational deconstruction that keeps The Hold Steady from sounding like heartland music for rednecks.</p>
<p>Finn&#039;s not much of a singer. He&#039;s mostly a talker with little to no regard for traditional meter or orthodox phrasing, but he makes it work with his bizarrely nagging and persistent flow. If you closed your eyes and could block out Finn&#039;s stream of conscious brain scrambles, you&#039;d swear you were listening to a Bob Segar &#034;Like a Rock&#034; commercial. Ok, maybe not quite that extreme, but The Hold Steady&#039;s music certainly mixes generic bar rock with pop punk flair, like Bruce Springsteen channeling The Replacements. And I swear I can hear some Bruce Hornsby thrown in there, too. I realize that this seems like the worst amalgamation of sounds imaginable, but Finn&#039;s dense stories unfurl out of your speakers so quickly, you can&#039;t help but need another take.  </p>
<p>Finn&#039;s delivery is sloppy yet distinct, and it sounds completely off the cuff, often evoking Shane MacGowan&#039;s guttural rants, only twice as literate. Finn looks like a bloated Buddy Holly, and he speaks his mind so effortlessly and effectively. This is music utterly devoid of pretension, and by the same turn it makes so many bands look silly for trying to be so weird. It&#039;s not going to blow away any music theory geeks with its tinkering piano, power chords, and predictable changes, but that is because this music succeeds on a different level. It&#039;s gutsy and honest and hard to swallow, and every time I listen to **Boys and Girls in America**, I am blown away by its lyrical daring.</p>
<p>Admittedly, it took me more listens then I typically have the patience to allow not only to get into The Hold Steady but just to get it at all. Something kept me coming back- a curiosity I couldn&#039;t quite figure out. The band&#039;s second record, **Separation Sunday** was my introduction. I was instantly put off by Finn&#039;s ragged voice, incessantly firing idiomatic narratives as though he were catching his last breath, but so many lines intrigued me enough to keep trying. I&#039;m still not even sure if I like the music, but I&#039;m positive Finn&#039;s a lyrical genius. And that&#039;s more than I could say for some of my favorite bands.</p>
<p>Quoting lyrics often falls flat, unless you can quote a full verse or even an entire song. But Finn tosses off so many golden one-liners, he&#039;s almost daring you not to write them down: &#034;She was a really cool kisser and she wasn&#8217;t all that strict of a Christian&#034; (&#034;Stuck Between Stations&#034;). &#034;How am I supposed to know that you&#8217;re high if you won&#039;t let me touch you?&#034; (&#034;Chips Ahoy!&#034;). &#034;We started recreational. It ended kinda medical. It came on hot and soft and then it tightened up its tentacles&#034; (&#034;Hot Soft Light&#034;). &#034;I feel Jesus in the clumsiness of young and awkward lovers. I feel Judas in the long odds of the rackets on the corners. I feel Jesus in the tenderness of honest nervous lovers. I feel Judas in the pistols and the pagers that come with all the powders&#034; (&#034;Citrus&#034;). It&#039;s endless. Finn&#039;s lyrical acumen knows no bounds.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lily Allen, Alright, Still (Regal)</title>
		<link>./../../../../2006/11/29/lily-allen-alright-still-regal/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2006 15:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2006/11/29/lily-allen-alright-still-regal/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lily Allen Alright, Still Regal By: Eric Greenwood I was a fan of Lily Allen&#039;s long before I even heard a note of her music. Her reputation for trashing her peers and calling bullshit on the hypocrisy of the rock star lifestyle preceded her. On Pete Doherty: &#034;I do think he needs to be exterminated.&#034; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="old_review_heads"> <span class="old_review_header_artist">Lily Allen</span><br /> <span class="old_review_header_album">Alright, Still</span><br /> <span class="old_review_header_label">Regal</span><br /> <span class="old_review_header_writer">By: Eric Greenwood</span></div>
<p>I was a fan of Lily Allen&#039;s long before I even heard a note of her music. Her reputation for trashing her peers and calling bullshit on the hypocrisy of the rock star lifestyle preceded her. On Pete Doherty: &#034;I do think he needs to be exterminated.&#034; On Madonna: &#034;She might have meant something once, but I don&#8217;t know anyone my age who cares.&#034; She can mouth off because she has the musical prowess to get away with it.  And she&#039;s ridiculously cute.</p>
<p>Allen may be the daughter of a famous comedian (Keith Allen), but she feels no sense of entitlement for success of any kind. Her street-level wit and unforgiving observational skills pepper her eclectic music with a strange mix of worldly authenticity and girlish charm. I approached her album with trepidation, though, because I didn&#039;t want to be let down.</p>
<p>Just like every other aspiring musician on the planet, Allen started a Myspace page, which unpredictably catapulted her to stardom in England in late 2005. Posting her demos and blogs filled with biting rants started a frenzy of friend requests, and, although she says her record deal happened prior to her Myspace phenomenon, her success has been married to it ever since.</p>
<p>I bought her album based solely on her trash-talking skills. I knew going in that it was pop music, but I figured she must do something right to be able to call out the crap so consistently. And she does. Her voice is infectiously charming. Her thick British accent wraps around each syllable so effortlessly. She sounds like a female version of The Streets, except that she can sing as well as rap. It&#039;s ironic that such acerbic wit comes with such a little-girl voice. </p>
<p>The production couldn&#039;t be more saccharine, but what sets Allen apart from the dregs of auto-tuned pop is her knack for lyrical revenge, which she floats over sunny choruses, ska-tinged pop, and street-beat grime. It&#039;s endlessly entertaining to listen to such an effortlessly charismatic girl talk so much smack, while making it so catchy you can&#039;t stop thinking about it. 		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Slits, Return Of The Giant Slits!: History And Conversation (Saf)</title>
		<link>./../../../../2006/11/08/the-slits-return-of-the-giant-slits-history-and-conversation-saf/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 21:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2006/11/08/the-slits-return-of-the-giant-slits-history-and-conversation-saf/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Slits Return Of The Giant Slits!: History And Conversation Saf By: Eric Greenwood As much as I hate the idea of reunions, I must admit I can&#039;t resist certain regroupings. It&#039;s just as easily a case of morbid curiosity as it is genuine excitement that forces me to go see bands decades past their [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="old_review_heads"> <span class="old_review_header_artist">The Slits</span><br /> <span class="old_review_header_album">Return Of The Giant Slits!: History And Conversation</span><br /> <span class="old_review_header_label">Saf</span><br /> <span class="old_review_header_writer">By: Eric Greenwood</span></div>
<p>As much as I hate the idea of reunions, I must admit I can&#039;t resist certain regroupings. It&#039;s just as easily a case of morbid curiosity as it is genuine excitement that forces me to go see bands decades past their prime on the off chance that somehow they will recapture what once made them great. Barring the rare exception (like Mission of Burma), it&#039;s typically a letdown. Being an art form inextricably bound to the recklessness of youth, punk rock doesn&#039;t age well.</p>
<p>We last heard from The Slits in 1981. With only two albums to its name, The Slits gained notoriety for two reasons: it was the first all-female punk band; and it opened for The Clash on its 1977 European tour. When the original four Slits started playing together, musical prowess was obviously not high on the list. But this group took the DIY aesthetic to a new level of incompetence. By today&#039;s standards The Slits&#039; early bootleg recordings sound horribly generic and uninteresting. Luckily, the band waited several years before cutting its first record with veteran reggae producer Dennis Bovell.</p>
<p>Bovell cracked The Slit&#039;s world wide open with his sound effects, oddly syncopated rhythms, and fascination with dub beats. And by 1979 The Slits had carved an unique niche out of its early punk ramblings on its debut, Cut. Vocalist Ari Up&#039;s sputtering melodies mingled well with the dub effects and stilted rhythms to form a sound that no other post-punk band could claim. To this day the music sounds spooky, assertive, and subversive. How these proudly non-musical instrumentalists transformed into envelope-pushing idea-makers is still a mystery, but Cut remains one of the most important post-punk records ever recorded.</p>
<p>Delving even deeper into world beats and ethnic verisimilitude, Return of the Giant Slits marked an even more extreme sense of ambitiousness. At this point in 1981, The Slits showed little to no interest in any adherence to the Puritanism of punk, instead opting for the destruction of pre-conceived notions of punk&#039;s boundaries and women&#039;s place in music. </p>
<p>Such extremism was eventually the band&#039;s undoing, and, ironically, The Slits lived up to punk&#039;s inevitable, self-fulfilling implosion, disbanding before the year&#039;s end. Up joined the avant-pop New Age Steppers before disappearing to Jamaica.</p>
<p>I recently spoke with The Slits en masse and newly reunited on speakerphone, as they were traveling to a show during their first week of touring in twenty-five years. It was a difficult interview to say the least- not because the band wasn&#039;t eager to talk (it was). But all of them would speak at once, their accents thick and rough. I quickly learned my questions were far too wordy and detailed for such a jovial, haphazard interview, so I tried to simplify them on the spot.</p>
<p>I started off with the obvious in what prompted The Slits&#039; reformation after so many years, to which they snarkily replied, &#034;Cuz we missed each other so much.&#034; Clearly. When I pressed for a more substantive answer, I managed to get them to eke out &#034;we have unfinished business.&#034; Fair enough. Up claims she never left music at all, even though she left the public eye. She says she &#034;didn&#039;t want to know about European existence anymore&#034;, thus the move to Jamaica, where she &#034;lived in music every day.&#034;</p>
<p>I tried to explore the first women in punk angle, but they weren&#039;t taking the bait, although they did say that, if anything, The Slits &#034;gave girls an alternative to standing in the audience.&#034; I brought up the band&#039;s legacy, asking if there were any bands in which the influence of The Slits were audible, which prompted the most emphatic response of the interview, &#034;THERE HAS NEVER BEEN A BAND LIKE THE SLITS AND THERE NEVER WILL BE!&#034;</p>
<p>And with that, you should probably do whatever you can to see them live because, even though it&#039;s a silly, cop-out answer, there&#039;s a kernel of truth to it.  2006 tour dates:       </p>
<p>Wed	11/08/06        Atlanta, GA 		Drunken Unicorn   <br />Thu	11/09/06  	Birmingham, AL 	        Bottletree   <br />Fri	11/10/06  	Baton Rouge, LA 	Spanish Moon    <br />Sat	11/11/06  	Austin, TX 		Emo&#8217;s Austin    <br />Tue	11/14/06  	Tucson, AZ 		Club Congress    <br />Thu	11/16/06  	San Diego, CA 	        The Casbah    <br />Fri	11/17/06  	West Hollywood, CA      The Troubadour    <br />Sat	11/18/06  	San Francisco, CA 	Mezzanine    <br />Sun	11/19/06  	Oakland, CA 		Uptown Night Club    <br />Tue	11/21/06  	Portland, OR 		Dante&#8217;s    <br />Wed	11/22/06  	Seattle, WA 		El Corazon   <br />Sun	11/26/06  	Chicago, IL 		Logan Square  		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Mars Volta, Amputechture (GSL/Universal)</title>
		<link>./../../../../2006/11/08/the-mars-volta-amputechture-gsluniversal/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 20:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2006/11/08/the-mars-volta-amputechture-gsluniversal/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Mars Volta Amputechture GSL/Universal By: Eric Greenwood Despite its post-punk pedigree, it&#039;s hard to imagine The Mars Volta sharing many fans with today&#039;s typical indie kid. You know the type cuddled up with his Sufjan Stevens records, wearing a nondescript striped sweater, faux frames, and spotty facial hair. That kid hates The Mars Volta [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="old_review_heads"> <span class="old_review_header_artist">The Mars Volta</span><br /> <span class="old_review_header_album">Amputechture</span><br /> <span class="old_review_header_label">GSL/Universal</span><br /> <span class="old_review_header_writer">By: Eric Greenwood</span></div>
<p>Despite its post-punk pedigree, it&#039;s hard to imagine The Mars Volta sharing many fans with today&#039;s typical indie kid. You know the type cuddled up with his Sufjan Stevens records, wearing a nondescript striped sweater, faux frames, and spotty facial hair. That kid hates The Mars Volta and all of its pretentious, prog-rock ambitions. </p>
<p>The Mars Volta appeals more to that guy who defends Faith No More because Mike Patton was in it, declaring Patton&#039;s ability to turn scatological humor into experimental nightmares without using anything but his voice exempts him from judgment for his embarrassing rap-funk beginnings. And because he was in Bungle, dude.  Yeah, that guy worships The Mars Volta.</p>
<p>If you don&#039;t fall into either ridiculously narrow or caricatured camp, that doesn&#039;t mean you&#039;re out of the loop. It&#039;s just one way of demonstrating how polarizing The Mars Volta&#039;s music is. Not too many people are on the fence- you either love this stuff or you hate it. </p>
<p>I&#039;ll admit to being intrigued to the point of being impressed by the band&#039;s debut, the Tremulant EP, and even most of De-Loused in the Comatorium for its pummeling fits of Led Zeppelin progged-out in space. The Santana-style solos were forgivable because they were far outnumbered by hooks and impossibly technical aggression. The same can&#039;t be said for Frances The Mute, a sprawling, stream of conscious set of heavy-lidded space rock, world-fusion eccentricity, and jazzy discombobulation.</p>
<p>The band&#039;s third full length, Amputechture, continues on a fans-be-damned journey to the center of nonsense, with layers upon layers of harmonized, processed vocals, scaling guitar wankery, and lush, atmospheric passages interrupted by extreme jolts of pistol-fire percussion. Cedric Bixler-Zavala&#039;s voice can knock you on your ass just as easily as Omar Rodriguez-Lopez&#039;s solos can numb your face.</p>
<p>Musically, it&#039;s mind-blowing in both execution and creativity, but it&#039;s a masturbatory nightmare to sit through in one listen.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
