<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Duran Duran flub tour opener in New Zealand	</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 23:40:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Bridget		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-1179</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bridget]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 23:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2008/03/27/duran-duran-flub-tour-opener-in-new-zealand/#comment-1179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Im still surprised that such a non-event has spread across the world...yes, the band had a couple of technical issues, Nick&#039;s laptop crashed halfway through the set, and he had to reboot it - thats technology for you.  And as for John storming off the stage - what a fallacy.  I was second row at the performance and John was all smiles the whole time - is a little humour lost on the masses these days?????  It was the first date of their world tour; there were bound to be some minor glitches, and Simon has siad that they didn&#039;t have quite enough rehersal time - but it frustrates me that a performance that was FANTASTIC to say the least has been torn to shreds.  Red Carpet Massacre is in it&#039;s element live, and anyone trying to create a scandal out of last week&#039;s performance in Auckland should seriously consider getting a life.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Im still surprised that such a non-event has spread across the world&#8230;yes, the band had a couple of technical issues, Nick&#8217;s laptop crashed halfway through the set, and he had to reboot it &#8211; thats technology for you.  And as for John storming off the stage &#8211; what a fallacy.  I was second row at the performance and John was all smiles the whole time &#8211; is a little humour lost on the masses these days?????  It was the first date of their world tour; there were bound to be some minor glitches, and Simon has siad that they didn&#8217;t have quite enough rehersal time &#8211; but it frustrates me that a performance that was FANTASTIC to say the least has been torn to shreds.  Red Carpet Massacre is in it&#8217;s element live, and anyone trying to create a scandal out of last week&#8217;s performance in Auckland should seriously consider getting a life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Kate		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-1178</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 21:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2008/03/27/duran-duran-flub-tour-opener-in-new-zealand/#comment-1178</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Although John had a point that the band was screwing up, I think it was pretty immature for him to walk off stage like that.   Simon had an off-day...so be it.   Unfortunately it was  at the opening of their tour.  There is way too much publicity on this one...Duran Duran will always be my favorite band regardless of whether a few lyrics or forgotten or not.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Although John had a point that the band was screwing up, I think it was pretty immature for him to walk off stage like that.   Simon had an off-day&#8230;so be it.   Unfortunately it was  at the opening of their tour.  There is way too much publicity on this one&#8230;Duran Duran will always be my favorite band regardless of whether a few lyrics or forgotten or not.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: eduardo		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-1177</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eduardo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 20:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2008/03/27/duran-duran-flub-tour-opener-in-new-zealand/#comment-1177</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The electro set of they, it is one of better that I have seen and if it is a high point in the show, and it is dance ... I do not deal because John Taylor has to call the attention publicly and leave the  stage;  If in 90s they did totally acoustic and not dance concerts that they all did not like,  and missing this electronic, experimental sound without limits with which DD became an acquaintance, because now John Taylor bothers....  

Well DD is the best band of all times, and Red Carpet Masacre one of the best albumes to that I have listened 

Simon  forget of the letter it is a proof that he really sings and does not do playbacks jajajajajajaja but the next time that one reminds of everything]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The electro set of they, it is one of better that I have seen and if it is a high point in the show, and it is dance &#8230; I do not deal because John Taylor has to call the attention publicly and leave the  stage;  If in 90s they did totally acoustic and not dance concerts that they all did not like,  and missing this electronic, experimental sound without limits with which DD became an acquaintance, because now John Taylor bothers&#8230;.  </p>
<p>Well DD is the best band of all times, and Red Carpet Masacre one of the best albumes to that I have listened </p>
<p>Simon  forget of the letter it is a proof that he really sings and does not do playbacks jajajajajajaja but the next time that one reminds of everything</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
