<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>album-review &#8211; Drawer B</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 19:40:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>album-review &#8211; Drawer B</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>REVIEW: Prince, Originals (Warner Bros.)</title>
		<link>./../../../2019/06/28/review-prince-originals-warner-bros/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 18:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[album-review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jay Z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kenny Rogers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Martika]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Morris Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peggy McCreary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prince]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sheila E.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sinead O'Connor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Bangles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tidal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../wp/index.html?p=7786</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Prince’s estate has been a bit of a PR shambles since the star’s sudden death in April of 2016. The lack of any discernible will has led to a never-ending legal battle between Prince’s family and the banks appointed to care for the business dealings of the musician’s vast estate. Despite the financial squabbles, the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft"></figure></div>



<p style="text-align:left">Prince’s estate has been a bit of a PR shambles since the star’s sudden death in April of 2016. The lack of any discernible will has led to a never-ending legal battle between Prince’s family and the banks appointed to care for the business dealings of the musician’s vast estate. Despite the financial squabbles, the estate has managed to eke out a few posthumous releases that one would assume even hardcore fans have to admire. Sadly, this is unlikely since Prince’s elite hardcore fans are an admittedly miserable and impossible lot to please, complaining endlessly about any and everything to do with the man. These releases speak more to spreading the legacy to potential fans as well as to those who already identify as “fams”- the term Prince applied to his followers as he found “fan” (short for a fanatic) to be derisive. </p>



<span id="more-7786"></span>



<p>The deluxe edition of Prince’s star-making <em>Purple Rain</em>
soundtrack, released in June of 2017, pried open the door to the man’s storied
vault with a bonus disc of mostly pristine versions of tracks that some had
only read about &#8211; much less heard &#8211; and had long become the stuff of legend
(presumably, elite collectors collectively rolled their eyes and laughed). Exactly
one year later a long-bootlegged session of Prince alone at the piano (pre-<em>Purple
Rain</em>) working out material in an impromptu session received a deluxe
package, <em>Piano &amp; Microphone 1983</em>. With Prince’s birthday as the
release pattern launch date, the estate has returned in 2019 with <em>Originals</em>&#8211;
a collection of songs Prince wrote for other artists. </p>



<p>Fulfilling a contractual obligation with Jay Z’s Tidal streaming service, with whom Prince had entrusted his catalog for streaming purposes toward the end of his life, the estate and Jay Z have compiled a swath of tunes Prince wrote primarily for his female protegees. Despite a few outliers, the bulk of the material stems from the start of Prince’s imperial period (1981-1985), where he was writing and recording in an almost constant state of motion. It was such a frantic period of creative inertia that Prince’s <a href="https://pitchfork.com/thepitch/prince-engineer-peggy-mccreary-interview-originals/">idea of a birthday gift</a> to his beleaguered engineer, Peggy McCreary, was to spend the day in the studio and record a song for her. I’m pretty sure she just wanted to go to sleep, but she now owns a one-of-a-kind, unreleased Prince song. Not everyone can say that.</p>



<p>Hearing Prince’s voice instead of Morris Day’s on “Jungle
Love” is jarring at first. A lot of these songs were intended as guide vocals,
so a full-on radio-ready Prince is not always represented. And a song like
“Jungle Love” by The Time is so inextricably bound to the cultural fabric of
its time that hearing someone else sing it – even Prince &#8211; is hard to wrap your
head around. These issues don’t exist on lesser-known songs like Sheila E.’s
“Noon Rendevous,” which features a stunning, goose-bump-inducing vocal from
Prince. Or on the mind-blowing harmonic explosion of “Love… Thy Will Be Done,”
originally given to one-hit-wonder Martika. The demo version of “Manic Monday,”
which The Bangles turned into a smash hit in early 1986, is stripped to its
core and shows what a quality writer Prince was. It could have easily been
included on his psychedelic <em>Around The World In A Day</em> LP in 1985. Prince’s
recording schedule was so erratic during this period that his staff had to be
on call just to keep up with his muse. The music just flowed out of him.</p>



<p>Anyone well-versed in the deeper ends of Prince’s catalog
shouldn’t be too surprised that he wrote a song for country icon Kenny Rogers.
“You’re My Love” is a simple love song with a straightforward vocal melody as
its centerpiece. The way in which Prince sings it suggests that he was laying
down a blueprint for Rogers to follow exactly, which was typical of Prince’s
method. This is not how Prince would’ve sung it if he were to have meant it for
himself, however. Knowing how to meld your art to fit someone else’s aesthetic
requires a deep level of empathy and understanding. It’s a charming demo albeit
slightly rougher than some of the other songs on this collection.</p>



<p>Creating Sheila E.’s empowering persona was one of Prince’s
most successful side projects. Despite being a huge hit, the version of
“Glamorous Life” here is easier to digest with Prince’s voice because it’s more
in line with his androgynous vision at that time. Sheila E. even looked and
dressed like Prince during this era. With 10 of the 15 tracks written
specifically for women and engineered (mostly) by a woman, the overarching
theme of this compilation is female empowerment- or at least Prince’s version
of it, which leaned more towards sexual empowerment- a daring construct even in
the 1980s. There’s a mix of sexual bravado (“Sex Shooter”), sexual weirdness
(“Makeup”), elevating love over the material (“Glamorous Life”), and love
itself (“Love… Thy Will B Done”). And even though it was written and originally
given to Prince’s girlfriend’s band, The Family, “Nothing Compares 2 U” is pure
gut-wrenching heartbreak made internationally famous by another musically
pioneering woman, Sinead O’Connor.</p>



<p>Few artists have ever possessed the songwriting prowess and
depth that Prince demonstrated during this manic run in the 80s, and this
collection barely scratches the surface of the songs he gave away, much less
wrote for himself. Prince wanted to take over the world, and he wanted to do it
in lockstep with women leading the charge.&nbsp;
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>REVIEW: Fiona Apple, The Idler Wheel Is Wiser Than the Driver of the Screw and Whipping Cords Will Serve You More Than Ropes Will Ever Do (Epic)</title>
		<link>./../../../2012/12/05/review-fiona-apple-the-idler-wheel-is-wiser-than-the-driver-of-the-screw-and-whipping-cords-will-serve-you-more-than-ropes-will-ever-do-epic/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 20:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[album-review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiona Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maude Maggart]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=6910</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fiona Apple’s re-emergence every half decade or so is a triumphant celebration for a niche community of devotees and rather an apathetic shrug for the rest of America, which assumes (wrongly) that she’s just a Lilith Fair throwback, trying to claw her way back into the limelight. I belong to the former group, as my [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<a rel="attachment wp-att-6915" href="http://www.drawerb.com/2012/12/05/review-fiona-apple-the-idler-wheel-is-wiser-than-the-driver-of-the-screw-and-whipping-cords-will-serve-you-more-than-ropes-will-ever-do-epic/fiona-apple/"></a></p>
<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-6915" href="http://www.drawerb.com/2012/12/05/review-fiona-apple-the-idler-wheel-is-wiser-than-the-driver-of-the-screw-and-whipping-cords-will-serve-you-more-than-ropes-will-ever-do-epic/fiona-apple/"></a>Fiona Apple’s re-emergence every half decade or so is a triumphant celebration for a niche community of devotees and rather an apathetic shrug for the rest of America, which assumes (wrongly) that she’s just a Lilith Fair throwback, trying to claw her way back into the limelight. I belong to the former group, as my parenthetical aside betrays. Apple is a brilliant songwriter. I know this to be true. I just feel guilty enjoying her music as much as I do. She’s clearly unwell, both in heart and mind (no matter what she says on the chat shows), and this has never been more apparent than on her latest opus, the steely-eyed and daringly entitled <em>The Idler Wheel Is Wiser Than the Driver of the Screw and Whipping Cords Will Serve You More Than Ropes Will Ever Do</em>.</p>
<p>“Every Single Night” is a most bizarre album opener and even more confounding as a single. With its wild dynamic shifts from heart pounding chants to shaky whispers, Apple sounds not of sound mind. But it works on every level. The lyrics are obsessively reflective, of course, as Apple analyzes the tricks her brain plays on her night after night. She’s fixated on how the brain functions, and its impact on her many neuroses has infiltrated her perceptiveness as a songwriter. You simply can’t help but believe her when she whisper-sings, maniacally, “I just want to feel everything.” On “Daredevil” Apple concedes that she may indeed “need a chaperone” as she’s not to be left alone, but her melodies and vocal idiosyncrasies are so endearing that it’s easy to overlook the obvious pleas for help just to enjoy the song.</p>
<p><span id="more-6910"></span></p>
<p><em>The Idler Wheel</em>… is Apple’s most rhythmically dense album. Several songs spark from odd syncopations that effortlessly weave into minimal layers of piano, stilted percussion and Apple’s oddly nuanced delivery. Her piano refrains embed themselves into your subconscious before she even utters a word. But when the words do come, you can feel the songs slowly ensnare your emotions, too, until you’re trapped in her world, seeing things exactly as she sees them. It’s as frightening as it is moving. Apple’s rawness eschews judgment. The girl doesn’t give a damn what you think of her. She knows what she’s feeling, and she’s able to express it in myriad complicated ways.</p>
<p>Apple’s never been one to hold back- not on stage, not in interviews, and certainly not on record. For “Jonathan” Apple adopts one of her most frequented personae: that of spurned lover. The scorned woman in her has matured, however. Where once she would have raged she now eviscerates in subtle yet cutting ways. Her lyrics have never been better. To make such bitterness palpable yet musical is a talent few possess. On “Left Alone” her theme is simple: She wants to be loved but how can anyone love her and be close to her when all she wants is to be left alone? The Alanis Morrisettes of the world can’t conceive of that level of irony. And she lets loose of soul-mining, gut-wrenching insightfulness: “My ills are reticulate/my woes are granular/the ants weigh more than the elephants” before lurching into an operatic, bemoaning crescendo of the word “alone.” It’s staggeringly good.</p>
<p>The climax of the album &#8211; without question – is “Werewolf,” which very well might be Apple’s finest piece of songwriting to date. What sounds so simple is complicated by factors that aren’t necessarily obvious upon first listen. The lyrics are brutal and honest and hyperbolic. You know, normal Fiona Apple terrain. But her inflection is so universally empathetic and heart-rending that you can’t avoid being hypnotized by the simplicity of the verses, which she sings in a conversational, easy-going tone. The juxtaposition of the absurdity of the content versus the casual delivery is a bit of a mindfuck. The context, of course, is absurdly over the top, but she drifts into the world of meta in the non-sequitur coda/refrain: “There’s nothing wrong when a song ends in a minor key.” It’s more than just an infectious line. You can’t stop singing it to yourself once you’ve heard it. It has such a classic cadence that you can’t believe Elton John – or someone &#8211; hadn’t thought of it before now. It’s simply that good.</p>
<p>“Periphery” mines a familiar theme of love lost and squandered but with a new spirit of optimism engendered with true empathy and understanding. Apple’s lyrical incisiveness is what stands out, though: “Oh, the periphery/I lost another one there/he found a prettier girl than me/with a more even tempered air/and if he wants her, he should get her/cause I think she’s worth it.” Fiona Apple circa 1999 would never have said such things. She’s blowing off love lost? And even encouraging its culmination with another? What? The sadness in her voice is that of passive resignation. Even the vocal histrionics toward the end reveal an “oh well” sort of send-off. It’s a fine line between maturity and just not giving a shit anymore. But then the anger returns on “Regret”: “I ran out of white dove feathers/to soak up the hot piss that flows from your mouth/every time you address me.” Jesus. I would not want to be on the receiving end of that conversation.</p>
<p>“Anything We Want” is a shrewdly understated love song. It qualifies as quite jubilant for this record, though. It’s honest and open and nostalgic and imaginative but not in a sentimental way. There’s an air of dissonance that meanders through it – and the whole album, actually – that keeps you guessing. “Hot Knife” is vocal masterwork in the round, wherein she and her sister, Maude Maggart, play with exuberant harmonies, as though in a room of echoing infinity filled with nothing but voices. It’s a genre-bending tip of the hat to baroque pop’s past that showcases Apple’s respect for the sound of her own voice.  And, if the breathtaking brilliance of <em>The Idler Wheel</em>… proves anything, it’s that Apple knows she’s good, despite the fact that she may not be well.</p>
<p>&nbsp;		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>REVIEW: Cotton Candy, Top Notch &#038; First Rate, Teenbeat</title>
		<link>./../../../2010/06/24/review-cotton-candy-top-notch-first-rate-teenbeat/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2010 22:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[album-review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Air Miami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blast Off Country Style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cotton Candy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flin Flon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Robinson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teenbeat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unrest]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=5943</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Unrest disbanded at what I considered to be the height of its powers in 1994, my college radio-infused world was devastated. Unrest was my favorite band at the time, simply because its wildly erratic yet highly collectible records mimicked what I thought made college radio so interesting and intriguing and vital. The abrupt mood [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				When Unrest disbanded at what I considered to be the height of its powers in 1994, my college radio-infused world was devastated. Unrest was my favorite band at the time, simply because its wildly erratic yet highly collectible records mimicked what I thought made college radio so interesting and intriguing and vital. The abrupt mood shifts, random non-sequiturs, and brazen avant-silliness were all packaged in a DIY shell with a dark, sardonic undercurrent (and, of course, exquisite design). You couldn’t pin that band down. Granted, its final two albums veered sharply in a clean, clinical direction, but the sum of its years and dizzying musical styles were always at bay, especially in a live setting.</p>
<p><span id="more-5943"></span></p>
<p>Post-Unrest, Mark Robinson has become even more of an enigma. The man behind Teenbeat Records, Unrest, Air Miami, Flin Flon, and now Cotton Candy (just to name a few) has remained on the fringe of the musical underground for decades. With Unrest’s unwieldy trajectory, Robinson almost punctured that elusive commercial domain, but I always felt like the taste of the edge of success never sat well with him. And the subsequent solo albums and brief band dalliances pushed him further and further into very specific experimental realms.</p>
<p>And now with Cotton Candy, a duo featuring Blast Off Country Style’s Evelyn Hurley, Robinson has just barely cracked the door back open to the glistening pop world that Unrest dabbled with on those splendid final albums and singles. His affection for jangly pop has never been in question, nor has his ear for catchy, rhythmically dynamic yet unorthodox progressions. But Cotton Candy is heavier on ideas than it is songs. There are snippets of brilliance, as on the title track, which sounds like a sped up version of one of Unrest’s <em>Imperial</em>-era gems, but the album is cut with so many conceptual snippets of camp and fodder that it feels like Robinson is trying to keep his audience at arm’s length.</p>
<p><em>Top Notch &amp; First Rate</em> does little to unravel the mystery behind Robinson’s musical motives, but it’s a cleverly executed record full of self-referential minutiae and pop culture satire with glimpses of his pop genius. When Robinson melds the schtick with substance as on album-highlight “Hot Wieners (All the Way)”, Cotton Candy’s place in the musical pantheon makes more sense. If only <em>Top Notch &amp; First Rate</em> balanced the artful diversions with more of the hook-laden pop, then Cotton Candy might amount to more than beautifully packaged and brilliantly presented fluff.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>REVIEW: SLED, S/T, Lunchbox</title>
		<link>./../../../2010/04/02/review-sled-st-lunchbox/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2010 14:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[album-review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Assfactor 4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Columbia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SLED]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=5820</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s true that most bands rock less as they age. The few that go against the grain remain rare exceptions. Specifically, hardcore bands tend to blow up long before they can go limp. Such was the case with Assfactor 4. The legendary South Carolina quartet called it quits at the height of its powers in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<a href="http://www.drawerb.com/wp/media/2010/04/sledfinalfront2.jpg"></a>It’s true that most bands rock less as they age. The few that go against the grain remain rare exceptions. Specifically, hardcore bands tend to blow up long before they can go limp. Such was the case with Assfactor 4. The legendary South Carolina quartet called it quits at the height of its powers in 1997, despite its second LP, <em>Sports</em>, not being released until 2000. That posthumous release has managed to keep the rumors alive that the band would get back together in some form for a decade.</p>
<p><span id="more-5820"></span>Enter SLED. Featuring one-half of Assfactor 4, SLED is a trio from Columbia, South Carolina, which certainly takes its foundational cues from a 90’s hardcore aesthetic. The tempo is less frantic than Assfacor 4’s frenzied stampede, but the urgency is just as extreme. The overall impact is more brutal, as the guitars have a thick, punk-metal crunch to them, but most of the credit goes to the fact that production values have improved so much since those early 90’s hardcore 7”s.</p>
<p>SLED leaves little to the imagination in terms of temperament. This is angry, hateful music on the surface, but, like Assfactor 4, there’s a tongue-in-cheek facet that might escape casual listeners. These guys have outgrown the humor that stemmed from the inside jokes of the punk-zine community that helped shape the hardcore scene long before the world of blogs, but there’s still a decidedly piss-taking slant evident in the lyrics and in song-titles like &#8220;Metal Boy Band.&#8221;</p>
<p>With all three members contributing to vocals, the screaming takes on varying degrees of rage, but it’s all likely to peel the paint off your walls. The bitterness and anger that punctuate barn-burners like “Blood &amp; Portence” and “Corpse” are almost overtaken by the searing cacophony of distortion and rage surging beneath them. This debut LP is unapologetically in your face and proves that SLED defies the mindset that age dictates how hard you can rock. These guys have kept it bottled up for far too long.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>REVIEW: The Avett Brothers, The Gleam II, Ramseur</title>
		<link>./../../../2008/09/22/review-the-avett-brothers-the-gleam-ii-ramseur/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[drew]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 20:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2008/09/22/review-the-avett-brothers-the-gleam-ii-ramseur/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What are a few country boys to do? Following their defining release, 2007&#8217;s Introducing: Emotionalism, Concord N.C.&#8217;s The Avett Brothers have enjoyed what most burgeoning bands would consider one hell of a year: National TV appearances, sold out shows in mid-sized venues across the U.S., a mention on Perez Hilton, and a move to the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://media.drawerb.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/media/2008/09/gleam.jpg"></a> What are a few country boys to do? Following their defining release, 2007&#8217;s <i>Introducing: Emotionalism</i>, Concord N.C.&#8217;s The Avett Brothers have enjoyed what most burgeoning bands would consider one hell of a year: National TV appearances, sold out shows in mid-sized venues across the U.S., a mention on Perez Hilton, and a move to the majors to record an album with Rick Rubin. With such widespread acclaim and a staggering tour schedule, the bucolic Avett boys, once considered a regional act at best, have precipitously found themselves perched on the cusp of national recognition.</p>
<p><span id="more-3419"></span> </p>
<p>So, in between all the hype and hullabaloo, how did they choose to position themselves for stardom? Rather than writing a primer with Rubin on &#8220;beards getting it done&#8221; or consulting for Ross Jeffries on seduction tactics for Southern girls (write her a sweet song and call her pretty. Duh.), the notoriously hirsute brothers in their modest &#8220;aw, shucks&#8221; manner released a sequel to 2006&#8217;s EP of low-key acoustic ruminations, <i>The Gleam</i>.</p>
<p>In a recent interview, Scott Avett remarked on how he will likely look back most fondly on these changing times in their career. Whether prescient or precocious, <i>The Second Gleam</i> EP reflects this notion.</p>
<p>Forgoing the assistance of bassist Bob Crawford and touring cellist Joe Kwon, Scott and brother Seth use their last recording for the Ramseur label to introduce six tender melodies (eight on vinyl) to whet the appetite of longtime fans. Beginning with opening track, &#8220;Tear Down the House,&#8221; <i>The Second Gleam</i> is the most serious affair of the Avetts&#8217; catalogue and seems to portend the gravity of the emotions felt about their future. The song cycle of quiet reflections is redolent with hushed picking that intimates the ambivalence and guarded optimism about their changing personas and reconciles their fears with vulnerable affirmations of love and truth.</p>
<p>Scott&#8217;s &#8220;Murdered in the City&#8221;, a concert staple, is underscored with light piano flourishes that enhance the song&#8217;s allegory, the sworn bonds of family and honor. Seth&#8217;s &#8220;Bella Donna,&#8221; intimate and rarely performed live, begs the wistful contemplation of a lover&#8217;s feelings and sets the tone for the responding &#8220;The Greatest Sum,&#8221; a homespun soliloquy of destiny and devotion. &#8220;St. Joseph&#8217;s,&#8221; with its staggered chorus, sings a nostalgic praise of a relationship weathering sickness and health, while &#8220;Souls Like the Wheels&#8221; sews up the earnest theme of love and understanding as the touchstones for growth and humility in an unpredictable world.</p>
<p>Absent the anachronistic instrumentation, flair, and theatrical hallmarks of the Avett brand, <i>The Second Gleam</i> won&#8217;t quite grab new listeners by the hair so much as their live show does, but it proves that at this point the prolific Avett Brothers are on a creative roll, churning out beautifully crafted tunes seemingly effortlessly. And add to that the fact that Rick Rubin has been known to polish a turd or two in the studio over the years, so imagine what he could do with nuggets like these. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>REVIEW: Anakrid, FeverDreamFever, Stereonucleosis</title>
		<link>./../../../2008/09/03/review-anakrid-feverdreamfever-stereonucleosis/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 21:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[album-review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anakrid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Bickel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Horror]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2008/09/03/review-anakrid-feverdreamfever-stereonucleosis/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Inarguably, Anakridâ€™s music is inherently uneasy on the ears, but that shouldnâ€™t completely scare you away, if youâ€™re ever even slightly intrigued by whatâ€™s behind the other, less welcoming door. Anakridâ€™s so-called â€œdifficultâ€ musical canvas is an acquired taste to be sure, but itâ€™s worth adjusting the tuning in your musical ear to appreciate the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://media.drawerb.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/media/2008/09/feverdreamfever.jpg"></a> Inarguably, Anakridâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s music is inherently uneasy on the ears, but that shouldnâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />t completely scare you away, if youâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />re ever even slightly intrigued by whatâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s behind the other, less welcoming door. Anakridâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s so-called â€œdifficultâ€ musical canvas is an acquired taste to be sure, but itâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s worth adjusting the tuning in your musical ear to appreciate the premeditated aural deconstruction that awaits.</p>
<p><span id="more-3346"></span> </p>
<p><i>FeverDreamFever</i> is Anakridâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s first LP of 2008; if youâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />ve been paying attention, thatâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s a grinding pace compared to last yearâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s flurry of limited selections, all of which were housed in fetishistic hand-made packaging. This one is a batch of only 200 released by Chris Bickelâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s own Stereonucleosis label. Returning to a drone-heavy atmosphere after the brutal <i>Pos Load: Nihilsurrealisme</i>, <i>FeverDreamFever</i> proffers a slightly less organic collage of sound delivered in pithy bursts of distant clanging wreckage, whereby electronic manipulation seems to have taken over Bickelâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s found-sound approach.  </p>
<p>If the first side of this LP doesnâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />t make you look under your bed before going to sleep, the second half will assure as much. The layered drone gives way to tribal percussion and an unforgiving malaise. This is the soundtrack to the dream that wakes you in a cold sweat. This is exquisitely stylish doom.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>REVIEW: Band of Horses, Cease to Begin, Sub Pop</title>
		<link>./../../../2007/12/30/review-band-of-horses-cease-to-begin-sub-pop/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2007 17:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[album-review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2007/12/30/review-band-of-horses-cease-to-begin-sub-pop/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On paper Band of Horses seems like it would be a hideously boring mess: mid-tempo rock drenched in gratuitous reverb all with more than a hint of twang. But Ben Bridwell&#8217;s idiosyncratic execution of such a simple formula catapulted his band to the upper echelon of Sub Pop&#8217;s prestigious roster, alongside The Shins and mentors [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://media.drawerb.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/2007/12/41xswbekz1l.-aa240-.jpg"></a> On paper Band of Horses seems like it would be a hideously boring mess: mid-tempo rock drenched in gratuitous reverb all with more than a hint of twang. But Ben Bridwell&#8217;s idiosyncratic execution of such a simple formula catapulted his band to the upper echelon of Sub Pop&#8217;s prestigious roster, alongside The Shins and mentors Iron &amp; Wine with its unassuming debut, <i>Everything All the Time</i>. Bridwell and former bandmate Mat Brooke took an earnest approach to indie rock, relying on unpretentious themes, laid-back performance, and sincere lyrics. The results surpassed any and all expectations, as the band found itself in extremely high demand from frat boys to unapproachable elitists thanks to its defining anthemic single, &#8220;The Funeral.&#8221;</p>
<p><span id="more-2668"></span></p>
<p>In a year when follow-up albums have underwhelmed and underperformed (Bloc Party, Clap Your Hands Say Yeah), Band of Horses has returned more focused than ever. The band&#8217;s en masse move cross country to South Carolina is barely audible, as <i>Cease to Begin</i> rarely strays far from its predecessor&#8217;s shimmering beauty. It certainly feels wiser and svelter, though. Bridwell not only knows how affecting the odd timbre of his voice can be, especially when he pushes the limits of his upper register, but he also knows how to manipulate a fairly simply constructed song to meet his desired intentions. His crystalline delivery and oddly syncopated phrasing emotes in a universally appealing way. </p>
<p>Bridwell&#8217;s songwriting is sharper and much more sophisticated here, though never showy or indulgent, and with the album clocking in at just under 35 minutes it never has a chance to be. &#8220;Is There A Ghost&#8221; kicks things off with a storming crescendo a la &#8220;The Funeral&#8217;s&#8221; grand strokes. It&#8217;s by far the most aggressive moment of the album, allowing the band to delve deeper into the more recessive aspects of its mercurial beauty. &#8220;No One&#8217;s Gonna Love You&#8221; and &#8220;Detlef Schrempf&#8221; showcase Bridwell&#8217;s growing balladeering prowess masterfully. Despite occasional lyrics that would be hard to muster with a straight face, Bridwell sounds genuinely heartfelt and honest. And that clear, clean tenor is nearly impossible to second-guess. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
