<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>commentary &#8211; Drawer B</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 13:56:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>commentary &#8211; Drawer B</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>REUNION: Ride</title>
		<link>./../../../2014/11/22/reunion-ride/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 13:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reunions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ride]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7630</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m always completely torn when a band I worship &#8211; or have worshiped &#8211; decides to reunite. Of course, there&#8217;s the selfish desire to relive the nostalgic emotions a certain record may have evoked during the formative teenage years. But then there&#8217;s the cynical desire to understand the invariably disappointing motivation, which always points to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<iframe width="420" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/9kfLJmqFl2U" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>I&#8217;m always completely torn when a band I worship &#8211; or have worshiped &#8211; decides to reunite. Of course, there&#8217;s the selfish desire to relive the nostalgic emotions a certain record may have evoked during the formative teenage years. But then there&#8217;s the cynical desire to understand the invariably disappointing motivation, which always points to the potential pile of cash. The Pixies have reduced the reunion act to its basest form: an obvious (and unending) play on fans&#8217; collective nostalgia followed by the dreaded yet inevitable failure of &#8220;new music.&#8221; When I read that <a href="http://www.spin.com/articles/ride-shoegaze-band-reunites-world-tour/">Ride had decided to reunite</a>, I felt the usual dose of inner conflict. On the one hand, <em>Nowhere</em> was a seminal record for me. I immersed myself in it, obsessing over every note for months and basking in the wash of glorious shoegaze feedback its majestic wall of noise created. I can return to it any time and still feel the same rush- a rare feat for any album to sustain that sort of impact, especially outside of the context of being 17. A Ride poster adorned my freshman dorm room, much to the bewilderment of my TLC-loving roommate. But decades have passed. I used to think rock n roll was a decidedly youthful endeavor. But, as I age, I am less strict in my cut off points for what is &#8220;too old&#8221; for rock n roll. Obviously, part of it stems from my reticence to accept my own age and relative stage in life. I used to be appalled by the fact that The Rolling Stones existed a day past 1975. Now, I find myself starting to justify their longevity, despite the obvious cash cow their &#8220;brand&#8221; generates. I once heard a guy say, &#8220;there&#8217;s nothing sadder than an old punk.&#8221; I get that. And my 19-year-old self would completely agree. I probably still agree. Certain genres do have a lifespan that has a definite expiration date. But being so cut and dry is probably missing the point. I&#8217;ve seen plenty of reunited bands over the years. Some lived up to the idealized potential while others were beyond embarrassing. If you can still pull it off without compromising the integrity of the music, I don&#8217;t see why you can&#8217;t forge on. But then the thought of watching a bunch of haggard ass has-beens trying to act like they&#8217;re 25 sounds like hell on Earth. Nostalgia and curiosity almost always win. So, I&#8217;m definitely erring on the side of excitement at the thought of Ride existing in any form in 2015. It&#8217;s just not without a healthy dose of trepidation.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nirvana&#8217;s Going to the Rock &#038; Roll Hall of Fame — Without Chad Channing</title>
		<link>./../../../2014/03/19/nirvanas-going-to-the-rock-roll-hall-of-fame-without-chad-channing/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pat]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 17:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[controversy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s one big sticking for eligibility for induction into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame (outside of that whole, y&#8217;know, being good and important thing). As in baseball, it&#8217;s all about time: To qualify for induction into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame, there must be a passing of 25 years since the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<a href="http://media.drawerb.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp/media/2014/03/Nirvana1.png"></a></p>
<p>There&#8217;s one big sticking for eligibility for induction into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame (outside of that whole, y&#8217;know, being <em>good</em> and <em>import</em><em>ant</em> thing). As in baseball, it&#8217;s all about time: To qualify for induction into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame, there must be a passing of 25 years since the band&#8217;s first release.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s been exactly 25 years since Nirvana released <em>Bleach</em>, and if there are few first-ballot decisions as no-brainer as Kurt Cobain, Krist Novoselic and Dave Grohl.</p>
<p>But Grohl didn&#8217;t play on <em>Bleach</em>. Chad Channing did. (He&#8217;s the guy on the far right in the above picture.)</p>
<p>But Chad Channing isn&#8217;t getting inducted into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame. Worse, he found out via text message.</p>
<p>&#8220;Can you tell whoever looks after Chad Channing that he isn’t being inducted,&#8221; the Rock Hall wrote to Nirvana&#8217;s manager, reports radio.com. &#8220;It is just Dave, Krist and Kurt.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cold. Blooded.</p>
<p>&#8220;I’ll be there at the table ready to walk up,&#8221; Channing told the site in an earlier interview about Nirvana&#8217;s imminent induction. &#8220;When I told my daughter about the induction, she was super excited for me! So much of my excitement about it is for her!&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>COLD. BLOODED.</strong> I haven&#8217;t been this upset about a Hall of Fame snub since Tim &#8220;Rock&#8221; Raines.</p>
<p>(Then again, if the Hall inducts Chad Channing, shouldn&#8217;t it induct Dale Crover, who played on <em>Bleach</em>&#8216;s &#8220;Floyd the Barber&#8221;, &#8220;Paper Cuts&#8221; and &#8220;Downer&#8221;? Then again, isn&#8217;t the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame kind of stupid to begin with?)</p>
<p>The Hall of Fame induction ceremony is April 10 at the Barclays Center in Brooklyn.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alex Turner&#8217;s Mic-dropping Brit Awards Speech</title>
		<link>./../../../2014/02/23/alex-turners-mic-dropping-brit-award-speech/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 14:53:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gossip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alex Turner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arctic Monkeys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brit Awards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peaches Geldof]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7492</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Arctic Monkeys racked up again at the Brit Awards this year, taking home Best British Group for the fourth time and its well-deserved third Best British Album for AM. Lead singer Alex Turner used the occasion to drop an irony-laced speech that was a winking piss-take on the &#8220;state&#8221; of rock &#8216;n roll. Reactions have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/9ZzJtxrGmtQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Arctic Monkeys racked up again at the Brit Awards this year, taking home Best British Group for the fourth time and its well-deserved third Best British Album for <em>AM</em>. Lead singer Alex Turner used the occasion to drop an irony-laced speech that was a winking piss-take on the &#8220;state&#8221; of rock &#8216;n roll. Reactions have been hilariously all over the map. Peaches Geldof <a href="http://www.entertainmentwise.com/news/141571/Ungrateful-Tt-Peaches-Geldof-Blasts-Alex-Turner-Over-BRIT-Awards-Acceptance-Speech">called him</a> an &#8220;ungrateful twat,&#8221; but I dare say she didn&#8217;t pick up on any of Turner&#8217;s subversive humor. The <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/music/2014/feb/19/arctic-monkeys-win-british-album-of-the-year-2014-brits">comment section on this subject at The Guardian</a> is a goldmine.</p>
<p>Full transcript of Turner&#8217;s mic-dropping speech:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;That rock&#8217;n&#8217;roll, ay? That rock&#8217;n&#8217;roll, it just won&#8217;t go away. It might hibernate from time to time, sink back into the swamp. I think the cyclical nature of the universe in which it exists demands that it acquiesce to some of its rules. But it&#8217;s always waiting there, just around the corner, ready to make its way back through the sludge and smash through the glass ceiling, looking better than ever. Yeah, that rock&#8217;n&#8217;roll, it seems like it&#8217;s faded away sometimes, but it will never die. And there&#8217;s nothing you can do about it. Invoice me for the microphone if you need to.&#8221;   </p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Patrick Wall&#8217;s Top Albums of 2013</title>
		<link>./../../../2013/12/31/patrick-walls-top-albums-of-2013/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pat]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 23:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contentious list-making]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[link]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yearend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7378</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ABOUT THE AUTHOR: Patrick Wall is the man whose name you’d love to touch. But you mustn’t touch. People pay him to write things. KNEE MEETS JERK In Which a Beleaguered Music Journalist Attempts — and Fails — to Identify Ten Records Released Between December 2012 and December 2013 That Were Better Than All Other [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				ABOUT THE AUTHOR: Patrick Wall is the man whose name you’d love to touch. But you mustn’t touch. People pay him to write things.</p>
<p><strong>KNEE MEETS JERK</strong><br />
<em>In Which a Beleaguered Music Journalist Attempts — and Fails — to Identify Ten Records Released Between December 2012 and December 2013 That Were Better Than All Other Releases in the Same Time Period. Listed in alphabetical order. Results subject to change. In seven acts.<br />
</em></p>
<p><span id="more-7378"></span></p>
<p><strong>I. Perspicacity</strong><br />
<em>Or, Twenty-Three Records for Twelve Months<br />
</em><br />
<iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/119200180&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Action Bronson, <em>Blue Chips 2</em> (Atlantic/Vice)</strong><br />
The knock on Action Bronson is that he’s almost a Kenny Powers-ish caricature of Ghostface Killah, that he amplifies Tony Starks’ swagger, flow and gift for storytelling to cartoonish levels. I fail to see the problem with that: <em>Blue Chips 2</em> is freewheeling and fun, and over the 19 sprawling tracks, Bronsoliño’s got the mind of a fucking scientist.</p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2951209986/size=medium/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/t=5/transparent=true/" height="240" width="320" seamless=""></iframe><br />
<strong>Alpoko Don, <em>The Ol Soul</em> EP (Kidfire)</strong><br />
Randrickas Young is from Greenville, S.C. He started posting YouTube videos under the name Alpoko Don sometime last year, his fluid lyrical facility — buoyed by stories and jokes about the coke trade and paeans to the Almighty and Technicolor metaphors — laid naked with just his gruff voice over barely-there beats he makes by pounding his fists on tables and front-porch railings. It’s equal parts trap rap and field hollers. It’s amazing, and proves rap music’s inherent but oft-doubted musicality.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/110753864&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Daniel Bachman, <em>Jesus I’m a Sinner</em> (Tompkins Square)</strong><br />
What Colin Stetson is to the saxophone, Daniel Bachman is to the guitar. That is to say: He is of his tradition — in Bachman’s case, post-Takoma school American primitive guitar — but supersedes it, recalling Basho’s spiritual heft and Rose’s whirling-dervish dexterity while suprassing them. Bachman encompasses, and he eclipses.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/93549370&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Boards of Canada, <em>Tomorrow’s Harvest</em> (Warp)</strong><br />
The Earth is not a cold, dead place, but Boards of Canada makes it seem like one. <em>Tomorrow’s Harvest</em> implies in its title reap-what-we’ve-sown mortality; its disintegrating loops invoking dust storms and abandoned freeway gas stations and scorched landscapes and the Earth reclaiming itself anew. It is music for Thunderdone.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/59082643&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Brokeback, <em>Brokeback and the Black Rock</em> (Thrill Jockey)</strong><br />
Brokeback’s from Chicago — Tortoise’s Douglas McCombs leads the group, and his band features members of Windy City faves Pinebender and The Zincs — but its growling instrumental rock evokes the lonesome, crowded west. Drums roll like tumbleweeds. Guitars whip like desert winds. The reverb — oh, how there’s reverb! — sounds like echoes bouncing off canyon walls.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/97876126&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Richard Buckner, <em>Surrounded</em> (Merge)</strong><br />
I used to go to church once a year. Then, I started seeing Richard Buckner in concert about once a year. I’m happier now.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/90243751&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Chance the Rapper, <em>Acid Rap</em> (self-released)</strong><br />
Great rap is evocative of time and place: New York City in the early ’80s. Los Angeles in the early ’90s. Atlanta in the mid ’90s. New Orleans in the late ’90s. Memphis in 2003. Like Kendrick Lamar’s sprawling <em>good kid, M.A.A.D. City</em> (Compton, mid-late ’00s), Chance the Rapper’s <em>Acid Rap</em> (Chicago, 2013) stamps the emcee as one of the most astounding street-poet storytellers of this generation.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/93221623&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Deafheaven, <em>Sunbather</em> (Deathwish)</strong><br />
The album My Bloody Valentine should’ve made.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/117790792&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Chris Forsyth, <em>Solar Motel</em> (Paradise of Bachelors)</strong><br />
This is probably what the first few Television jam sessions were like, I’d imagine.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/playlists/5242117&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="450" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Steve Gunn, <em>Time Off</em> (Paradise of Bachelors)</strong><br />
Music for quittin’ time, for gettin’ outdoors and sittin’ on the porch and kickin’ off the shoes and crackin’ open a beer and watchin’ the sunset and shootin’ the shit and droppin’ the velar nasal and lettin’ time just kinda go by. (Side note: Between Gunn’s <em>Time Off</em>, Forsyth’s <em>Solar Motel</em> and Hiss Golden Messenger’s <em>Haw</em>, Paradise of Bachelors kind of killed it this year.)</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/107489426&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Tim Hecker, <em>Virgins</em> (Kranky)</strong><br />
Dark. Spectral. Haunting. Austere. Tense. Primal. Eerie. Forcefully so, like the sounds are alive, and trying to claw out of the speakers. You might be able to listen to this one with the lights off. I won’t.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/84281005&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Glenn Jones, <em>My Garden State</em> (Thrill Jockey)</strong><br />
My dad loves Harry Chapin. My dad loves Harry Chapin, he says, because his songs are stories, rich and vibrant and infinitesimally detailed. I love Glenn Jones for the same reason. Thing is, Jones’ songs tell stories without any words.</p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2549328916/size=medium/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/t=8/transparent=true/" height="240" width="320" seamless=""></iframe><br />
<strong>KEN Mode, <em>Entrench</em> (Season of Mist)</strong><br />
The best songs hit you the hardest.<br />
“Figure your life out,” KEN Mode’s Jesse Matthewson sneers on the song of the same name, from the Winnipeg noise-rock trio’s awesome, impassioned <em>Entrench</em>.<br />
I turned 31 this year. I sold my house. I quit my job. I passed up an opportunity to move to the West Coast. I moved, but stayed in the South — from a city in which I was eminently comfortable to one where I live but, as Travis Morrison once quipped, have never felt less at home.<br />
I watched my friends have more successful, more fulfilling years than I did. Some of my friends got married. Some of my friends had children. I put off learning to play the pedal steel guitar another year. I felt undeniable pangs of jealousy as I watched longtime friends in successful bands play on late-night television shows while I slummed and struggled in dive bars. I drank with friends on last nights in town, before they moved to find fulfillment in their work as I slowly lost gratification in mine. As friends and one-time objects of affection reinvented themselves in mind or body or spirit, I just got older, just felt sorry for myself.<br />
So, yeah, I got depressed in 2013. I stopped drinking, then started again. I stopped exercising. For five days a week for nearly six months, I drove 100 miles to work, then another 100 back. I gained 20 pounds.<br />
So, now, on the cusp of a new year, I’m about to be jobless, perhaps careerless, and without health insurance. And all I have to fall back on is a lousy liberal arts diploma, a few guitars, a couple amplifiers and nagging, gnawing, crippling doubt that maybe it’s too late, maybe I&#8217;m too old to start fresh.<br />
“Figure your life out,” Jesse Matthewson sneers. I’m trying, dude. I’m trying.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/125238333&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>The Necks, <em>Open</em> (Northern Spy)</strong><br />
Without fail, I always miscalculate the denouement of The Neck’s graceful, meditative Open. I always think it’s wrapping up, finally winding down its blissful, captivating calm. I always look at the time remaining, and I always see that there are at least 20 minutes remaining in the most subtle and musically sensitive 68 minutes of music released in 2013. I’m never so happy to make a mistake.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/102749319&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Oneohtrix Point Never, <em>R Plus Seven</em> (Warp)</strong><br />
When I was just out of college, before I started working in earnest, I house-sat for some friends of mine. They had a pool, and their stereo system ran cables to speakers on their back porch, meaning I could, ostensibly, listen to music in the pool. One night, I got really high, put on Nobukazu Takemura’s “Icefall” and floated for ten minutes. I want to do something similar with Oneohtrix Point Never’s R Plus Seven, particularly “Problem Areas,” except with DMT and a top-down shooter. (Aside: I’m pretty sure a lot of the instrument samples come from Mario Paint.)</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/102734786&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>William Onyeabor, <em>Who Is William Onyeabor?</em> (Luaka Bop)</strong><br />
Who is William Onyeabor? An elusive and obscure Nigerian funk musician who made a few records in the 1970s and 1980s. Who is William Onyeabor? A musician rediscovered by Luaka Bop, who reissued his impossible-to-find futuristic synth funk on its exemplary World Psychedelic Classics series. Who is William Onyeabor? A mysterious musician on par with Fela Kuti in terms of how and where they pushed funk and electro music. Who is William Onyeabor? A man finally getting his due.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/104273830&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Polvo, <em>Siberia</em> (Merge)</strong><br />
My favorite Polvo album, 1996’s <em>Exploded Drawing</em>, takes a long time to get started. “Fast Canoe” sputters at its outset, like an old lawnmower that needs a few good tugs to really get going — guitar lines stab and dart tentatively, drums tiptoe but don’t tighten. When it finally roars at about the minute-forty-five mark, its locks into a skull-crushing groove. My second-favorite Polvo record, this year’s <em>Siberia</em>, doesn’t wait — it throttles from the get-go, “Total Immersion” beginning seemingly in the throes of an epic jam session that finally got going. And it doesn’t let up.</p>
<p><iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=3226130328/size=medium/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/t=1/transparent=true/" height="240" width="320" seamless=""></iframe><br />
<strong>Puig Destroyer, <em>Puig Destroyer</em> / <em>Wait for Spring</em> EPs (The Ghost is Clear)</strong><br />
Why do I like Puig Destroyer, which writes grindcore songs about baseball, so much? Because I like grindcore and baseball. Because fuck you, that’s why. #STOPFUCKINGBUNTING #ONEMANFIVETOOLS</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/98706380&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Run the Jewels, <em>Run the Jewels</em> (Fool&#8217;s Gold)</strong><br />
El Producto sets the tone right off the bat: “Oh dear, what the fuck have we here? / These motherfuckers all thorn, no rose.” Run the Jewels, ten tracks of speaker-obliterating beats and razor sharp verses laced with searingly honest emotion and pitch-black humor, was supposed to be a one-off fuckaround for El-P and Killer Mike following a banner 2012 for both. But when everyone was sweating Kanye’s blown-out <em>Yeezus</em> and Drake’s tepid <em>Nothing Was the Same</em> this summer, Run the Jewels burst through brick walls like the Kool-Aid Man. While Ye and Drizzy were just unlikeable, Mike and El were downright villainous, downright merciless, went Darth Vader on the rap game, force-choking the shit out of sucker emcees. I find everyone else’s lack of faith disturbing.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/112635701&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Savages, <em>Silence Yourself</em> (Matador/Pop Noire)</strong><br />
Maybe this year really was a banner year for women in rock and rock-derived and rock-esque musics. Maybe it was just a banner year for thinkpieces about women in rock and rock-derived and rock-esque musics this year. Either way, women helmed some really great records (Torres’ <em>Torres</em>; Neko Case’s <em>The Worse Things Get…</em>; Beyonce’s <em>Beyonce</em>) and wrote some really great songs (Case’s “Man”; Janelle Monae’s “Q.U.E.E.N.”; Tegan and Sara’s “I Was a Fool) in 2013. But it all starts and ends with Savages, four nails-tough British women playing the best and darkest post-punk since Joy Division.</p>
<p><strong>Wayne Shorter, <em>Without a Net</em> (Blue Note)</strong><br />
Wayne Shorter is jazz’s greatest living saxophonist and improviser and, at 80 years old plays circles around the rest of the blue-chip crew assembled on the fertile <em>Without a Net</em>. Blue Note, nearly 30 years after its relaunch following a lengthy hiatus, remains one of the most essential jazz labels. You do the math.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/90031039&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>Speedy Ortiz, <em>Major Arcana</em> (Carpark)</strong><br />
RIYL: Stephen Malkmus, if he were a woman with an MFA in poetry, and she fronted Nirvana instead of Pavement.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/70385017&amp;color=ff6600&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true" height="166" width="100%" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
<strong>William Tyler, <em>Impossible Truth</em> (Merge)</strong><br />
It was a great and fashionable year for instrumental guitar music. Hell, I put three other instrumental guitar records on this list. But William Tyler’s <em>Impossible Truth</em> is the best because it’s the most nuanced. It’s a rangy record obsessed with open highways and desert heat, a nimble record that heaves big open sighs of drone and purring fingerpicking patterns, a spacious record that calls to mind Ennio Morricone and Daniel Lanois and Willie Nelson in equal measure. I’ve never seen the Grand Canyon, but I’ve seen William Tyler perform <em>Invisible Truth</em>. That’s good enough for me.</p>
<p><strong>II. Whimsy</strong><br />
<em>Or, Bonus Tracks!: 25 Great Songs From Albums Not on the Above List</em><br />
A$AP Rocky, “1 Train” feat. Kendrick Lamar, Joey Badass, Yelawolf, Danny Brown, Action Bronson and Big K.R.I.T.<br />
Big Sean, “Control” feat. Kendrick Lamar &amp; Jay Electronica<br />
Captain Murphy, “Between Villains” feat. Viktor Vaughn, Earl Sweatshirt, Thundercat<br />
Charles Bradley, “Changes”<br />
CFCF, “Forest at Night”<br />
Dads, “My Crass Patch”<br />
Haim, “The Wire”<br />
Earl Sweatshirt, “Chum”<br />
The Front Bottoms, “Twin Sized Mattress”<br />
Ghostface Killah, “Blood on the Cobblestone”<br />
Jason Isbell, “Live Oak”<br />
Juicy J, “One of Those Nights”<br />
Mystikal, “Hit Me”<br />
Pelican, “Immutable Dusk”<br />
Prince, “Breakfast Can Wait”<br />
Pusha T, “40 Acres”<br />
Robin Thicke, “Blurred Lines”<br />
Rich Homie Quan, “Type of Way”<br />
Schoolboy Q, “Collard Greens”<br />
Superchunk, “Me and You and Jackie Mittoo”<br />
Toro Y Moi, “Campo”<br />
Whores., “Cougars, Not Kittens”<br />
Bo White, “National Love and Other Tyrants”<br />
Yo La Tengo, “Ohm”</p>
<p><strong>III. Lamentation</strong><br />
<em>Or, Honorable Mentions and/or Apologies To</em><br />
A$AP Rocky, <em>LONG.LIVE.A$AP</em>; Califone, <em>Stitches</em>; Bill Callahan, <em>Dream River</em>; The Body, <em>Christs, Redeemers</em>; Charles Bradley, <em>Victim of Love</em>; CFCF, <em>Music for Objects</em> EP; Dads, <em>Pretty Good</em> EP; Earl Sweatshirt, <em>Doris</em>; Four Tet, <em>Beautiful Rewind</em>; Helado Negro, <em>Invisible Life</em>; Lonnie Holley, <em>Keeping a Record of It</em>; Hiss Golden Messenger, <em>Haw</em>; Jason Isbell, <em>Southeastern</em>; Keefe Jackson’s Likely So, <em>A Round Goal</em>; Kylesa, <em>Ultraviolet</em>; The Littlest Viking, <em>The Littlest Viking</em>; Low, <em>The Invisible Way</em>; Magnetic Flowers, <em>Old, Cold. Losing It.</em>; Mount Moriah, <em>Miracle Temple</em>; Mountains, <em>Centralia</em>; The National, <em>Trouble Will Find Me</em>; Owen, <em>L’Ami du Peuple</em>; Pelican, <em>Forever Becoming</em>; Phosphorescent, <em>Muchacho</em>; Pusha T, <em>My Name Is My Name</em>; Russian Circles, <em>Memorial</em>; Sigur Ros, <em>Kveikur</em>; Southern Femisphere, <em>Houses</em>; Colin Stetson, <em>New History Warfare Vol 3</em>; Superchunk, <em>I Hate Music</em>; Torres, <em>Torres</em>; Toro Y Moi, <em>Anything in Return</em>; Touche Amore, <em>Is Survived By</em>; Vattnet Viskar, <em>Sky Swallower</em>; Washed Out, <em>Paracosm</em>; Bo White, <em>Adornment</em>; Whores., <em>Clean</em>; Dustin Wong, <em>Mediation of Ecstatic Energy</em>; The World is a Beautiful Place and I Am No Longer Afraid to Die, <em>Whenever If Ever</em>; Yo La Tengo, <em>Fade</em></p>
<p><strong>IV. Purgation</strong><br />
<em>Or, Critically Acclaimed Records I Did Not Care For But Expected I Would or Thought I Might</em><br />
Action Bronson, <em>Saaab Stories</em>; Arcade Fire, <em>Reflektor</em>; Big Boi, <em>Vicious Lies and Dangerous Rumors</em>; David Bowie, <em>The Next Day</em>; CFCF, <em>Outside</em>; Lorde, <em>Pure Heroine</em>; The Men, <em>New Moon</em>; My Bloody Valentine, <em>mbv</em>; Rhye, <em>Woman</em>; Vampire Weekend, <em>Modern Vampires of the City</em>; Kurt Vile, <em>Walkin’ On a Pretty Daze</em>; Waxahatchee, <em>Cerulean Salt</em>; Kanye West, <em>Yeezus</em></p>
<p><strong>V. Quandary</strong><br />
<em> Or, Critically Acclaimed Records I Did Not Listen To Enough (Or, In Some Cases, At All) And I&#8217;m Still Unsure How Much I Like</em><br />
Burial, <em>Rival Dealer</em>; Chvrches, <em>The Bones of What You Believe</em>; Daft Punk, <em>Random Access Memories</em>; Death Grips, <em>Government Plates</em>; Disclosure, <em>Settle</em>; Arnold Dreyblatt &amp; Megafaun, <em>Appalachian Extinction</em>; Forest Swords, <em>Engravings</em>; Ben Goldberg, <em>Unfold Ordinary Mind</em>; John Grant, <em>Pale Green Ghosts</em>; Haim, <em>Days Are Gone</em>; Ka, <em>The Night’s Gambit</em>; The Knife, <em>Shaking the Habitual</em>; Laura Marling, <em>Once I Was an Eagle</em>; Matmos, <em>The Marriage of Two Minds</em>; Migos, <em>YRN</em>; Kacey Musgraves, <em>Same Trailer Different Park</em>; Pharmakon, <em>Abandon</em>; DJ Rashad, <em>I Don’t Give a Fuck</em></p>
<p><strong>VI. Catharsis</strong><br />
<em>Or, The Thirteen Best Live Sets I Saw in 2013</em><br />
Alpoko Don @ Lincoln Theatre, Raleigh, N.C. (Sept. 6)<br />
Richard Buckner @ The Pinhook, Durham, N.C. (Oct. 10)<br />
Code Orange Kids @ Foxfield Bar &amp; Grille, Columbia, S.C. (July 15)<br />
Steve Gunn @ Raleigh Little Theatre, Raleigh, N.C. (Sept. 7)<br />
Keefe Jackson Trio @ Dialect Design, Charlotte, N.C. (Oct. 29)<br />
<a title="Do You Know How to Waltz?" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zI5-MuV5NSo">Low @ Rock the Garden, Minneapolis, Minn. (June 17)</a><br />
The Littlest Viking @ Headhunters, Austin, Tex. (March 16)<br />
Sigur Rós @ Asheville Civic Center, Asheville, N.C. (Sept. 28)<br />
Taylor Swift @ Colonial Life Arena, Columbia, S.C. (March 20)<br />
William Tyler @ The Parish, Austin, Tex. (March 14)<br />
Ken Vandermark &amp; Tim Daisy @ The Hive at Busy Bee Café, Raleigh, N.C. (Sept. 5)<br />
Whores. @ New Brookland Tavern, Columbia, S.C. (Jan. 27)<br />
Dustin Wong @ Central Presbyterian Church, Austin, Tex. (March 16)</p>
<p><strong>VII. Vilification</strong><br />
<em>Or, The Year’s Biggest Disappointment</em><br />
<strong>Dismemberment Plan, <em>The Uncanney Valley</em></strong> <strong>(Partisan)</strong><br />
The Dismemberment Plan is my favorite band. The Dismemberment Plan that made <em>Uncanney Valley</em> is not The Dismemberment Plan.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The New Order Reunion Is a Joke without Peter Hook</title>
		<link>./../../../2011/11/11/the-new-order-reunion-is-a-joke-without-peter-hook/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2011/11/11/the-new-order-reunion-is-a-joke-without-peter-hook/index.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 20:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bernard Sumner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Order]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peter Hook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=6634</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Order reunited recently to help raise money for friend and video-producer Michael Shamberg, as he fights a debilitating illness. Well, some of New Order reunited. Bassist Peter Hook was sadly absent from the festivities. Not every band&#8217;s bassist is integral to its sound. Some bass players are, in fact, totally replaceable. However, Peter Hook [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				</p>
<p>New Order <a href="http://www.slicingupeyeballs.com/2011/10/17/new-order-brussels-setlist-video-reunion/">reunited</a> recently to help raise money for friend and video-producer Michael Shamberg, as he fights a debilitating illness. Well, some of New Order reunited. Bassist Peter Hook was sadly absent from the festivities. Not every band&#8217;s bassist is integral to its sound. Some bass players are, in fact, totally replaceable. However, Peter Hook is not one of them. Almost every New Order song has a distinct bassline and melodic lead composed by Peter Hook. His style is one of the building blocks that we associate with the post-punk sound. It&#8217;s no secret that in-fighting amidst New Order&#8217;s ranks has been an ongoing problem for decades. The hiatus between 1993&#8217;s <em>Republic</em> and 2001&#8217;s <em>Get Ready</em> was always blamed on the band members being sick of one another. But it wasn&#8217;t until the past few years that we were spectators to the public sparring between Hook and vocalist Bernard Sumner. Throughout the 80&#8217;s and 90&#8217;s New Order remained frustratingly enigmatic. Since reforming, however, the band has let its collective guard down. Nasty words have been exchanged. Infantile name calling. It&#8217;s all rather silly and easily dismissed until the remaining members decided to toy with its own legacy and reunite without Hook- a passive aggressive stunt on a mammoth scale. Hook has expressed both <a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/music/news/peter-hook-saddened-and-upset-at-new-order-reunion-news-20110909">disappointment</a> and <a href="http://www.nme.com/news/new-order/59121">frustration</a> at the news, jokingly stating that &#8220;NEW ORDER without PETER HOOK is like QUEEN without FREDDIE MERCURY, U2 without THE EDGE, SOOTY without SWEEP!&#8221; While those are hyperbolic examples, he&#8217;s not entirely wrong. New Order without Hook is a joke. A sad joke. Replacing him on stage with two random blokes is beyond reproach. Consider my fandom revoked until this is resolved. And don&#8217;t get me started on Hook&#8217;s own legacy-flogging as he tours a Joy Division tribute band &#8230;		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2011/11/11/the-new-order-reunion-is-a-joke-without-peter-hook/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Cure Add &#8220;Reflections&#8221; Concerts Stateside, Call Out R&#038;R Hall of Fame</title>
		<link>./../../../2011/09/28/the-cure-add-reflections-concerts-stateside-call-out-rr-hall-of-fame/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2011/09/28/the-cure-add-reflections-concerts-stateside-call-out-rr-hall-of-fame/index.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 14:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jason Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robert Smith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rock and Roll Hall of Fame]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Cure]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=6587</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Cure has been nominated for induction into the joke that is the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame. Kudos! Except, wait, Robert Smith is pissed about something. Evidently, The Cure&#8217;s &#8220;current&#8221; drummer was left off the name check list on the band&#8217;s bio at the official Hall of Fame site. In the Hall of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				</p>
<p>The Cure <a href="http://www.slicingupeyeballs.com/2011/09/28/robert-smith-cure-drummer-jason-cooper/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+SlicingUpEyeballs+%28slicing+up+eyeballs%3A+%2780s+college%2C+indie%2C+alternative+rock+music%29">has been nominated</a> for induction into the joke that is the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame. Kudos! Except, wait, Robert Smith is pissed about something. Evidently, The Cure&#8217;s &#8220;current&#8221; drummer was left off the name check list on the band&#8217;s <a href="http://rockhall.com/inductees/nominees/the-cure/">bio</a> at the official Hall of Fame site. In the Hall of Fame&#8217;s defense, The Cure&#8217;s revolving door policy for members over the past 30 years is bound to result in a few oversights. Granted, Jason Cooper has been in The Cure for 17 years. But in all honesty The Cure isn&#8217;t being nominated for anything Jason Cooper has added to the canon. Playing drums on 17 years of, uhh, less than stellar albums does not an induction into the Rock n Roll Hall of Fame make.</p>
<p>In other Cure news, the band is preparing to <a href="http://pitchfork.com/news/44128-the-cure-to-perform-first-three-albums-in-london-los-angeles-and-new-york/">reprise</a> its &#8220;Reflections&#8221; concerts, wherein the band will play its first three albums in their entirety for special shows in London, New York, and Los Angeles this November.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2011/09/28/the-cure-add-reflections-concerts-stateside-call-out-rr-hall-of-fame/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fender Unveils Kurt Cobain Guitar</title>
		<link>./../../../2011/09/07/fender-unveils-kurt-cobain-guitar/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 17:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kurt Cobain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nirvana]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=6581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the pending 20th anniversary of Nirvana&#8217;s Nevermind, Fender has decided to cash in on the festivities by releasing an exact replica of Kurt Cobain&#8217;s 1965 Fender Jaguar. The replica comes complete with Cobain&#8217;s scuff marks and wear and tear. Besides the creepy factor, what surprises me most is that this hasn&#8217;t happened already. If [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				</p>
<p>With the pending 20th anniversary of Nirvana&#8217;s Nevermind, Fender has decided to cash in on the festivities by <a href="http://stereogum.com/802572/fender-makes-a-kurt-cobain-guitar/news/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed:+stereogum/cBYa+(stereogum)">releasing</a> an exact <a href="http://www.fender.com/products/kurtcobain/models.php?partno=0143000700">replica</a> of Kurt Cobain&#8217;s 1965 Fender Jaguar. The replica comes complete with Cobain&#8217;s scuff marks and wear and tear. Besides the creepy factor, what surprises me most is that this hasn&#8217;t happened already. If you want to pony up for this piece of manufactured nostalgia, it will cost you $1849.99.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
