<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Michael Anthony is way classier than Eddie Van-Halen	</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 05:36:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Tony		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-563</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tony]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 05:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2007/08/23/michael-anthony-is-way-classier-than-eddie-van-halen/#comment-563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Okay, it&#039;s been a few years since this all happened and things have moved on.

I can cite Edward as a chief reason I started playing thirty-plus years ago... I wasn&#039;t a huge fan of &quot;A Different Kind of Truth.&quot;  Here and there, moments of brilliance... but just kinda &quot;meh,&quot; overall.

I find it hard to see &quot;Van Halen&quot; without Michael Anthony... just as much as it was hard to see it without Roth.

A sad portion of the legacy, I guess.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Okay, it&#8217;s been a few years since this all happened and things have moved on.</p>
<p>I can cite Edward as a chief reason I started playing thirty-plus years ago&#8230; I wasn&#8217;t a huge fan of &#8220;A Different Kind of Truth.&#8221;  Here and there, moments of brilliance&#8230; but just kinda &#8220;meh,&#8221; overall.</p>
<p>I find it hard to see &#8220;Van Halen&#8221; without Michael Anthony&#8230; just as much as it was hard to see it without Roth.</p>
<p>A sad portion of the legacy, I guess.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Chris		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-562</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chris]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 16:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2007/08/23/michael-anthony-is-way-classier-than-eddie-van-halen/#comment-562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Way to be the bigger man! I&#039;m not seeing this tour because Mike is not on it. It&#039;s just not Van Halen without him!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Way to be the bigger man! I&#8217;m not seeing this tour because Mike is not on it. It&#8217;s just not Van Halen without him!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Mark		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-561</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mark]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 20:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2007/08/23/michael-anthony-is-way-classier-than-eddie-van-halen/#comment-561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MIKE IS A CLASS ACT! ....   as always,  I trust him more than Eddie! I have always felt  that Eddie hides the truth  from fans,   and wont let the other members talk  and express their opinions  and   alcoholics  tend to lie to themselves  and be in denial.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>MIKE IS A CLASS ACT! &#8230;.   as always,  I trust him more than Eddie! I have always felt  that Eddie hides the truth  from fans,   and wont let the other members talk  and express their opinions  and   alcoholics  tend to lie to themselves  and be in denial.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Chris		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-560</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chris]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2010 14:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2007/08/23/michael-anthony-is-way-classier-than-eddie-van-halen/#comment-560</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have to tall all you wanna be van halen fans that van halen will always be the best there is and the best there always will be.  With or with out Sambone and Mike.  Bottom line is everyone can&#039;t stand sammy bone and the bottom line is mike will alway&#039;s be van halen period.  Dave will do his shit but like it or not van halen kicks ass.   
Please feel free to question that FOLK&#039;s.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have to tall all you wanna be van halen fans that van halen will always be the best there is and the best there always will be.  With or with out Sambone and Mike.  Bottom line is everyone can&#8217;t stand sammy bone and the bottom line is mike will alway&#8217;s be van halen period.  Dave will do his shit but like it or not van halen kicks ass.<br />
Please feel free to question that FOLK&#8217;s.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Drew		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-559</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Drew]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2009 20:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2007/08/23/michael-anthony-is-way-classier-than-eddie-van-halen/#comment-559</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The contention between the two parties stems from an issue of betrayal in the exploitation of the Van Halen franchise, or the perceived notion of such, by his band-mates. After thinking about it, I came to the realization that this is a pretty legitimate concern, here you have Anthony and Hagar going into very similar commercial endeavors in creating food products although I don&#039;t think that it was a joint effort, in that one influenced the other to pursue similar passions (Hagar with his Tequila line and Anthony with his sauces).  It just happend.  But I can see how Eddie could perceive a conspiring effort on their parts-- not only musically were they isolating themselves as a pair but also, as businessmen. And we all know what makes a business successful -- you need to &quot;sell the Hell&quot; out of your products by MARKETING them.

Now if Hagar and Anthony separated themselves completely from the Van Halen catalogue and franchise while promoting their food items, thereby dealing with their businesses in a detached (more professional) manner, then I think that the Van Halen camp would&#039;ve left everything alone, and by-gones would be by-gones. But because Anthony and Hagar will forever be associated with Van Halen -- anything they do outside of Van Halen will be associated as such -- ESPECIALLY if their playing Van Halen music at these glitzy Cabo-whatever the fuck events they stage, which I&#039;m assuming has everything to do with the promotion of their line of food items (Hagar more so). 

So there you go, the music should not be played in conjunction with corporate interests, thus the falling out occurred between the two camps legally speaking. The personal stuff, too also had a lot to do with it. Anthony should have been more patient and less antsy to want to get up on stage and &quot;have fun&quot; again, stating that he was bored during the VH down-time, as he puts it so lightly. He doesn&#039;t seem to realize that there is SO MUCH at stake when you decide to jam on side-projects with ex-members especially, and  the songs that are played are of your former band which made you rich and famous in the first place, now you&#039;re wanting get more rich and famous by selling food items by playing VH covers?]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The contention between the two parties stems from an issue of betrayal in the exploitation of the Van Halen franchise, or the perceived notion of such, by his band-mates. After thinking about it, I came to the realization that this is a pretty legitimate concern, here you have Anthony and Hagar going into very similar commercial endeavors in creating food products although I don&#8217;t think that it was a joint effort, in that one influenced the other to pursue similar passions (Hagar with his Tequila line and Anthony with his sauces).  It just happend.  But I can see how Eddie could perceive a conspiring effort on their parts&#8211; not only musically were they isolating themselves as a pair but also, as businessmen. And we all know what makes a business successful &#8212; you need to &#8220;sell the Hell&#8221; out of your products by MARKETING them.</p>
<p>Now if Hagar and Anthony separated themselves completely from the Van Halen catalogue and franchise while promoting their food items, thereby dealing with their businesses in a detached (more professional) manner, then I think that the Van Halen camp would&#8217;ve left everything alone, and by-gones would be by-gones. But because Anthony and Hagar will forever be associated with Van Halen &#8212; anything they do outside of Van Halen will be associated as such &#8212; ESPECIALLY if their playing Van Halen music at these glitzy Cabo-whatever the fuck events they stage, which I&#8217;m assuming has everything to do with the promotion of their line of food items (Hagar more so). </p>
<p>So there you go, the music should not be played in conjunction with corporate interests, thus the falling out occurred between the two camps legally speaking. The personal stuff, too also had a lot to do with it. Anthony should have been more patient and less antsy to want to get up on stage and &#8220;have fun&#8221; again, stating that he was bored during the VH down-time, as he puts it so lightly. He doesn&#8217;t seem to realize that there is SO MUCH at stake when you decide to jam on side-projects with ex-members especially, and  the songs that are played are of your former band which made you rich and famous in the first place, now you&#8217;re wanting get more rich and famous by selling food items by playing VH covers?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Glennyjoe		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-558</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Glennyjoe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 12:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2007/08/23/michael-anthony-is-way-classier-than-eddie-van-halen/#comment-558</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Its really sad to see what big egos can do to great bands like Van Halen.Back in the day they were the epitomy of what a great rock&#038;roll band should look and sound like. Now they are a shell of their former selves. If they can just put the bottle and the drugs down they might clear up and see the picture more clearly.the original 4 members together are a mighty force to be reckoned with but separate they look like bickering old fools who keep thinking of where they were instead of where they are right now. Good for Michael  Anthony for showing class and rocking out with Sammy and Joe Satriani Chickenfoot is a rock and roll band in the classic tradition Eddie are ya listening?]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Its really sad to see what big egos can do to great bands like Van Halen.Back in the day they were the epitomy of what a great rock&amp;roll band should look and sound like. Now they are a shell of their former selves. If they can just put the bottle and the drugs down they might clear up and see the picture more clearly.the original 4 members together are a mighty force to be reckoned with but separate they look like bickering old fools who keep thinking of where they were instead of where they are right now. Good for Michael  Anthony for showing class and rocking out with Sammy and Joe Satriani Chickenfoot is a rock and roll band in the classic tradition Eddie are ya listening?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: kosmo		</title>
		<link>./../index.html#comment-557</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kosmo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2007 18:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/2007/08/23/michael-anthony-is-way-classier-than-eddie-van-halen/#comment-557</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good job Mike, you show alot of class. I know Dave will screw up the lyrics and be his usual clown act. Dave&#039;s vocals suck live and he barely sings the lyrics. He&#039;s going to really miss Michael hitting those high notes in concert. Also Van Halen was one of the best harmonizing bands in rock.Not without Michael will they pull it off...]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Good job Mike, you show alot of class. I know Dave will screw up the lyrics and be his usual clown act. Dave&#8217;s vocals suck live and he barely sings the lyrics. He&#8217;s going to really miss Michael hitting those high notes in concert. Also Van Halen was one of the best harmonizing bands in rock.Not without Michael will they pull it off&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
