<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>interview &#8211; Drawer B</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 20:35:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>interview &#8211; Drawer B</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Cure Prepares Concert Box Set for Fall Release, Post-pones New Album</title>
		<link>./../../../2019/08/04/the-cure-prepares-concert-box-set-for-fall-release-post-pones-new-album/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 20:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fuji Rock Festival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meltdown Festival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My Bloody Valentine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nine Inch Nails]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Cure]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../wp/index.html?p=7833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last summer Robert Smith curated the Meltdown festival in the UK with handpicked acts ranging from My Bloody Valentine to Nine In Nails to The Church. The Cure, of course, headlined but were billed as CURÆTION-25 so as not to violate a contract for its massive headlining slot a few weeks later in London&#8217;s Hyde [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"></figure>



<p>Last summer Robert Smith <a href="http://www.slicingupeyeballs.com/2018/06/24/cure-meltdown-setlist-audio-stream/">curated the Meltdown festival</a> in the UK with handpicked acts ranging from My Bloody Valentine to Nine In Nails to The Church. The Cure, of course, headlined but were billed as CURÆTION-25 so as not to violate a contract for its massive headlining slot a few weeks later in London&#8217;s Hyde Park. Both shows are being combined for a <a href="https://www.post-punk.com/the-cure-to-release-meltdown-and-hyde-park-40th-anniversary-dvd-blu-ray-live-album-box-set/?fbclid=IwAR3a0C5yvWAfCvcd4LotYY13wzQaaSyIwDaSBS9JVHcDXoHF653-fPdopIQ">DVD/Blu-Ray release</a> this October to celebrate the band&#8217;s 40th anniversary. The setlists are expectedly massive, showcasing every idiosyncratic incarnation of the band. </p>



<p>Smith recently <a href="https://www.post-punk.com/the-cures-new-album-may-take-a-bit-longer-to-be-finished-says-robert-smith-in-interview-with-japanese-radio-dj-chigusa/amp/">revealed an update</a> for the band&#8217;s progress on its first new album in 11 years in an interview at the Fuji Rock Festival, claiming that the record will be delayed until next year. He had originally claimed it would be out close to Halloween this year. Even casual Cure fans know not to trust anything the man says with regard to release timelines. </p>



<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/udVvb5giPcg" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Britpop Conspiracy: Guardian Interview with MBV&#8217;s Kevin Shields</title>
		<link>./../../../2013/10/04/kevin-shields-i-play-through-the-pain/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 12:32:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[link]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Feedly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ian Svenonius]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IFTTT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My Bloody Valentine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nation of Ulysses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Make-Up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=7305</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This interview with My Bloody Valentine&#8217;s Kevin Shields is worth a read even without the conspiracy theory that Britpop was pushed by the Labour Government in the mid-90&#8217;s (ha!). &#8216;But when it is jokingly suggested that, had Shields released m b v in 1994, as initially planned, he could have kiboshed Britpop, his mood changes. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				This <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/music/2013/oct/03/my-bloody-valentine-kevin-shields-interview">interview</a> with My Bloody Valentine&#8217;s Kevin Shields is worth a read even without the conspiracy theory that Britpop was pushed by the Labour Government in the mid-90&#8217;s (ha!).</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8216;But when it is jokingly suggested that, had Shields released m b v in 1994, as initially planned, he could have kiboshed Britpop, his mood changes. &#8220;Britpop was massively pushed by the government,&#8221; he says. &#8220;Someday it would be interesting to read all the MI5 files on Britpop. The wool was pulled right over everyone&#8217;s eyes there.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>However, this interview by Ian Svenonius of Nation of Ulysses and The Make-Up over at <a href="http://www.vice.com/soft-focus/kevin-shields">Vice</a> is probably more fun, though:</p>
<p><script height="360px" width="540px" src="http://player.ooyala.com/iframe.js#ec=VtOGhpMjrlbHX4YkvbpgA8C2ajfLr-lO&#038;pbid=YjMwNmI4YjU2MGM5ZWRjMzRmMjljMjc5"></script>		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>STREAM: Ryan Adams&#8217; &#8220;Ashes &#038; Fire&#8221;</title>
		<link>./../../../2011/09/28/stream-ryan-adams-ashes-fire/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 17:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ryan Adams]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=6600</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In an uncharacteristic act of act of restraint, Ryan Adams has been relatively quiet on the new album front the past few years. He did put out that weird proto-metal record last year (Orion), but that somehow doesn&#8217;t count as a &#8220;Ryan Adams&#8221; album. The media is assuming the man has developed some kind of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				</p>
<p>In an uncharacteristic act of act of restraint, Ryan Adams has been relatively quiet on the new album front the past few years. He did put out that weird proto-metal record last year (<em>Orion</em>), but that somehow doesn&#8217;t count as a &#8220;Ryan Adams&#8221; album. The media is assuming the man has developed some kind of internal editor, hoping that <em>Ashes &amp; Fire</em> out October 11, 2011, will be a cliched &#8220;return to form.&#8221; If you want to decide for yourself, you can stream the new album <a href="http://www.npr.org/2011/09/25/140640429/first-listen-ryan-adams-ashes-and-fire">here</a>. I&#8217;ve never been in the camp that complained about too much product output from Adams. But his new album is amazing all the same.</p>
<p>But, if you&#8217;re also interested in a more in depth look at what Adams&#8217; motives are, <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/music/2011/sep/22/ryan-adams-things-got-broken">this interview</a> with the Guardian is extremely informative and shows Adams in his most stable frame of mind. 		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FEATURE: The Joy Formidable</title>
		<link>./../../../2011/09/28/feature-the-joy-formidable/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 16:59:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bruce Springsteen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Curve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elvis Costello]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roy Orbison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Joy Formidable]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=6594</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s often hard for me to believe it when bands say they have no direct influences on their sound. And when I recently spoke with The Joy Formidable’s bassist, Rhydian Daffyd, I heard a familiar refrain: “Sometimes we feel like we live in a bubble.” Yeah, yeah. Bands always hem and haw when asked to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				</p>
<p>It’s often hard for me to believe it when bands say they have no direct influences on their sound. And when I recently spoke with The Joy Formidable’s bassist, Rhydian Daffyd, I heard a familiar refrain: “Sometimes we feel like we live in a bubble.” Yeah, yeah. Bands always hem and haw when asked to describe their sound or list their favorite artists, so I always make a point to do so, just to see how much they squirm or if they’ll play along. Daffyd predictably begged off at first, but when pressed let slip quite a few. His list caught me off guard. While I was coming from a very narrow-minded and specific shoegaze angle with a little Curve and Britpop thrown in, he lobbed “Springsteen, Costello, Orbison, and Motown” back at me. Touché.</p>
<p><span id="more-6594"></span></p>
<p>His point was that his band didn’t have any preconceived notions about what it wanted to sound like when it began in 2007 other than wanting to be good, and that the artists that influenced it the most are the ones who focused on the songs, not image or sound. He also stressed how he and his bandmates grew up in an environment in Wales without the kind of access to new music that kids take for granted these days with the overwhelming limitlessness of the Internet. When he firmly asserted that his band’s sound is “secondary to the dynamic scope” I knew he was serious. So, I shouldn’t have been surprised by his conversational intensity, given how brazenly sharp and focused his band’s debut full-length is.</p>
<p>When I first heard The Joy Formidable’s “The Last Drop” off last year’s A Balloon Called Moaning EP, I knew instantly that I would love this band with its razor-sharp guitars, big booming choruses and a penchant for bombast that much of today’s trendier acts wouldn’t even know how to emulate. Ritzy Bryan’s voice cuts through the guitars with a piercing wail that recalls early 90’s Curve records, despite the fact that Daffyd claims ignorance on the subject of Curve (although he did acknowledge that I was not the first to mention the similarity). The band’s debut full-length, The Big Roar, takes the promise of “The Last Drop” and drives it to its logical conclusion on tracks like “Whirring” and “Cradle,” both of which employ whip-smart songwriting chops slathered in layers of guitars with an urgent backbone of bass.</p>
<p>Much of The Big Roar blurs the lines between aggression, melancholy and an underlying optimism. The in-the-red production underscores this trio’s power. Without such strong hooks, lesser bands would crumble under the weight of such sonic histrionics, but The Joy Formidable’s hooks soar amidst all the noise. It usually takes bands much longer than an EP and a full-length to achieve such swagger.</p>
<p>It’s so refreshing when bands find their way to people’s ears through word of mouth, instead of the tiresome hype cycle, where acts are vaulted and forgotten in the lapse of merely a semester. The Joy Formidable’s organic trajectory follows that of a band that came up in the 80’s, where the fan base grew in concert with the development of each each single or EP. It’s rare for bands to be allowed to develop naturally with the nanosecond attention spans of today’s micro-niche blog-culture.</p>
<p>The Joy Formidable has played the main stage at Glastonbury, one of the biggest, most renowned festivals in England, so I asked Daffyd if cracking America on that level was on the band’s to-do list. Daffyd stressed to me that commercial appeal is only “an after-thought”- that they would play their asses off for an empty club as much as for a field with hundreds of thousands of fans. The “we always give 100%” speech definitely means things are going well. I can’t imagine such enthusiasm if doors were being slammed at every turn.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Proto-Fascist Peer Pressure &#8211; James Murphy in 2006</title>
		<link>./../../../2011/04/05/proto-fascist-peer-pressure-james-murphy-in-2006/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[k]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 14:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=6474</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[m ss ng Murphy from m ss ng p eces on Vimeo. &#8220;Murphy shares his thoughts on musical discovery, the future of taste, artistic value in the face of technology and what he did with our plot device, something.&#8221;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				<iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/21933969" width="400" height="300" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/21933969">m ss ng Murphy</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/mssngpeces">m ss ng p eces</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com/">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Murphy shares his thoughts on musical discovery, the future of taste, artistic value in the face of technology and what he did with our plot device, something.&#8221;		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>You Won&#8217;t Ever See Steve Albini at Fashion Week</title>
		<link>./../../../2010/10/07/you-wont-ever-see-steve-albini-at-fashion-week/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 20:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GQ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sonic Youth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Albini]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=6096</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Steve Albini says seemingly outrageous things in interviews, but he never comes across as glib or unprepared. The guy means what he says, and he&#8217;s actually thought about his opinions before giving them. He&#8217;s one of the most uncompromising musicians I&#8217;ve ever admired. Sure, he can sound like an asshole, but he makes sense. Most [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				</p>
<p>Steve Albini says seemingly outrageous things in interviews, but he never comes across as glib or unprepared. The guy means what he says, and he&#8217;s actually thought about his opinions before giving them. He&#8217;s one of the most uncompromising musicians I&#8217;ve ever admired. Sure, he can sound like an asshole, but he makes <em>sense</em>. Most of the headlines about his recent <a href="http://www.gq.com/blogs/the-q/2010/09/steve-albini.html">Q&amp;A with GQ</a> focus on the lashes he gives Sonic Youth for signing to a major label, but they&#8217;re just the simple example in a much bigger picture. His over-arching point gets lost in the supposed &#8220;controversy&#8221; of his remarks, which is in regard to mainstream culture as a whole:</p>
<div>
<blockquote>
<div>&#8220;I&#8217;m not really interested in participating in  mainstream culture. Participating in the mainstream music business is,  to me, like getting involved in a racket. There&#8217;s no way you can get  involved in a racket and not someway be filthied by it.&#8221;</div>
</blockquote>
<div>The entire <a href="http://www.gq.com/blogs/the-q/2010/09/steve-albini.html">interview</a> is a must read. The culture of &#8220;selling out&#8221; seems to have been lost on today&#8217;s youth, as bloggers tend to sympathize with bands who sell their music to any old car company or sausage factory willing to shake a few bucks in their faces. Since it is accepted as a given that nobody actually &#8220;pays&#8221; for music anymore, the attitude seems to have shifted to allow for what used to be anathema to rock &#8216;n roll, which is the corporatization of counter-culture music. My attitudes were shaped long before the era of illegal downloading, so I find myself agreeing with just about everything Albini says.</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>eMusic interview with Teenbeat&#8217;s Mark Robinson</title>
		<link>./../../../2010/07/15/emusic-interview-with-teenbeats-mark-robinson/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eric]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 21:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[link]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cotton Candy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emusic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Robinson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maura Johnston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reunions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teenbeat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unrest]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.drawerb.com/?p=5983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Former Idolator honcho Maura Johnston interviews one of my heroes, Mark Robinson (of Teenbeat, Unrest, and Cotton Candy fame), in a cool, informative, and laid back Q&#38;A session over at eMusic. In it Robinson discusses the nostalgic personal touch of home-dubbing cassettes, Unrest&#8217;s reunion tour, his proclivity for patterns in numbering, and his favorite designers. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>				</p>
<p>Former Idolator honcho <a href="http://twitter.com/MAURA">Maura Johnston</a> interviews one of my heroes, Mark Robinson (of Teenbeat, Unrest, and Cotton Candy fame), in a cool, informative, and laid back Q&amp;A session over at <a href="http://www.emusic.com/features/spotlight/2010_201007-qa-mark-robinson.html">eMusic</a>. In it Robinson discusses the nostalgic personal touch of home-dubbing cassettes, Unrest&#8217;s reunion tour, his proclivity for patterns in numbering, and his favorite designers. I failed to make the three-and-a-half hour drive to Chapel Hill last Sunday to catch the Unrest show, which I knew I would immediately regret. So, I will have to stock up on any leftover merch if/when it shows up in the <a href="http://www.teenbeatrecords.com/">Teenbeat store</a> to make up for it.		</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
